<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 20:34:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[iOS 17.4 发布，在欧盟支持第三方应用商店]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>苹果发布了 iOS 17.4，为 iPhone 提供了支持第三方应用商店的功能。</strong>此外，苹果还开放了 iPhone 的 NFC 芯片给外部开发者使用。通过这些变化，苹果希望符合欧盟的 DMA 法律要求。通过拥有自己的应用商店，开发者可以使用自己的支付方式，从而减少向苹果支付的佣金。在发布 iOS 应用之前，开发者仍需经过苹果的审核，并且对于下载次数超过一百万的应用，他们需要支付每次安装 50 欧分的费用。软餐早前报道，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">德国的数字服务提供商 Mobivention 将于本周三发布首个替代性 iOS 应用商店</a>。Epic Games 也希望将 Epic Games Store 引入 iOS。</p><p>此外，浏览器开发商还可以发布不使用苹果 WebKit 内核的浏览器；iMessage 将获得改进的加密协议；Podcasts 应用将具备自动音频转录功能；还有新的表情符号发布；Siri 可以朗读收到的消息；iPhone 15 设备还可以分享更多有关电池健康状态的信息，例如充电周期数据。iOS 17.4 和 iPadOS 17.4 适用于支持 iOS 17 或 iPadOS 17 的所有设备。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Apple has released iOS 17.4, which brings support for third-party app stores to iPhones. Additionally, Apple has opened up the NFC chip on iPhones for external developers. With these changes, Apple aims to comply with the EU’s DMA (Digital Markets Act) regulations.</p><p>By having their own app stores, developers can use their own payment methods, thereby reducing the commission they pay to Apple. Developers still need to go through Apple’s approval process before releasing iOS apps, and for apps that are downloaded more than one million times, they are required to pay 50 euro cents per installation.</p><p>According to recent reports, German digital service provider Mobivention plans to launch the first alternative iOS app store this Wednesday. Epic Games also intends to bring the Epic Games Store to iOS.</p><p>Furthermore, browser developers will have the option to release browsers that don’t utilize the Apple WebKit engine. iMessage will receive an improved encryption protocol, the Podcasts app will have automatic audio transcripts, new emojis will be introduced, Siri will be able to read incoming messages, and iPhone 15 devices will be able to share more information about battery health, such as the number of charging cycles. iOS 17.4 and iPadOS 17.4 are available for all devices that support iOS 17 or iPadOS 17.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Telegram 开始推出商家账户]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>Telegram 创始人帕维尔·杜罗夫（Pavel Durov）称，<strong>本周开始，该应用推出了 Telegram Business 的第一批功能。</strong>即 Telegram 个人账户可转为商业账户，商业账户可添加位置和营业时间，使用带有颜色标签的聊天组织，使用自动问候/离开消息和快速回复的快捷方式等。</p><p>本月晚些时候，更多的 Telegram Business 功能还将推出。包括 Telegram Business 账户将可无缝地将聊天机器人添加到所有或特定的聊天中以进行回复，以帮助客户提升客服自动化水平。开发者可在本月后期还可免费使用新的机器人 API。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Telegram founder Pavel Durov announced that this week, the app has launched the first batch of Telegram Business features. Users now have the ability to convert their personal Telegram accounts into business accounts, which allows them to add location and business hours, organize chats with color labels, and utilize shortcuts for automatic greetings, away messages, and quick replies.</p><p>More Telegram Business features are set to be released later this month. One notable feature is the seamless integration of chatbots into Telegram Business accounts, enabling them to respond to all or specific chats, thereby enhancing customer service automation. Additionally, developers will have access to the new Bot APIs, which will be available free of charge later this month.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:45:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[聊天软件 Signal 7.0 发布，全面支持用户名]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/aJs-5Go4.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>Signal 官方宣布，<strong>已在最新版本 Signal 7.0 中<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141681.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">按原定计划</a>推出其用户名功能。Signal 用户可创建一个用户名，以隐藏自己的手机号码</strong>。该功能可有效保护用户的隐私。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>电话号码隐私和用户名功能现已在使用 Signal 7.0 版本的所有人中推出！更新您的应用程序以利用这些新功能。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[清单] 本周起 Pixel 手机、手表和平板获多项新功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>本周一开始，部分 Pixel 手机、手表和平板电脑获得了一系列新功能。</strong>这些更新将在未来几周内完成：</p><ul><li><strong>Google Pixel 7 和 Pixel Pro 将获得 「圈选搜索」（Circle to search）功能。</strong>用户可以通过在屏幕上圈出物体来进行搜索。上个月，这一功能已经应用于 Pixel 8 和 Pixel 8 Pro。</li><li><strong>Pixel 7 和 Pixel 8 的用户现在可以在 Instagram Reels 中制作更好的视频。</strong>现在可以使用 10 位 HDR 视频录制。还可以直接将照片以 Google 的 Ultra HDR 格式上传到 Instagram Feed。这两个设置需要在 Pixel 相机应用中先打开。目前尚不清楚这些功能将在哪些市场上可用。</li><li><strong>谷歌还将 Pixel Watch 2 的新功能添加到初代 Pixel 手表中。</strong>其中包括增强的运动模式，如一致节奏的 Pace Training 以及当用户步行速度过快或过慢时的振动通知。第一代 Pixel 手表现在还可以在检测到工作开始时自动启动和停止。用户现在还可以在 Pixel 手表上直接获取公共交通的路线指引。</li><li><strong>Pixel 手机或平板电脑的用户现在共享屏幕时可选择仅共享一个应用程序，而不是整个屏幕。</strong>此功能适用于 Pixel Tablet、Pixel Fold 和 Pixel 5a 与 5G 及更高版本的手机。</li><li><strong>谷歌简化了先前使用过的设备的配对过程。</strong>在更新后，Pixel 平板电脑的用户可以在 Google Docs 中使用注释和批注进行评论。</li><li><strong>谷歌将为 Pixel 6 及更高版本的手机在美国推出更新版本的通话屏幕（Call Screen）。</strong>当来电者保持沉默时，用户将看到一个 「你好」 按钮。按下按钮后，谷歌助手会要求来电者开口。这样用户就可以知道为什么要联系他们。如果用户无法回答，谷歌助手会告知来电者稍等片刻。目前尚不清楚这一功能是否会在全球范围内推出，以及何时推出。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><ul><li>Google Pixel 7 and Pixel Pro will receive the 「Circle to search」 feature. Users can search by circling an object on the screen. Last month, this feature was already applied to Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro.</li><li>Users of Pixel 7 and Pixel 8 can now create better videos on Instagram Reels. 10-bit HDR video recording is now available. It is also possible to directly upload photos in Google’s Ultra HDR format to Instagram Feed. These two settings need to be enabled in the Pixel Camera app. It is currently unclear in which markets these features will be available.</li><li>Google has also added new features from Pixel Watch 2 to the first-generation Pixel Watch. This includes enhanced motion modes such as consistent rhythm Pace Training and vibration notifications when the user’s walking speed is too fast or too slow. The first-gen Pixel Watch can now also automatically start and stop when work is detected. Users can now also directly access public transit directions on the Pixel Watch.</li><li>Users of Pixel phones or tablets can now choose to share only one application instead of the entire screen when screen sharing. This feature is available for Pixel Tablet, Pixel Fold, Pixel 5a with 5G, and higher versions of Pixel phones.</li><li>Google has simplified the pairing process for previously used devices. After the update, users of Pixel tablets can use comments and annotations in Google Docs.</li><li>Google will release an updated version of Call Screen for Pixel 6 and higher versions of the phone in the United States. When the caller remains silent, users will see a 「Hi」 button. Pressing the button will prompt the Google Assistant to ask the caller to speak. This way, users can know why they are being contacted. If the user is unable to answer, the Google Assistant will inform the caller to wait for a moment. It is currently unclear if and when this feature will be launched globally.</li></ul>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 10:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142050.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142050.html</link>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[重磅：微软宣布停止支持 Windows 安卓子系统]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软公司宣布将于 2025 年初结束对 Windows 安卓子系统（WSA）的支持。</strong>该工具允许用户在 Windows 11 中运行 Android 应用程序。自 2025 年 3 月 5 日起，将不再支持所有依赖 WSA 的应用程序和游戏。在 2024 年 3 月 6 日之前安装了 Amazon Appstore 或 Android 应用的用户，可以继续使用它们并获得技术支持，直到明年初。在 2021 年 6 月首次发布 Windows 11 时，微软透露了对 Android 应用程序的支持。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Microsoft 将终止对 Windows Subsystem for Android™️（WSA）的支持。因此，从 2025 年 3 月 5 日开始，将不再支持 Windows 上的 Amazon Appstore 以及所有依赖于 WSA 的应用程序和游戏。在此之前，仍将为客户提供技术支持。</p><p>在 2024 年 3 月 5 日之前安装了亚马逊应用商店或 Android 应用的客户，在 2025 年 3 月 5 日的弃用日期之前，将继续有权访问这些应用。如有其他问题，请联系我们的支持团队，网址为 support.microsoft.com。我们感谢开发者社区的支持，并将继续致力于在改进体验的过程中听取反馈。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:29:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
