<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 15:56:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[马斯克称将停用电话号码，仅用 X 平台通信]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>马斯克发文称：「几个月后，我将停止使用我的电话号码，只使用 X 平台发消息和进行音频/视频通话。」</strong>据悉，马斯克希望通过此举，将 X（Twitter）平台转型为一家可以盈利并与中国的微信分庭抗礼的社交平台。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 03:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141561.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141561.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google 密码管理器将可与家人共享密码]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>Google 密码管理器将可以与伴侣或子女共享密码。</strong>Google 并未透露该功能的发布时间。要使用此功能，账户必须已经使用 Family Link 登录，这是 Google 的家庭管理系统，允许父母管理子女的手机。该选项的目的之一是在父母之间或父母与子女之间快速交换例如学校系统的密码。许多密码管理器已经具备了与其他用户共享密码的选项。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google Password Manager will allow users to share passwords with their partners or children. Google has not disclosed the release date for this feature. To use this functionality, the account must already be logged in with Family Link, Google’s family management system that allows parents to manage their children’s phones. One of the purposes of this option is to facilitate the quick exchange of passwords, such as school system passwords, between parents or between parents and children. Many password managers already have options to share passwords with other users.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[苹果 Vision Pro 曝重大疏漏：忘记密码需重置设备]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>购买了苹果混合现实头显 Apple Vision Pro 的用户发现，如果忘记了该头显的密码，他们将不得不把设备送回苹果商店或运回苹果，才能重置密码。</strong>这里说的密码并非 Apple ID 电子邮箱和密码，而是实际访问 Vision Pro 时需要输入的一组数字。消费者必须牢记这组密码，一旦忘记，头显需要完全恢复出厂设置，用户需要重新下载应用程序并重新设置 Vision Pro。据悉，大量相关的抱怨已经涌入苹果的客户支持部门，服务人员为没有做好应对而致歉。苹果公司尚未就此问题进行回应。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Users who have purchased the Apple mixed reality headset, Apple Vision Pro, have discovered that if they forget the password for the headset, they will have to send the device back to an Apple store or ship it to Apple to have the password reset. The password referred to here is not the Apple ID email and password but a set of numbers required to access the Vision Pro itself. Consumers must remember this password, as forgetting it would require a complete factory reset of the headset, leading users to have to re-download applications and reconfigure the Vision Pro. Numerous complaints regarding this issue have reportedly flooded Apple’s customer support department, and Apple has apologized for not being adequately prepared to address the problem. The company has not yet responded to this issue.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:42:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</link>
            <category>iOS</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[去中心化社交应用 Bluesky 全面开放用户注册]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>去中心化的社交媒体应用程序 Bluesky 全面开放了用户注册</strong>（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.blueskyweb.app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Play 商店</a>）<strong>。</strong>现在任何人无需邀请即可注册账号。在开放注册之前，该应用增强了其基础设施和内容审核能力。Bluesky 于 2023 年 3 月<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/121704.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">推出</a>，一直以来采用邀请制模式，此前超过 300 万注册了该应用。Bluesky 官方还宣布，未来几周或几个月将推出一些新功能，包括：为想要进一步审核其 Feed 的用户提供标签服务、允许开发者和其他组织使用自己的审核规则创建自己的 Bluesky 服务器、提供类似于 X 的收费额外功能等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The decentralized social media application Bluesky has opened up user registration to the public. Now anyone can sign up for an account without needing an invitation. Prior to opening up registration, the app enhanced its infrastructure and content moderation capabilities. Launched in March 2023, Bluesky had been operating on an invitation-only basis and attracted over 3 million registrations. Bluesky’s official announcement also revealed that new features will be rolled out in the coming weeks or months, including labeling services for users who want to further moderate their feed, allowing developers and other organizations to create their own Bluesky servers with their own moderation rules, and offering additional paid features similar to X.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Spotify 月活用户突破 6 亿]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2006422084.jpeg.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p><strong>Spotify 首次突破了 6 亿月度活跃用户的大关。</strong>过去一个季度，其用户数量增加了 2800 万，略高于预期。该公司披露，在在 6.02 亿月活跃用户中，有 2.36 亿人为付费订户。这比一年前增加了 15％，对应增加 3100 万名订阅者。在过去一个季度，订户数量增加了 1000 万。无论是活跃用户数量还是高级订阅者数量都超过了预期。<strong>这家流媒体服务公司在上一季度再次亏损，亏损金额 7500 万欧元。其收入达 37 亿欧元，符合预期。</strong>这比一年前增长了 16％。大部分收入仍然来自高级订阅者，达到了 32 亿欧元。而在此之前的一个季度，Spotify 自 2021 年以来首次实现了盈利。Spotify 解释说，亏损是 「促进效率的行动」 造成的。这可能指的是为了节省成本而裁员 17％。</p><p><strong>Spotify 预计下一个季度用户数量仍将继续增长，并计划在三个月内达到 6.18 亿活跃用户。收入预计将保持相对稳定，该平台预计将获得 1.8 亿欧元的利润。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Spotify has surpassed 600 million monthly active users for the first time. In the past quarter, its user base increased by 28 million, slightly exceeding expectations. The company revealed that out of the 602 million monthly active users, 236 million are paid subscribers. This represents a 15% increase compared to a year ago, with an additional 31 million subscribers since the beginning of 2023. The number of subscribers grew by 10 million in the past quarter. Both the active user count and the number of premium subscribers exceeded expectations by one million. Spotify saw higher-than-expected growth in subscriber numbers in Latin America and the Rest of the World, meaning regions outside of the Americas and Europe.</p><p>Spotify’s revenue in the past quarter reached €3.7 billion, in line with expectations. This represents a 16% increase compared to the previous year. The majority of revenue still comes from premium subscribers, amounting to €3.2 billion. The streaming service reported a loss of €75 million, while in the previous quarter, Spotify achieved its first profit since 2021. Spotify attributes this loss to 「actions to promote efficiency,」 which cost the company €143 million. Presumably, the platform is referring to the 17% reduction in staff to cut costs.</p><p>Spotify expects the user count to continue growing in the next quarter and anticipates reaching 618 million active users in three months. Revenue is projected to remain relatively stable, and the platform expects to achieve a profit of €180 million.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:09:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141535.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141535.html</link>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
