<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 07:30:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>被廣泛批評後，Meta 希望將「去廣告」服務價格減半</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，Meta 的一位高管週二表示，&lt;strong&gt;該公司提出將 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月訂閲費從 9.99 歐元減半至 5.99 歐元，以消除歐盟監管監管機構的擔憂。&lt;/strong&gt;此次降價是在隱私活動人士和消費者團體對 Meta 在歐盟的無廣告訂閲服務提出批評之後進行的，批評者稱該服務要求用户付費以確保其隱私。現在，歐盟的隱私保護活動人士並不認可降價方案，他們認為這與價格無關，即使降價到 1.99 歐元或更低，也會導致用户選擇 「同意」，即接受在訪問 Meta 服務的同時瀏覽廣告。上週，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;39 名歐盟議員發出公開信，希望 Meta 停止提供該付費去廣告模式&lt;/a&gt;。Meta 於 11 月推出了付費去廣告訂閲計劃，以遵守《數字市場法案》(DMA)，該法案限制了其在未經用户同意的情況下為用户提供個性化廣告的能力，從而損害了其主要收入來源。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>iPhone 借力谷歌 Gemini，暗示蘋果 AI 研發緩慢</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;我們稍早前&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142426.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;報道&lt;/a&gt;，蘋果正與 Google 討論向新款 iPhone 植入後者的 Gemini 人工智能引擎。這無疑對 iPhone 和 Gemini AI 模型都是雙贏的局面。但華爾街日報評論説，這 「&lt;strong&gt;同時也可能意味着，蘋果公司開發自身 AI 能力的進展可能比投資者希望的要慢。&lt;/strong&gt;」&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we reported that Apple is in discussions with Google regarding the integration of Google’s Gemini artificial intelligence engine into the new iPhone. This undoubtedly presents a win-win situation for both the iPhone and the Gemini AI model. However, The Wall Street Journal comments, 「It may also imply that Apple’s progress in developing its own AI capabilities could be slower than what investors had hoped for.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:45:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[時間表/鏈接] 聚焦英偉達 GTC 2024 大會</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;毫無疑問，英偉達 GTC 2024 大會是今年最受矚目的科技盛會。創始人兼 CEO 黃仁勳將於大會上發佈備受關注的主題演講，主題為 「見證 AI 的變革時刻」，分享展望未來英偉達在 AI 領域的重大突破。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;直播時間：&lt;/strong&gt;北京時間 3 月 19 日，星期二 | 4:00 — 6:00 全球首播&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;重播時間：&lt;/strong&gt;北京時間 3 月 21 日，星期四 | 10:00 — 12:00 中文字幕重播&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;屆時讀者可在&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.cn/gtc-global/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;英偉達官網&lt;/a&gt;或油管搜索觀看黃仁勳的演講直播。&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:28:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>亞馬遜下週將舉辦首次春季大促</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文是普通報道，而非廣告，本站不通過報道獲利。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;電商巨頭亞馬遜將於 3 月 19 日開啓春季大促。&lt;/strong&gt;作為亞馬遜有史以來第一次春季大促銷活動，活動將持續 6 天，3 月 19 日美東時間凌晨 3 點正式開始，一直持續到 3 月 25 日。促銷期間將有大幅的商品折扣，涵蓋運動/户外/傢俱/美容/電子產品/服裝等品類，包括亞馬遜自家的 Kindle 電子書閲讀器、Echo 智能音箱和顯示器系列等。最高折扣幅度達 50%。該活動比亞馬遜夏季的 Prime 會員日和秋季的 Big Deal Days 持續時間更長。更重要的是，這次大促將適用於任何互聯網用户，而不侷限於 Prime 會員。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;E-commerce giant Amazon will kick off its spring promotion on March 19. As Amazon’s first-ever spring promotion event, the event will last for 6 days, starting officially at 3:00 am Eastern Time on March 19 and running until March 25. During the promotion period, there will be significant discounts on a wide range of products, including sports/outdoor/furniture/beauty/electronics/clothing categories, as well as Amazon’s own Kindle e-readers, Echo smart speakers, and display series. The highest discount rate reaches up to 50%. This event lasts longer than Amazon’s summer Prime Day and fall Big Deal Days events. More importantly, this major promotion will apply to any internet user, not just Prime members.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>歐盟議員呼籲 Meta 停止提供「付費去廣告」模式</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;39 名歐洲議會議員聯署了一封致 Meta 首席執行官扎克伯格的公開信，呼籲 Meta 停止其 「付費或同意模式」。&lt;/strong&gt;——去年 11 月，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/138516.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Meta 為 Instagram 和 Facebook 提供了一個付費訂閲服務&lt;/a&gt;，每月支付 10 歐元，訂户就不會看到（個性化）廣告。&lt;strong&gt;議員們認為這種模式破壞了《通用數據保護條例》（AVG）的目標，理由是 「隱私權不應被購買。徵收隱私税不僅歧視性強，還暗示着隱私和數據保護被視為商品而非基本權利」&lt;/strong&gt;。政治家們強調，公民根據《通用數據保護條例》應當得到 「真正或自由選擇」，而 Meta 的 「付費或同意模式」 並未滿足此要求，其次議員們批評了訂閲價格，認為隱私不應作為奢侈品出售。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;39 Members of the European Parliament jointly signed an open letter to Meta’s CEO Mark Zuckerberg, calling on Meta to stop its 「pay or consent model.」 Last November, Meta introduced a paid subscription service for Instagram and Facebook, where subscribers pay 10 euros per month to avoid personalized ads. The parliamentarians believe that this model undermines the objectives of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), stating that 「privacy should not be for sale. Levying a privacy tax is not only discriminatory but also implies that privacy and data protection are treated as commodities rather than fundamental rights.」 Politicians emphasize that citizens should have a 「genuine or free choice」 under the GDPR, which Meta’s 「pay or consent model」 does not meet. Additionally, the parliamentarians criticized the subscription price, arguing that privacy should not be sold as a luxury item.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:12:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>