<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 12:33:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德國高速鐵路還在用古老的 Windows 3.11]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，由西門子交通發佈的一則招聘廣告（已刪除）顯示，<strong>其客户德國鐵路公司（DB）內部仍在使用已有 30 年曆史的 Windows for Workgroups 3.11 系統。該系統發佈於 1992 年 10 月。</strong>西門子正為德國鐵路尋找一位瞭解傳統操作系統的系統管理員，尤其是 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups。其職責是處理該系統的更新和維護。這則招聘信息還顯示，列車駕駛室的顯示系統基於 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups 運行，該系統實時向駕駛員顯示所有重要的技術數據。據悉，該系統最有可能用於舊的 ICE 1 和 ICE2 高速城際快車。西門子交通證實了招聘信息的真實性，並解釋説火車和鐵路基礎設施的使用壽命為 30 年或更長時間。該公司向公眾保證，其客户 「繼續安全地使用業內久經考驗的遺留系統」，並且西門子為整個生命週期提供支持和維護。該公司還補充説，更新的系統是使用當前可用的軟件產品開發的，甚至會用到人工智能。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A recruitment advertisement (now deleted) released by Siemens Mobility has revealed that their client, Deutsche Bahn (DB), is still using the 30-year-old Windows for Workgroups 3.11 system internally. This system was released in October 1992. Siemens is actively seeking a system administrator with knowledge of traditional operating systems, particularly Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, to handle updates and maintenance of this system for Deutsche Bahn. The job description also states that the display systems in train cabins run on Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, providing real-time display of all critical technical data to the train drivers. It is reported that this system is most likely used for the older ICE 1 and ICE 2 high-speed intercity trains. Siemens Mobility has confirmed the authenticity of the recruitment information, explaining that the lifespan of trains and railway infrastructure is typically 30 years or longer. The company assures the public that their clients continue to use industry-proven legacy systems safely, and Siemens provides support and maintenance throughout the entire lifecycle. The company also adds that the updated systems are developed using currently available software products and may even incorporate artificial intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google 搜索停止提供網頁快照]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>Google 已從搜索結果中刪除了網頁快照選項。</strong>Google 員工 Danny Sullivan 確認，網頁緩存功能不再顯示在 Google 搜索結果中。以前該選項位於搜索結果條目右側的菜單中，用户可藉助該選項訪問 Google 緩存網頁的早期索引版本。緩存功能於幾年前引入，它是網絡原因導致原始網頁無法加載時的替代選擇，但現在網絡狀況已有了很大改善。因此，Google 決定停止提供該功能。過去幾個月來，Google 一直在逐漸刪除該功能。Google 建議希望查看網站緩存版本的用户使用 Google Search Console。用户還可使用 Wayback Machine 等服務。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google has removed the option for webpage snapshots from its search results. Google employee Danny Sullivan confirmed that the webpage cache functionality is no longer displayed in Google search results. Previously, this option was located in the menu on the right side of the search result entry, allowing users to access earlier indexed versions of webpages through Google’s cache. Google now considers this feature irrelevant. The cache functionality was introduced several years ago as an alternative when the original webpage couldn’t load due to network issues. However, with significant improvements in network conditions, Google has decided to discontinue this feature. Over the past few months, Google has been gradually removing this functionality. Google advises users who wish to view cached versions of websites to use the Google Search Console. Users can also utilize services like the Wayback Machine.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 09:40:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141444.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141444.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[清單]2024 年 1 月瀏覽器市場份額公佈]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，Statcounter 發佈了 2024 年 1 月的瀏覽器份額報告。數據顯示，桌面方面，谷歌的 Chrome 瀏覽器地位穩固，佔有 64.84% 的份額，微跌 0.39%；第二位的 Microsoft Edge 瀏覽器表現亮眼，增長 1.01 %，拿到 12.96% 的份額。移動瀏覽器領域格局相對更加穩定，各家漲跌變化均未超過 0.50%。</p><p><strong>2024 年 1 月，桌面瀏覽器市場份額：</strong></p><ol><li>Google Chrome – 64.84% (-0.39 points)</li><li>Microsoft Edge – 12.96% (+1.01 points)</li><li>Apple Safari – 8.83 (-0.13 points)</li><li>Mozilla Firefox – 7.57% (-0.05 points)</li><li>Opera – 3.23% (-0.57 points)</li></ol><p><strong>2024 年 1 月，移動瀏覽器市場份額：</strong></p><ol><li>Google Chrome – 64.74% (-0.19 points)</li><li>Apple Safari – 25.07% (+0.36 points)</li><li>Samsung Internet – 4.39% (-0.09 points)</li><li>Opera – 2.15% (-0.12 points)</li><li>UC Browser – 1.36% (-0.12 points)</li></ol>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 09:49:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141425.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141425.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟正為 Edge 瀏覽器安卓版開發擴展功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2006406784.jpeg.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟被發現正為 Edge 瀏覽器安卓版開發擴展功能。</strong>開發者 Leopeva64 分享的截屏顯示，在 Microsoft Edge 的 Canary 測試版中，瀏覽器菜單中已出現擴展程序的選項菜單。微軟公司尚未對該消息發表迴應。<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140171.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Firefox 安卓版已於去年底全面支持擴展功能</a>。觀察人士認為，隨着歐盟《數字市場法案》（DMA）的生效，蘋果將允許在 iOS 上使用基於其他瀏覽器引擎的瀏覽器，微軟等瀏覽器廠商也將在 iOS 平台上有所作為。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has been discovered to be developing extension functionality for the Android version of its Edge browser. A screenshot shared by developer Leopeva64 shows that the options menu for browser extensions has appeared in the browser menu of the Canary test version of Microsoft Edge. Microsoft has not yet responded to this news. Observers believe that with the enforcement of the EU’s Digital Markets Act (DMA), Apple will allow browsers based on other browser engines to be used on iOS, and browser vendors like Microsoft will also make moves on the iOS platform.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 08:13:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141397.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141397.html</link>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[人民日報稱「整個國家都洋溢着樂觀向上的氛圍」]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/photo_2024-02-02_14-40-13-1.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，2 月 2 日，人民日報刊文《「整個國家都洋溢着樂觀向上的氛圍」》。該報援引德國的共產黨國際關係書記雷娜特·科佩的話稱：「中國在住房、醫療、教育和基礎設施等方面的進步明顯，人民的整體生活水平得到很大提升。整個國家都洋溢着樂觀向上的氛圍，給我留下深刻印象。」</p><p><a href="http://world.people.com.cn/n1/2024/0202/c1002-40171413.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">圍觀原文</a></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 06:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141378.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141378.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
