<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 11:56:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[曝新版 Outlook 與 700 多家廣告商通信]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，瑞士加密郵箱開發商 Proton 近日聲稱，<strong>微軟的新版 Outlook 應用程序正在與 770 多個廣告合作伙伴進行通信。</strong>Proton 稱，新版 Outlook for Windows 應用程序會向歐盟用户彈出一個用户協議彈窗，其中提到微軟公司會與 772 個第三方共享用户的數據。只有歐盟用户能看到這個彈窗，因為歐盟《通用數據保護條例》（GDPR）強制要求 Web 服務通知用户有關數據收集和 Cookie 的信息。彈出的協議允許這些實體執行展示、衡量個性化廣告和內容、在用户設備上存儲和/或訪問信息、獲取精確的地理位置數據、通過設備掃描識別用户等操作。Proton 還表示，Microsoft Outlook 從用户處會收集多種數據，包括姓名和聯繫方式、密碼、人口統計數據、付款數據、訂閲和許可數據等等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Swiss encrypted email provider Proton has recently claimed that Microsoft’s new version of the Outlook application is communicating with over 770 advertising partners. Proton states that the new Outlook for Windows application displays a user agreement pop-up to European Union (EU) users, mentioning that Microsoft will share user data with 772 third-party entities. Only EU users can see this pop-up as the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) mandates web services to inform users about data collection and cookies. The displayed agreement allows these entities to perform activities such as displaying, measuring personalized ads and content, storing and/or accessing information on user devices, obtaining precise geolocation data, and identifying users through device scanning. Proton indicates that Microsoft Outlook collects various data from users, including names and contact information, passwords, demographic data, payment data, subscription and licensing data, and more.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 10:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141268.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141268.html</link>
            <category>辦公/生產力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Chrome 發佈更新，修復四個安全漏洞]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>谷歌日前為 Chrome 瀏覽器發佈更新，修復了桌面版和 Android 版中的四個安全漏洞。</strong>其中一個已在野外被利用。最新版本號為 120.0.6099.234（Mac 版）、120.0.6099.224（Linux 版）、120.0.6099.224 或 120.0.6099.225（Windows 版）。谷歌公佈了其中的三個漏洞，即 CVE-2024-0517、CVE-2024-0518 和 CVE-2024-0519。谷歌確認 CVE-2025-0519 在野外被利用。其他基於 Chromium 的瀏覽器也會受到這些問題的影響，預計也將很快推出更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google recently released an update for the Chrome browser, addressing four security vulnerabilities in both the desktop and Android versions. One of these vulnerabilities was being actively exploited in the wild. The latest version numbers are 120.0.6099.234 for Mac, 120.0.6099.224 for Linux, and 120.0.6099.224 or 120.0.6099.225 for Windows. Google disclosed three of the vulnerabilities as CVE-2024-0517, CVE-2024-0518, and CVE-2024-0519. Google has confirmed that CVE-2025-0519 is being actively exploited. Other Chromium-based browsers are also expected to be affected by these issues and are likely to release updates soon.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:28:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141261.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141261.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟推出 Copilot GPT，允許自行定製機器人]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/1705344161_copilotgpt_story.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟宣佈推出 Copilot GPT。</strong>它允許用户根據特定需求和主題量身定製自己的 AI 聊天機器人。只有購買了付費版計劃 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141205.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Copilot Pro</a> 的訂户才可以使用 Copilot GPT。 Copilot Pro 服務的訂閲價格為每月 20 美元。微軟還計劃推出一款專門用於定製聊天機器人的全新應用程序 Copilot GPT Builder 。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has announced the launch of Copilot GPT. It allows users to customize their own AI chatbots based on specific needs and topics. Copilot GPT is only available to subscribers who have purchased the paid version plan, Copilot Pro. The subscription price for Copilot Pro service is $20 per month. Microsoft also plans to release a new application specifically for customizing chatbots called Copilot GPT Builder.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 09:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141228.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141228.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟將 USB4 2.0 80Gpbs 引入 Win11]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，在上週發佈的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141117.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 11 build 23615</a>（Dev 通道）中，微軟已為 Windows 11 引入了 USB4 Gen 4 支持。這是最新的 USB 標準，它將性能從 40Gbps 提高到 80Gbps。它支持下一代高性能顯示器、存儲和連接。微軟稱，USB4 2.0 80Gpbs 最初將在配備英特爾最近推出的第 14 代移動處理器的特定設備上推出。新的 Razer Blade 18 將成為首批支持 USB4 2.0 的 Windows 筆記本電腦之一。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the Windows 11 build 23615 (Dev Channel) released last week, Microsoft has introduced support for USB4 Gen 4, the latest USB standard, to Windows 11. This upgrade increases the performance from 40Gbps to 80Gbps. USB4 Gen 4 supports next-generation high-performance displays, storage, and connectivity. Microsoft stated that USB4 2.0 80Gbps will initially roll out on specific devices equipped with Intel’s recently launched 14th generation mobile processors. The new Razer Blade 18 will be one of the first Windows laptops to support USB4 2.0.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 09:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141223.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141223.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[最高法稱將加大裁判文書上網力度]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>據<a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/751825369_121284943" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">央視新聞</a>，最高人民法院相關負責人表示，為針對性解決裁判文書網使用效果不佳、權利保護不力、安全風險暴露等問題，<strong>最高人民法院要求加大上網力度，具有法治引領、教育、警示作用的文書，都應當上網；最高人民法院、高級法院的文書，要更多地上網；上網文書數量應當保持相當規模，並應當覆蓋各審判領域、多種案件類型。要平衡好文書公開與當事人合法權利、隱私保護之間的關係，上網公佈裁判文書要隱去相關識別信息，確保當事人及其家人的生活工作、各類企業單位的經營發展不受裁判文書上網公佈的影響。</strong>同時加大人民法院案例庫建設力度，更優更實為司法審判優質高效服務，為社會公眾學法、專家學者科研、律師辦案服務。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 16:25:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141191.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141191.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
