<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 09:33:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google 密码管理器将可与家人共享密码]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>Google 密码管理器将可以与伴侣或子女共享密码。</strong>Google 并未透露该功能的发布时间。要使用此功能，账户必须已经使用 Family Link 登录，这是 Google 的家庭管理系统，允许父母管理子女的手机。该选项的目的之一是在父母之间或父母与子女之间快速交换例如学校系统的密码。许多密码管理器已经具备了与其他用户共享密码的选项。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google Password Manager will allow users to share passwords with their partners or children. Google has not disclosed the release date for this feature. To use this functionality, the account must already be logged in with Family Link, Google’s family management system that allows parents to manage their children’s phones. One of the purposes of this option is to facilitate the quick exchange of passwords, such as school system passwords, between parents or between parents and children. Many password managers already have options to share passwords with other users.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[苹果 Vision Pro 曝重大疏漏：忘记密码需重置设备]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>购买了苹果混合现实头显 Apple Vision Pro 的用户发现，如果忘记了该头显的密码，他们将不得不把设备送回苹果商店或运回苹果，才能重置密码。</strong>这里说的密码并非 Apple ID 电子邮箱和密码，而是实际访问 Vision Pro 时需要输入的一组数字。消费者必须牢记这组密码，一旦忘记，头显需要完全恢复出厂设置，用户需要重新下载应用程序并重新设置 Vision Pro。据悉，大量相关的抱怨已经涌入苹果的客户支持部门，服务人员为没有做好应对而致歉。苹果公司尚未就此问题进行回应。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Users who have purchased the Apple mixed reality headset, Apple Vision Pro, have discovered that if they forget the password for the headset, they will have to send the device back to an Apple store or ship it to Apple to have the password reset. The password referred to here is not the Apple ID email and password but a set of numbers required to access the Vision Pro itself. Consumers must remember this password, as forgetting it would require a complete factory reset of the headset, leading users to have to re-download applications and reconfigure the Vision Pro. Numerous complaints regarding this issue have reportedly flooded Apple’s customer support department, and Apple has apologized for not being adequately prepared to address the problem. The company has not yet responded to this issue.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:42:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</link>
            <category>iOS</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[去中心化社交应用 Bluesky 全面开放用户注册]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>去中心化的社交媒体应用程序 Bluesky 全面开放了用户注册</strong>（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.blueskyweb.app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Play 商店</a>）<strong>。</strong>现在任何人无需邀请即可注册账号。在开放注册之前，该应用增强了其基础设施和内容审核能力。Bluesky 于 2023 年 3 月<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/121704.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">推出</a>，一直以来采用邀请制模式，此前超过 300 万注册了该应用。Bluesky 官方还宣布，未来几周或几个月将推出一些新功能，包括：为想要进一步审核其 Feed 的用户提供标签服务、允许开发者和其他组织使用自己的审核规则创建自己的 Bluesky 服务器、提供类似于 X 的收费额外功能等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The decentralized social media application Bluesky has opened up user registration to the public. Now anyone can sign up for an account without needing an invitation. Prior to opening up registration, the app enhanced its infrastructure and content moderation capabilities. Launched in March 2023, Bluesky had been operating on an invitation-only basis and attracted over 3 million registrations. Bluesky’s official announcement also revealed that new features will be rolled out in the coming weeks or months, including labeling services for users who want to further moderate their feed, allowing developers and other organizations to create their own Bluesky servers with their own moderation rules, and offering additional paid features similar to X.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Z-Library 现在可以高效地推荐图书]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>电子书网站 Z-Library 周一宣布改进了其图书推荐系统。</strong>新的系统可帮助读者找到真正符合您兴趣的图书。Z-Library 介绍说，以前，其图书推荐仅基于用户行为，但这种方法存在局限，例如它无法为稀有或不受欢迎的图书生成推荐。<strong>为此该网站开发了自己的技术，可以在数百万本图书中找到相似的文本，并将其应用于推荐模块中。</strong>现在，在生成推荐时，除了考虑用户行为，还会用到其独特的文本比较技术。这意味着在选择推荐图书时，Z-Library 会分析图书内容，以提供更准确、多样化的建议。</p><p>Z-Library 同时再次提醒避免访问两个仿冒网站，分别是 z-lib[.] io 和 z-lib[.] id。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The e-book website Z-Library announced on Monday that it has improved its book recommendation system. The new system is designed to help readers find books that truly match their interests. According to Z-Library, the previous book recommendations were solely based on user behavior, but this approach had limitations, such as the inability to generate recommendations for rare or unpopular books. To address this, the website developed its own technology to find similar texts among millions of books and implemented it in the recommendation module. Now, when generating recommendations, Z-Library takes into account not only user behavior but also its unique text comparison technology. This means that when selecting recommended books, Z-Library analyzes the content of the books to provide more accurate and diverse suggestions.</p><p>Z-Library also reminds users to avoid accessing two fraudulent websites, namely z-lib[.] io and z-lib[.] id.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 10:55:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141526.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141526.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[近七成 iPhone 安装了 iOS 17]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>苹果披露了 iOS 17 和 iPadOS 17 的安装数据。</strong>据 developer.apple.com 网站，截至 2024 年 2 月 4 日：</p><ul><li><strong>iOS 17</strong><ul><li>在 App Store 上交易的所有 iPhone 中，有 66% 安装了 iOS 17。23% 仍在运行 iOS 16，其余 11% 仍在运行 iOS 15 及更早版本。</li><li>过去四年推出的所有 iPhone（iPhone 15、iPhone 14、iPhone 13、iPhone 12 和 iPhone SE 系列）中，76% 的设备运行 iOS 17，20% 运行 IOS 16 ，4% 使用 iOS 15 及更早版本。</li></ul></li><li><strong>iPadOS 17</strong><ul><li>53% 的注册 iPad 设备运行 iPadOS 17，29% 运行 iPadOS 16，18% 的设备运行旧版本。</li><li>过去四年中发布的 iPad 中，61% 运行 iPadOS 17，29% 运行 iPadOS 16，10% 运行旧版本。</li></ul></li></ul>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 10:13:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141517.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141517.html</link>
            <category>iOS</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
