<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 18:28:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[扩展] 你用的浏览器扩展被卖了？第一时间获得通知]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/no_name-1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>一位 Google 的软件开发人员发布了一个 Chrome 扩展程序，它可以在扩展的所有者发生变化时向用户发出警告。</strong>如果扩展的所有者信息发生变化，这枚名为」Under New Management」 的扩展（<a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/under-new-management/jppepdecgemgbgnjnnfjcmanlleioikj" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">主页</a>）图标旁将显示一个红色警告标志。开发者称，该扩展每小时检查一次 Chrome Web Store 中已安装扩展的开发者信息是否有变化。也就是说，只有 Chrome Web Store 上的所有者信息更新，用户才会收到通知。开发者同时还在开发 Firefox 版本。</p><p>历史上经常发生浏览器扩展易主导致的攻击事件。被第三方收购后，新的所有者可能向扩展添加恶意代码/跟踪器以攻击或跟踪用户。例如<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/43553.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">被出售的知名扩展 The Great Suspender</a>。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A software developer at Google has released a Chrome extension that alerts users when there is a change in the ownership of the extension. If there is a change in the extension’s ownership information, a red warning sign will be displayed next to the extension icon called 「Under New Management.」 The developer stated that the extension checks the developer information of installed extensions in the Chrome Web Store every hour for any changes. In other words, users will only receive a notification if there is an update to the ownership information on the Chrome Web Store. The developer is also working on a Firefox version of the extension.</p><p>In the past, there have been incidents of attacks related to changes in ownership of browser extensions. After being acquired by a third party, the new owner may add malicious code/trackers to the extension to attack or track users. For example, the well-known extension 「The Great Suspender」 that was sold.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 14:15:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142132.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142132.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[《纽约时报》要求开发者停止盗版其字谜游戏 Wordle]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>GitHub 上众多开发者收到了来自《纽约时报》的 DMCA 侵权通知。该媒体要求移除他们创建的 Wordle 游戏的克隆版本。</strong>《纽约时报》声称自己拥有该游戏的商标，以及特定的游戏元素，这些元素正被众多克隆版本使用。Wordle 是一款流行的猜单词游戏，《纽约时报》于 2022 年初以超过 100 万美元的价格收购了 Wordle，该游戏一直保持免费。据悉，纽时还向 Reactle 开发者发送了一份请求。Reactle 是一个在 GitHub 上的开源存储库，用户可以使用它来运行和创建自己的 Wordle 克隆游戏。这个存储库导致 Wordle 的大量仿制版本竞相出现。过去，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/78154.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">苹果也曾从 App Store 下架该游戏的大量盗版版本</a>。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Numerous developers on GitHub have received DMCA takedown notices from The New York Times, requesting the removal of their cloned versions of the Wordle game. The newspaper claims ownership of the game’s trademark and specific gameplay elements that are being utilized by many of these clone versions. Wordle is a popular word-guessing game that The New York Times acquired in early 2022 for over one million dollars, and it has remained free. It has been reported that The New York Times also sent a request to the developer of Reactle, an open-source repository on GitHub that allows users to run and create their own Wordle clone games. This repository has led to the proliferation of numerous counterfeit versions of Wordle. In the past, Apple has also taken down numerous pirated versions of the game from the App Store.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:10:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142127.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142127.html</link>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Android 14 电池健康仅适用于 Pixel 8a 以上机型]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>自去年底开始，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140440.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Android 14 预览版中出现了一个隐藏的电池状态页面</a>，其代码表明它可以显示电池当前能提供的估计电量。不过谷歌现在说，<strong>电池健康页面将仅适用于 Pixel 8a 及更高型号的设备。</strong>这也是谷歌首次提及廉价机型 Pixel 8a，该设备预计将在几个月内发布。尚不清楚谷歌为何不打算为现有的 Pixel 型号提供电池健康状态查询功能。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Since the end of last year, a hidden battery health page has appeared in the Android 14 preview version, indicating that it can display estimated battery capacity. However, Google now states that the battery health page will only be available for devices from Pixel 8a and higher models. This is also the first mention of the budget-friendly Pixel 8a by Google, which is expected to be released in the coming months. It is not yet clear why Google does not plan to provide battery health status for existing Pixel models.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:56:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142123.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142123.html</link>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Chrome Canary 版可将所有网页安装为 PWA 应用程序]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>在最新发布的 Chrome Canary V124 中，可以将所有网页转换为渐进式 Web 应用（PWA）。</strong>暂不清楚谷歌何时正式推出该功能。若要使用该功能，必须启用以下标志：chrome://flags/#web-app-universal-install 和 chrome://flags/#shortcuts-not-apps。然后可在浏览器右上角的 「保存和共享」 标题下的菜单中找到 PWA 功能。可以选择将网页安装为应用程序。当单击该应用程序时，该网站将在自己的窗口中打开。已拥有自己的 PWA 的网站（例如 Reddit 和 YouTube）将出现下载该应用的选项。除 ChromeOS 外，该功能还适用于 Windows、Mac 和 Linux。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the latest release of Chrome Canary V124, it is now possible to convert all web pages into Progressive Web Apps (PWAs). The official rollout date for this feature by Google is currently unknown. To use this functionality, the following flags must be enabled: chrome://flags/#web-app-universal-install and chrome://flags/#shortcuts-not-apps. The PWA feature can then be found in the menu under the 「Save and share」 section in the top-right corner of the browser. Users have the option to save the web page as an application. When the application is clicked, the website will open in its own window. Websites that already have their own PWAs, such as Reddit and YouTube, will display an option to download the application. This feature is available for Windows, Mac, Linux, and ChromeOS.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:46:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142120.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142120.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[OneDrive 将下线通过 URL 上传文件的功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软公司决定将于今年 3 月 29 日起从 OneDrive 移除通过 URL 上传文件的选项。</strong>因为该功能使用率低，且维护所需的工作量和成本太高。这是 OneDrive 在 2021 年推出的实验性功能，适用于所有 OneDrive 消费者用户。微软称该服务 「与我们将 OneDrive 作为云存储服务并在设备之间同步文件的愿景不符」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has decided to remove the option to upload files to OneDrive via URL starting from March 29th this year. This decision was made due to the low usage of this feature and the high maintenance workload and costs associated with it. The feature was introduced as an experimental functionality in OneDrive in 2021 and was available to all OneDrive consumer users. Microsoft stated that this service 「does not align with our vision of using OneDrive as a cloud storage service that synchronizes files between devices.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:39:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142117.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142117.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
