<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:53:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[电子书网站 Z-Library 入驻中国社交媒体]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GDEOQMNaIAA83wB.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>电子书网站 Z-Library 已入驻中国社交媒体 bilibili 和微信。</strong>该网站入驻后表现活跃，已经在 B 站发布了一则提醒用户避免访问仿冒网站的视频，并在微信公众号发布了多篇文章。在微信公号上，其 IP 属地显示为捷克，公号注册主体类型为 「个人」。有观察人士认为，Z-Library 可能 「又选错了地方」，这些账号很可能很快会被平台注意并处置。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The e-book website Z-Library has joined the Chinese social media platforms Bilibili and WeChat. Since its presence on these platforms, the website has been active. It has posted a video on Bilibili, reminding users to avoid visiting counterfeit websites, and has published multiple articles on its WeChat official account. The IP location of the WeChat official account is registered in the Czech Republic, and the account is registered under the category of 「individual.」Some observers believe that Z-Library may have 「chosen the wrong place」 again, and it is likely that these accounts will soon be noticed and dealt with by the platforms.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 08:58:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140846.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140846.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[发布「日本地震是报应」言论的主持人粉丝激增至 700 万]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站对所刊内容不持任何立场。</p></div></div></div><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GC_u3AJbkAArgcV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，因发布 「日本发生地震是报应」 言论引发争议的海南广电总枱主持人肖程皓的抖音粉丝数近日已从 69 万激增至 700 万。本周早些时候，这名主持人因上述言论被其供职的海南广播电视总枱<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140726.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">暂停工作</a>。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 16:32:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140835.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140835.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[抚州网警称「抚州警方处置加密货币」为虚假信息]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站对所刊内容不持任何立场。</p></div></div></div><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GC9qp8IacAAyu24.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>据官媒<a href="http://www.stcn.com/article/detail/1082106.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">证券时报</a>，江西省抚州市公安局网警通过微博辟谣称：近日，有网民通过微博、今日头条等网络平台传播 「抚州市公安局获批处置大额涉案国外数字加密货币」 的相关图文信息。经核实，相关内容为虚假信息。抚州网警提醒广大网民不造谣、不信谣、不传谣，公安机关将依法严厉打击网络谣言，维护清朗网络环境。</p><p>——此前社交媒体上流传一份 「会议决议文件」 照片，照片显示江西抚州公安局获得批准，将处理涉案的大量比特币和以太币，所得资金将被用于地方财政。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The Public Security Bureau Cybersecurity Division of Fuzhou City in Jiangxi Province, China, has debunked rumors through Weibo. Recently, some netizens have been spreading related text and image information on platforms such as Weibo and Toutiao, claiming that the Fuzhou City Public Security Bureau has been authorized to handle a large amount of foreign digital encrypted currencies. After verification, it has been confirmed that this information is false. Fuzhou Cybersecurity Division reminds the public not to create, believe, or spread rumors, as law enforcement agencies will strictly crack down on online rumors and maintain a clean online environment.</p><p>Previously, a photo of a 「meeting resolution document」 circulated on social media. The photo indicated that the Fuzhou Public Security Bureau in Jiangxi had been approved to handle a large amount of Bitcoin and Ethereum related to a case, and the funds obtained would be used for the local financial system.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 16:20:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140831.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140831.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Twitch 禁止直播时暗示身体裸露信息]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>亚马逊拥有的直播平台 Twitch 再度收紧了裸露政策。现在主播不再被允许 「暗示部分或完全裸体」。</strong>去年 12 月，Twitch 平台曾放宽了该政策。但 Twitch 发现有主播开始使用物体来隐藏身体或衣服，或使用特殊的角度放置摄像头，以制造裸体的印象，尽管很多主播实际并未裸体。Twitch 认为这种操作会破坏观众的体验。</p><p>去年 12 月，Twitch 曾放宽了裸露政策，新政策允许性暗示内容，但用户必须用 「性主题」 标签标记自己的直播，以免它们出现在首页上。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Amazon-owned live streaming platform Twitch has tightened its nudity policy once again. Streamers are no longer allowed to 「imply partial or full nudity.」 The policy was relaxed in December of last year, but Twitch found that some streamers were using objects to hide their bodies or clothing, or utilizing specific camera angles to create the impression of nudity. Despite not actually being nude, Twitch deemed this implication to be detrimental to the viewer experience.</p><p>In December of last year, Twitch relaxed its nudity policy, allowing for sexually suggestive content. However, users were required to label their streams with a 「Sexual Content」 tag to prevent them from appearing on the homepage.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 11:04:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140818.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140818.html</link>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[图] 新款 Windows 电脑将配备 「Copilot」 键]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/20240104174833.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软公司表示，今年发布的许多 Windows 11 PC 的键盘都将配备 Copilot 键。</strong>Microsoft Copilot 键可以快速打开同名的 Windows Copilot 人工智能应用程序。微软称这是近三十年来 Windows PC 键盘的首次重大变化。据悉，首批具有 Copilot 测试的 PC 将在 CES（国际消费类电子产品展览会）前宣布，并将于 2 月底上市。它还将添加到未来的 Surface 笔记本电脑中。</p><p>该键位于右侧 alt 键旁边，具体位置可能因制造商而异。如果用户无权访问 Copilot，则按该键将打开 Windows 搜索。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has announced that many Windows 11 PCs released this year will be equipped with a Copilot key. The Microsoft Copilot key allows for quick access to the Windows Copilot artificial intelligence application of the same name. According to Microsoft, this is the first significant change to Windows PC keyboards in nearly three decades. It is reported that the initial batch of PCs featuring Copilot testing will be announced before the CES (Consumer Electronics Show) and will be available for purchase by the end of February. It will also be added to future Surface laptops.</p><p>The key is located next to the right Alt key, although the exact placement may vary depending on the manufacturer. If users do not have access to Copilot, pressing the key will open Windows search.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 09:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140802.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140802.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
