<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:37:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[遊戲直播服務 Twitch 將退出韓國]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，亞馬遜旗下游戲直播服務 Twitch 宣佈將於 2024 年 2 月 27 日停止在韓國運營。其首席執行官 Dan Clancy 表示，做出這一決定是因為在該國運營 Twitch 的成本極高。Twitch 在韓國運營多年都是虧損的，因為該國的網絡費用比世界其他地區高出 10 倍。該公司曾嘗試多種方法來降低成本，例如使用 P2P 技術來提高片源質量，甚至將流的分辨率降低到 720p，但收效甚微。韓國是全球最大的視頻遊戲市場之一，退出該市場讓 Twitch「深感悲痛」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Amazon’s game streaming service Twitch announced that it will cease operations in South Korea on February 27, 2024. CEO Dan Clancy stated that this decision was made due to the extremely high operating costs in the country. Twitch has been running at a loss in South Korea for many years because the internet fees are ten times higher than other regions worldwide. The company had tried various methods to reduce costs, such as using P2P technology to improve video quality and even lowering the stream resolution to 720p, but with little success. South Korea is one of the largest video game markets globally, and withdrawing from this market has left Twitch 「deeply saddened.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:08:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139593.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139593.html</link>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟再次「閹割」了 new Bing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐實測發現，微軟再次 「閹割了」new Bing（Bing Chat）——<strong>每個會話現在僅支持 5 個回合，5 個回合後就會返回話題結束的提示</strong>。「&nbsp;很抱歉，此對話已達到其限制。使用 「掃除」 按鈕清除此內容並進行更多聊天。」</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has once again 「castrated」 new Bing (Bing Chat) – each conversation now only supports 5 rounds, and will return a prompt when the topic ends: 「Sorry, this conversation has reached its limit. Use the ‘clear’ button to clear this content and chat more.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:24:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139491.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139491.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[實測] 過去幾個月微軟 new Bing 進步緩慢]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231204141906.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐針對 new Bing 進行的大量測試還顯示，儘管微軟為它引入了很多新功能，<strong>但和幾個月之前相比，微軟 new Bing 的 「智商」 似乎並沒有顯著提高。和以前一樣，new Bing 頻繁地捏造答案、經常捏造並不存在的 「事實」，在指出錯誤之後，new Bing 會被 「激怒」 並立即結束當前會話。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Our extensive testing of new Bing also shows that although Microsoft has introduced many new features for it, compared to a few months ago, the 「intelligence」 of Microsoft’s new Bing does not seem to have significantly improved. Like before, new Bing frequently fabricates answers and often fabricates non-existent 「facts」. After pointing out the errors, new Bing will be 「angered」 and immediately end the current session.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:18:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139483.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139483.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[海量的「虛擬人」色情視頻正湧向互聯網]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231203183155.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐監控的數據顯示，<strong>成千上萬個由 AI 生成的 「虛擬人」 短視頻正在蜂擁湧向 YouTube、Facebook、TikTok、Instagram、X（Twitter）等主流社交媒體平台。</strong>我們重點追蹤的幾百個賬號正在日夜不停的利用 AI 創建視頻內容，這些內容相當一部分來自中國。為了快速獲取流量，<strong>這些賬號的操縱者從搜索引擎上批量獲取色情內容，並由 AI 虛擬人以自述的方式閲讀並生成視頻。我們發現某些視頻的播放量已突破千萬。由於這些視頻畫面中的虛擬人聲情並茂，不仔細甄別很容易誤以為是真人。</strong>大量不明真相的觀眾對這些視頻發表了評論。</p><p>社交媒體不會完全阻止虛擬人視頻，但可能會要求創作者向觀眾聲明視頻主角是虛擬人，並且仍會沿用當前的內容審核政策來審核這些視頻。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Thousands of AI-generated 「virtual human」 short videos are flooding towards mainstream social media platforms such as YouTube, Facebook, TikTok, Instagram, and X (Twitter). We have been closely monitoring hundreds of accounts that continuously use AI to create video content, with a significant portion originating from China. In order to quickly gain traffic, the operators of these accounts disclose obtaining pornographic content from search engines and generate videos in a self-narrative manner through AI virtual humans. We have found that the views on certain videos have already surpassed tens of millions. Due to the vivid portrayal of emotions by virtual humans in these videos, it is easy for uninformed viewers to mistake them for real people without careful discernment. A large number of unsuspecting audiences have commented on these videos.</p><p>Social media platforms may not completely block virtual human videos but may require creators to declare to the audience that the protagonist in the video is a virtual human. They will continue using their current content moderation policies to review these videos.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:33:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139471.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139471.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[傳微軟 2024 年夏天發佈 Windows 12]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，據台灣商業時報 (CTEE) ，微軟將於 2024 年 6 月發佈其下一代操作系統 <strong>Windows 12</strong>，以及各種基於人工智能的 PC。這一消息的來源是廣達電腦董事長林百里和宏碁董事長兼首席執行官陳俊聖最近在台灣醫療技術展覽會上的發言。林百里預期明年夏季隨着新一代的 Windows 作業系統時，AI PC 也將陸續推出。他看好這對 PC 硬件產業的機會。</p><p>這不是第一次出現有關 Windows 12 的傳聞。英特爾首席財務官最近也聲稱 Windows 12 將於 2024 年問世。更早前有德國媒體報道，微軟計劃<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138116.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">將 Windows 12 打造為一個基於訂閲的操作系統</a>。已經離開微軟的前 Windows 負責人 Panos Panay 也曾暗示，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/117042.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 12 將由 AI 深度驅動</a>。</p><p>與此同時，微軟還在緊鑼密鼓的開發 Windows 11 24H2，這是 Windows 11 的下一個功能更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Taiwan Business Times (CTEE), Microsoft will release its next-generation operating system, Windows 12, and various AI-based PCs in June 2024. The source of this news is the speeches given by Lin Baili, Chairman of Quanta Computer, and Chen Junsheng, Chairman and CEO of Acer, at a recent medical technology exhibition in Taiwan. Lin Baili expects that with the new generation of Windows operating system next summer, AI PCs will also be launched one after another. He sees this as an opportunity for the PC hardware industry.</p><p>This is not the first time rumors about Windows 12 have surfaced. Recently, Intel’s CFO also claimed that Windows 12 will be released in 2024. Earlier reports from German media stated that Microsoft plans to develop Windows 12 as a subscription-based operating system. Former head of Windows at Microsoft who has since left the company, Panos Panay, also hinted that Windows 12 would be driven by AI.</p><p>Meanwhile, Microsoft is also actively developing Windows 11 24H2, which is the next feature update for Windows 11.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 07:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
