<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 18:43:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[下載] 精簡版系統 tiny11 2311 發佈：基於 Win11 23H2 製作]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，Win11 第三方精簡版系統 tiny11 迎來更新，開發者 @NTDEV 現在基於 Windows 11 23H2 製作了新版本 <strong>tiny11 2311</strong>。<strong>tiny11 2311</strong> 包含了 Win11 23H2 的所有新功能，包括 Copilot、RAR 解壓縮支持、重新設計的音量滑塊、設置應用中的 RGB 控制等。與老版本相比，tiny11 2311 的體積縮小了 20%。並且可以接收微軟官方的服務更新。該版本沒有預裝 Edge 瀏覽器，刪除了 Xbox 相關功能（從微軟商店下載遊戲後會恢復）。</p><ul><li>讀者可從 <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a> 下載 tiny11 2311</li><li>網盤下載：請<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/wxa-6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">點此關注</a>公眾號 「軟餐」，發送口令&nbsp;<code><strong>139081</strong></code>獲取下載鏈接。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>[[Download] Simplified version system tiny11 2311 released: Based on Win11 23H2 production] The third-party lightweight version of Win11, tiny11, has received an update. Developer @NTDEV has now created a new version, tiny11 2311, based on Windows 11 23H2. Tiny11 2311 includes all the new features of Win11 23H2, including Copilot, RAR decompression support, redesigned volume slider, and RGB control in the Settings app. Compared to the previous version, tiny11 2311 has reduced its size by 20%. It can also receive official service updates from Microsoft. This version does not come pre-installed with Edge browser and removes Xbox-related functions (which will be restored after downloading games from the Microsoft Store).</p><p>Readers can download tiny11 2311 from <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a>.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 05:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[復旦教授肖仰華：我們與 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>復旦大學計算機科學技術學院教授、上海市數據科學重點實驗室主任肖仰華推測，ChatGPT 或許使用了大小模型結合的技術，多模型協同可以很大程度上解決成本問題。「讓大模型去解決複雜問題，但普通用戶一般都是簡單的問題，用小模型就可以了。」 他形容，ChatGPT 的 AI 技術已形成一種 「飛輪效應」，迭代和優化正推動技術進入一個自我強化的快速發展階段行業或將變成 「只有第一，沒有第二」 的局面。「我們的文化中，聰明人太多，總想抄近路。有時候就是要堅持，要笨一點，才能做出真正的大殺器。<strong>我們與 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大，不是在縮小。</strong>」 肖教授指出，還有很多如機器人、環境交互技術、醫療大模型、科學大模型等其他方向，都是大趨勢。企業可以在這些新領域找到自己的優勢。肖仰華指出，AI 技術的進步可能導致人類智力的相對退化。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Recently, Professor Xiaoyanghua, from the School of Computer Science and Technology at Fudan University and Director of the Shanghai Key Laboratory of Data Science, speculated that ChatGPT may have used a combination of large and small models to address cost issues. 「Let the large model solve complex problems, but ordinary users usually have simple questions that can be answered with a small model,」 he described. The AI technology of ChatGPT has formed a 「flywheel effect」, where iteration and optimization are driving the technology into a self-reinforcing rapid development stage. The industry may become a situation where there is only one leader without any competitors. 「In our culture, there are too many smart people who always want shortcuts. Sometimes we need to persist and be a little foolish in order to create truly powerful tools. The gap between us and OpenAI is widening rather than narrowing,」 Professor Xiao pointed out. He also mentioned that there are other emerging trends such as robotics, interactive environmental technologies, large-scale medical models, scientific models, etc., where companies can find their own advantages. Professor Xiaoyanghua indicated that advancements in AI technology could potentially lead to relative decline in human intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[誕生 20 週年，文本編輯器 Notepad++8.6 版發佈]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，文本編輯器 Notepad++官方發佈了最新的 Notepad++ 8.6 版，以紀念該編輯器誕生 20 週年。Notepad++ 8.6 是一個較小的版本，包含多處 Bug 修復、新的多重編輯功能（允許用戶在文本文檔的多個位置添加或刪除字符）、自定義多選背景和護理顏色等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The official release of the latest version, Notepad++ 8.6, has been announced by the text editor Notepad++, commemorating its 20th anniversary. Notepad++ 8.6 is a minor release that includes several bug fixes, new multiple editing capabilities (allowing users to add or remove characters at multiple positions within a text document), customizable multi-selection backgrounds and caret colors, and more.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:19:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</link>
            <category>辦公/生產力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Chrome 擴展商店迎來全新 UI 改版]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/20231122171854.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐訪問谷歌 Chrome 網上應用店看到，谷歌為該商店帶來了全面的 UI 更新。谷歌基於 Material You 風格重新設計了頁面，並增加了新的擴展分類。搜索欄已被放置在右上角，並新增了更多篩選選項。谷歌表示，由於圖標可讀性的提升和新的設計，現在瀏覽 Chrome 網上應用店變得更加容易。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google has brought a comprehensive UI update to the Chrome Web Store. Google has redesigned the pages based on the Material You style and added new extension categories. The search bar has been relocated to the top right corner, and additional filtering options have been introduced. According to Google, browsing the Chrome Web Store has become easier now with improved icon readability and the new design.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:32:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/138951.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/138951.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[YouTube 否認故意針對 Firefox 降速]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，谷歌否認針對 Firefox 瀏覽器故意延遲了 YouTube 的加載速度。該公司通過外媒發佈聲明稱：「<em>為了支持全球多元化的創作者生態系統，並讓數十億人在 YouTube 上訪問他們喜愛的內容，我們發起了一項活動，敦促啓用了廣告攔截器的觀看者允許在 YouTube 上投放廣告，或嘗試使用 YouTube Premium 以獲得無廣告體驗。<strong>安裝了廣告攔截器的用戶可能會遇到觀看效果不佳的情況，無論他們使用什麼瀏覽器。</strong></em>」</p><p>谷歌的聲明確實間接否認了傳言，並且指出延遲是因廣告攔截擴展引起的。本週早些時候，有 Reddit 用戶<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138878.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">發現</a>，YouTube 似乎置入了導致 Firefox 加載視頻延遲的代碼。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google denies deliberately delaying YouTube’s loading speed for Firefox. The company said in a statement: 「To support a diverse ecosystem of creators globally and allow billions to access their favorite content on YouTube, we’ve launched an effort to urge viewers with ad blockers enabled to allow ads on YouTube or try YouTube Premium for an ad free experience. Users who have ad blockers installed may experience suboptimal viewing, regardless of the browser they are using.」</p><p>Google’s statement did indirectly deny the rumors and pointed out that the delay was caused by the expansion of ad blocking. Earlier this week, Reddit users noticed that YouTube appeared to have embedded code that caused Firefox to delay loading videos.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 04:38:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/138942.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/138942.html</link>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
