<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 15:56:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[馬斯克稱將停用電話號碼，僅用 X 平台通信]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>馬斯克發文稱：「幾個月後，我將停止使用我的電話號碼，只使用 X 平台發消息和進行音頻/視頻通話。」</strong>據悉，馬斯克希望通過此舉，將 X（Twitter）平台轉型為一家可以盈利並與中國的微信分庭抗禮的社交平台。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 03:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141561.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141561.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google 密碼管理器將可與家人共享密碼]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>Google 密碼管理器將可以與伴侶或子女共享密碼。</strong>Google 並未透露該功能的發佈時間。要使用此功能，賬户必須已經使用 Family Link 登錄，這是 Google 的家庭管理系統，允許父母管理子女的手機。該選項的目的之一是在父母之間或父母與子女之間快速交換例如學校系統的密碼。許多密碼管理器已經具備了與其他用户共享密碼的選項。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google Password Manager will allow users to share passwords with their partners or children. Google has not disclosed the release date for this feature. To use this functionality, the account must already be logged in with Family Link, Google’s family management system that allows parents to manage their children’s phones. One of the purposes of this option is to facilitate the quick exchange of passwords, such as school system passwords, between parents or between parents and children. Many password managers already have options to share passwords with other users.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141532.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[蘋果 Vision Pro 曝重大疏漏：忘記密碼需重置設備]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>購買了蘋果混合現實頭顯 Apple Vision Pro 的用户發現，如果忘記了該頭顯的密碼，他們將不得不把設備送回蘋果商店或運回蘋果，才能重置密碼。</strong>這裏説的密碼並非 Apple ID 電子郵箱和密碼，而是實際訪問 Vision Pro 時需要輸入的一組數字。消費者必須牢記這組密碼，一旦忘記，頭顯需要完全恢復出廠設置，用户需要重新下載應用程序並重新設置 Vision Pro。據悉，大量相關的抱怨已經湧入蘋果的客户支持部門，服務人員為沒有做好應對而致歉。蘋果公司尚未就此問題進行迴應。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Users who have purchased the Apple mixed reality headset, Apple Vision Pro, have discovered that if they forget the password for the headset, they will have to send the device back to an Apple store or ship it to Apple to have the password reset. The password referred to here is not the Apple ID email and password but a set of numbers required to access the Vision Pro itself. Consumers must remember this password, as forgetting it would require a complete factory reset of the headset, leading users to have to re-download applications and reconfigure the Vision Pro. Numerous complaints regarding this issue have reportedly flooded Apple’s customer support department, and Apple has apologized for not being adequately prepared to address the problem. The company has not yet responded to this issue.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:42:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141551.html</link>
            <category>iOS</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[去中心化社交應用 Bluesky 全面開放用户註冊]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>去中心化的社交媒體應用程序 Bluesky 全面開放了用户註冊</strong>（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.blueskyweb.app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Play 商店</a>）<strong>。</strong>現在任何人無需邀請即可註冊賬號。在開放註冊之前，該應用增強了其基礎設施和內容審核能力。Bluesky 於 2023 年 3 月<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/121704.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">推出</a>，一直以來採用邀請制模式，此前超過 300 萬註冊了該應用。Bluesky 官方還宣佈，未來幾周或幾個月將推出一些新功能，包括：為想要進一步審核其 Feed 的用户提供標籤服務、允許開發者和其他組織使用自己的審核規則創建自己的 Bluesky 服務器、提供類似於 X 的收費額外功能等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The decentralized social media application Bluesky has opened up user registration to the public. Now anyone can sign up for an account without needing an invitation. Prior to opening up registration, the app enhanced its infrastructure and content moderation capabilities. Launched in March 2023, Bluesky had been operating on an invitation-only basis and attracted over 3 million registrations. Bluesky’s official announcement also revealed that new features will be rolled out in the coming weeks or months, including labeling services for users who want to further moderate their feed, allowing developers and other organizations to create their own Bluesky servers with their own moderation rules, and offering additional paid features similar to X.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Spotify 月活用户突破 6 億]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2006422084.jpeg.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p><strong>Spotify 首次突破了 6 億月度活躍用户的大關。</strong>過去一個季度，其用户數量增加了 2800 萬，略高於預期。該公司披露，在在 6.02 億月活躍用户中，有 2.36 億人為付費訂户。這比一年前增加了 15％，對應增加 3100 萬名訂閲者。在過去一個季度，訂户數量增加了 1000 萬。無論是活躍用户數量還是高級訂閲者數量都超過了預期。<strong>這家流媒體服務公司在上一季度再次虧損，虧損金額 7500 萬歐元。其收入達 37 億歐元，符合預期。</strong>這比一年前增長了 16％。大部分收入仍然來自高級訂閲者，達到了 32 億歐元。而在此之前的一個季度，Spotify 自 2021 年以來首次實現了盈利。Spotify 解釋説，虧損是 「促進效率的行動」 造成的。這可能指的是為了節省成本而裁員 17％。</p><p><strong>Spotify 預計下一個季度用户數量仍將繼續增長，並計劃在三個月內達到 6.18 億活躍用户。收入預計將保持相對穩定，該平台預計將獲得 1.8 億歐元的利潤。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Spotify has surpassed 600 million monthly active users for the first time. In the past quarter, its user base increased by 28 million, slightly exceeding expectations. The company revealed that out of the 602 million monthly active users, 236 million are paid subscribers. This represents a 15% increase compared to a year ago, with an additional 31 million subscribers since the beginning of 2023. The number of subscribers grew by 10 million in the past quarter. Both the active user count and the number of premium subscribers exceeded expectations by one million. Spotify saw higher-than-expected growth in subscriber numbers in Latin America and the Rest of the World, meaning regions outside of the Americas and Europe.</p><p>Spotify’s revenue in the past quarter reached €3.7 billion, in line with expectations. This represents a 16% increase compared to the previous year. The majority of revenue still comes from premium subscribers, amounting to €3.2 billion. The streaming service reported a loss of €75 million, while in the previous quarter, Spotify achieved its first profit since 2021. Spotify attributes this loss to 「actions to promote efficiency,」 which cost the company €143 million. Presumably, the platform is referring to the 17% reduction in staff to cut costs.</p><p>Spotify expects the user count to continue growing in the next quarter and anticipates reaching 618 million active users in three months. Revenue is projected to remain relatively stable, and the platform expects to achieve a profit of €180 million.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:09:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141535.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141535.html</link>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
