<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 11:40:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[中国考虑采取一揽子措施稳定股市]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>据<a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/753737426_161795" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">南方都市报</a>，23 日券商中国援引彭博社消息，<strong>目前，中国正在考虑采取一揽子措施来稳定股市，涉及的金额比较大。</strong>但上述消息未获官方证实。昨天晚上，国务院常务会议指出，要采取 「强有力」 的措施稳定资本市场。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>On the 23rd, Chinese brokerage firm China Securities cited Bloomberg news that China is currently considering a package of measures to stabilize the stock market, involving a significant amount of funds. However, the aforementioned news has not been officially confirmed. Last night, the executive meeting of the State Council emphasized the need to take 「strong」 measures to stabilize the capital market.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 08:50:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141279.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141279.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[曝新版 Outlook 与 700 多家广告商通信]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，瑞士加密邮箱开发商 Proton 近日声称，<strong>微软的新版 Outlook 应用程序正在与 770 多个广告合作伙伴进行通信。</strong>Proton 称，新版 Outlook for Windows 应用程序会向欧盟用户弹出一个用户协议弹窗，其中提到微软公司会与 772 个第三方共享用户的数据。只有欧盟用户能看到这个弹窗，因为欧盟《通用数据保护条例》（GDPR）强制要求 Web 服务通知用户有关数据收集和 Cookie 的信息。弹出的协议允许这些实体执行展示、衡量个性化广告和内容、在用户设备上存储和/或访问信息、获取精确的地理位置数据、通过设备扫描识别用户等操作。Proton 还表示，Microsoft Outlook 从用户处会收集多种数据，包括姓名和联系方式、密码、人口统计数据、付款数据、订阅和许可数据等等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Swiss encrypted email provider Proton has recently claimed that Microsoft’s new version of the Outlook application is communicating with over 770 advertising partners. Proton states that the new Outlook for Windows application displays a user agreement pop-up to European Union (EU) users, mentioning that Microsoft will share user data with 772 third-party entities. Only EU users can see this pop-up as the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) mandates web services to inform users about data collection and cookies. The displayed agreement allows these entities to perform activities such as displaying, measuring personalized ads and content, storing and/or accessing information on user devices, obtaining precise geolocation data, and identifying users through device scanning. Proton indicates that Microsoft Outlook collects various data from users, including names and contact information, passwords, demographic data, payment data, subscription and licensing data, and more.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 10:08:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141268.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141268.html</link>
            <category>办公/生产力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软正将部分「邮件和日历」用户迁至新版 Outlook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软已开始将 「<strong>邮件和日历</strong>」（Mail and Calendar）<strong>用户</strong>迁移到新的 Outlook 应用程序。</strong>系统会向 「邮件和日历」 用户显示简短通知，之后用户将被重定向到新的 Outlook 应用，并且没有提供停止重定向的选项。目前重定向仅为部分用户推出。微软去年<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/132758.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">宣布</a>，到 2024 年底，全新的 Outlook for Windows 应用程序将替换当前的 「邮件和日历」 应用程序。并不是所有用户都喜欢新版 Outlook 应用程序，因为新版本似乎更慢，并且不是原生的应用程序。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has initiated the migration of 「Mail and Calendar」 users to the new Outlook application. Users of 「Mail and Calendar」 will receive brief notifications, after which they will be redirected to the new Outlook app, with no option to stop the redirection. Currently, the redirection is being rolled out to a portion of the users. Microsoft announced last year that by the end of 2024, the new Outlook for Windows application will replace the current 「Mail and Calendar」 app. However, not all users are satisfied with the new version of the Outlook app as it appears to be slower and is not a native application.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:47:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141264.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141264.html</link>
            <category>办公/生产力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Chrome 发布更新，修复四个安全漏洞]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>谷歌日前为 Chrome 浏览器发布更新，修复了桌面版和 Android 版中的四个安全漏洞。</strong>其中一个已在野外被利用。最新版本号为 120.0.6099.234（Mac 版）、120.0.6099.224（Linux 版）、120.0.6099.224 或 120.0.6099.225（Windows 版）。谷歌公布了其中的三个漏洞，即 CVE-2024-0517、CVE-2024-0518 和 CVE-2024-0519。谷歌确认 CVE-2025-0519 在野外被利用。其他基于 Chromium 的浏览器也会受到这些问题的影响，预计也将很快推出更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google recently released an update for the Chrome browser, addressing four security vulnerabilities in both the desktop and Android versions. One of these vulnerabilities was being actively exploited in the wild. The latest version numbers are 120.0.6099.234 for Mac, 120.0.6099.224 for Linux, and 120.0.6099.224 or 120.0.6099.225 for Windows. Google disclosed three of the vulnerabilities as CVE-2024-0517, CVE-2024-0518, and CVE-2024-0519. Google has confirmed that CVE-2025-0519 is being actively exploited. Other Chromium-based browsers are also expected to be affected by these issues and are likely to release updates soon.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:28:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141261.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141261.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[油管将迎来裁员]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>据华尔街日报，YouTube 将裁减数目不详的职位。Alphabet 首席商务官 Mary Ellen Coe 周三在一份内部通知中宣布了上述消息。上周，Alphabet 裁减了 1,000 多名员工。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>YouTube will be cutting an undisclosed number of positions. Mary Ellen Coe, Chief Business Officer of Alphabet, announced this news in an internal memo on Wednesday. Last week, Alphabet laid off over 1,000 employees.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:05:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141259.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141259.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
