<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 19:15:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[《证券时报》删除了《为上证指数正名》一文]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-exclamation-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站对所刊内容不持任何立场。</p></div></div></div><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231225183532.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>《证券时报》已经从其官网删除了早前发布的《为上证指数正名》一文。这篇文章声称上证指数的财富回报率领先于美国三大指数</strong>。文章指出，上证指数的长期增长速度是很高的，甚至比许多历史悠久的股票指数都要高得多。道指发布于 1896 年 5 月 26 日，到 2023 年已经有 127 年的历史。在这 127 年间，道指从 40.94 点上涨到 3.74 万点，累计涨幅 913 倍，道指年复合增长率（CAGR）是 5.5%。上证指数的基期（也就是成立日期）是 1990 年 12 月 19 日，基点（最开始的点位）是 100 点。设立 33 年之后的 2023 年 12 月 21 日，上证指数的点位是 2918 点。33 年累计涨幅是 28 倍，CAGR 是 10.8%，几乎是道指的 2 倍。</p><p><em>这篇文章在《证券时报》开设的多个新媒体账号上仍然可见，并已被广泛转载。</em></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 10:46:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140564.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140564.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[游戏工委人士称可对「网游新规」意见稿畅所欲言]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-exclamation-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>文中涉及观点不代表本站。本站对报道对象不持任何观点。</p></div></div></div><p>今日，新闻出版署最新发布的《网络游戏管理办法（草案征求意见稿）》引发热议。其中提到，网络游戏不得设置每日登录、首次充值、连续充值等诱导性奖励；所有网络游戏须设置用户充值限额。这些规定或将直接影响游戏的日活与盈利能力。据澎湃新闻，针对意见稿引发的反应，<strong>中国音数协游戏工委内部人士表示，既然是征求意见稿，表明目前阶段各界均可畅所欲言，以使其切实可行，更为完善。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Today, the latest 「Administrative Measures for Online Game Management (Draft for Soliciting Opinions)」 released by the National Press and Publication Administration has sparked heated discussions. It mentions that online games should not have inducement rewards such as daily login rewards, first-time recharge rewards, and consecutive recharge rewards; all online games must set user recharge limits. These regulations may directly affect the daily active users and profitability of games. According to The Paper, an insider from the China Audio-Video and Digital Publishing Association’s Games Committee stated that since it is a draft for soliciting opinions, it indicates that at this stage, everyone can freely express their views in order to make it practical and more perfect.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 10:50:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140454.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140454.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软弃用混合现实平台 Windows Mixed Reality]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软宣布启用 Windows Mixed Reality 平台。</strong>微软称：「Windows Mixed Reality 已弃用，并将在 Windows 的未来版本中删除。此弃用包括混合现实门户应用，以及适用于 SteamVR 和 Steam VR Beta 的 Windows Mixed Reality。」</p><p>微软在 2015 年 1 月对外展示了 Microsoft HoloLens 增强现实 / 混合现实头显设备，并对此抱有雄心。HoloLens 及其随附的平台框架在当时被称为 「Windows Holographic」，但在 2017 年，它更名为 「Windows Mixed Reality」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft announced the activation of the Windows Mixed Reality platform. Microsoft stated, 「Windows Mixed Reality has been deprecated and will be removed in future versions of Windows. This deprecation includes the Mixed Reality Portal app as well as Windows Mixed Reality for SteamVR and Steam VR Beta.」</p><p>In January 2015, Microsoft showcased the Microsoft HoloLens augmented reality/mixed reality headset device to the public and had ambitious plans for it. The HoloLens and its accompanying platform framework were initially referred to as 「Windows Holographic,」 but in 2017, it was renamed 「Windows Mixed Reality.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140342.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140342.html</link>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软修复了 Win11 的一个「老大难」问题]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231219184152.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>2023-适用于 Windows 11 Version 22H2 的 11 累积更新，适合基于 x64 的系统 (KB5032288)</p></blockquote><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>此更新解决了影响文件资源管理器窗口的问题。即当您不希望它们出现时，它们会在前台显示。</p></blockquote><p>软餐获悉，在 12 月 4 日发布的 Windows 11 可选非安全更新 KB5032288 中，微软终于修复了一个存在于 Windows 11 文件资源管理器上的 「老大难」 问题——<strong>用户在使用 Windows 11 时，无论是使用浏览器、玩游戏或写代码，文件资源管理器经常莫名其妙的获取焦点并出现在屏幕上。这次更新已经修复了该问题。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the Windows 11 optional non-security update KB5032288 released on December 4th, Microsoft finally fixed a 「difficult」 issue that existed in the Windows 11 File Explorer. When using Windows 11, whether it’s browsing the internet, playing games, or coding, the File Explorer would frequently and inexplicably gain focus and appear on the screen. This update has resolved this problem.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>2023 – Cumulative Update for Windows 11 Version 22H2 for x64-based Systems (KB5032288)</p></blockquote><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>This update addresses an issue affecting File Explorer windows where they would appear in the foreground when you don’t want them to.</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 10:42:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140234.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140234.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[实测] Edge 浏览器终于迎来「超级拖拽」功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231219171317.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软终于为 Edge 浏览器带来了超级拖放（Super Drag and Drop）功能。软餐实测发现，它已出现在 Edge 121 稳定版（121.0.2277.4&nbsp;）中。</strong>只需在链接、文本或图片上单击鼠标，同时向浏览器地址栏方向拖动，即可在新标签页中打开它。如果拖拽的对象是文本，Edge 浏览器则会打开默认搜索引擎搜索文本——超级拖放功能对于 Chrome 或 Firefox 用户并不陌生。</p><p>目前需要手动启用 Edge 超级拖拽功能，方法是访问 edge://flags/#edge-super-drag-drop 并将标志启用，重启 Edge 浏览器，然后进入设置 – 外观 – 将 「启用超级拖放」 开关开启即可。你还可以在设置中选择在后台或前台打开超级拖拽的页面。<strong>我们的测试显示，该功能在 Edge 稳定版上运行良好。</strong><a href="https://cdn.neowin.com/news/images/uploaded/2023/12/1702926184_microsoft_edge_super_drag_and_drop.jpg"></a></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has finally brought the Super Drag and Drop feature to the Edge browser. Soft meal testing found that it has appeared in the stable, Dev, and Canary versions of Edge. Simply right-click or click on a link, text, or image and drag it towards the browser address bar to open it in a new tab. If the dragged object is text, Edge will use the default search engine to search for the text – Super Drag and Drop is not unfamiliar to Chrome or Firefox users.</p><p>Currently, you need to manually enable the Edge Super Drag and Drop feature by visiting edge://flags/#edge-super-drag-drop and enabling the flag, restarting Edge browser, then going into Settings – Appearance – toggle on 「Enable super drag and drop」. You can also choose whether to open super drag and drop pages in background or foreground in settings. Our tests show that this feature works well on the stable version of Edge.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 09:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140217.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140217.html</link>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
