<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 23:47:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[图] 微软发布 2023 款「丑毛衣」Windows Ugly Sweater]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/1701176110_bliss_ugly_sweaters_image_story.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，在西方假日季临近之际，微软按照传统推出了 2023 年的 「Windows 丑陋毛衣」(Windows Ugly Sweater)。微软没有停止怀旧，这次在毛衣上印上了经典的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/131375.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows XP 默认的 Bliss 壁纸</a>。过去几年，微软还曾在丑陋毛衣上印制 Windows 95、扫雷游戏、微软画图（MS Paint）和 Clippy（大眼夹/回形针）等形象。消费者可通过 windowsuglysweater.com 网站购买 「丑陋毛衣」，微软将把销售所得的 10 万美元捐给大自然保护协会（The&nbsp;Nature&nbsp;Conservancy）。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>As the Western holiday season approaches, Microsoft has traditionally released the 「Windows Ugly Sweater」 for 2023. Microsoft continues its nostalgia by printing the classic Windows XP default Bliss wallpaper on the sweater. In recent years, Microsoft has also printed Windows 95, Minesweeper game, MS Paint, and Clippy (the paperclip) images on ugly sweaters. Consumers can purchase the 「ugly sweater」 through the website windowsuglysweater.com, and Microsoft will donate $100,000 of sales proceeds to The Nature Conservancy (TNC).</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:52:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[字节跳动打造爆款游戏的计划落空了]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，消息人士称，字节跳动的游戏部门朝夕光年日前大举裁员，其幕后是创始人张一鸣和董事会主席梁汝波等高管不满意其表现。因为该部门一直未能开发出在全球大热的游戏，其游戏产品亦难以留住玩家。字节跳动近年来在游戏上投入了数十亿美元，并收购了热门游戏开发商，但收效甚微。收缩游戏部门是字节跳动精简业务并专注核心业务计划中的一环。本月，字节跳动还裁减了 VR 头戴设备业务 Pico 的团队。</p><p>据悉，字节跳动正转而专注 TikTok、抖音和电商等核心业务领域。最近 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139114.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TikTok 正试图在美国复制直播带货模式</a>，以挑战亚马逊、Temu 和希音 (Shein) 等对手。今年上半年，该公司的收入同比增长约 37%，逾 530 亿美元。字节跳动希望借助调整保持增长势头。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Insiders say that ByteDance’s gaming division recently carried out massive layoffs, driven by dissatisfaction from founder Zhang Yiming and Chairman of the Board Liang Rubo, among other executives. The division has been unable to develop globally popular games and its game products have struggled to retain players. In recent years, ByteDance has invested billions of dollars in gaming and acquired popular game developers, but with little success.</p><p>The contraction of the gaming division is part of ByteDance’s plan to streamline its business and focus on core operations. This month, ByteDance also downsized the team at Pico, a VR headset business. The company will now concentrate on core businesses such as TikTok, Douyin (the Chinese version of TikTok), and e-commerce. Recently, TikTok has been attempting to replicate the live-streaming shopping model in the United States to challenge competitors like Amazon, Temu, and Shein.</p><p>ByteDance hopes to maintain its growth momentum through strategic adjustments. In the first half of this year alone, the company’s revenue increased by approximately 37% compared to last year, surpassing $53 billion USD.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139198.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139198.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Instagram 推送了数量惊人的不雅短视频]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，华尔街日报的一项测试显示，Meta 旗下社交媒体 <strong>Instagram 的 Reels 视频服务向该媒体建立的测试账号推送了数量惊人的不雅内容。</strong>这包括儿童不雅视频和露骨的成人色情视频，以及一些美国大品牌的广告。该媒体还观察到，在青少年网红账户的成千上万名粉丝中，经常包含有大量成年男性，后者也表现出对儿童和成人性内容的兴趣。儿童保护组织加拿大儿童保护中心 (Canadian Centre for Child Protection) 进行的测试也得出了类似的结果。</p><p>Meta 发言人回应称，《华尔街日报》的测试并不代表数十亿用户所看到的内容。对于为什么算法会将显示儿童、性和广告的不同视频编排在一起，该公司不予置评，Instagram 每个月都会对 400 万个涉嫌违反其标准的视频进行删除或限流。</p><p>Instagram Reels 短视频的广告主包括 Match、Bumble、迪士尼、沃尔玛、Hims、必胜客等知名公司，这些公司要么对 Meta 的回应表示不满，要么不予置评。可以肯定的是，这些知名品牌都不希望在不当内容旁投放广告，因为这有损其品牌形象。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A test conducted by The Wall Street Journal revealed that Meta’s social media platform, Instagram, pushed an alarming amount of explicit content to a test account created by the media outlet. This included inappropriate videos involving children, explicit adult content, as well as advertisements from some major American brands. The media outlet also observed that among the tens of thousands of followers of teenage influencer accounts, there was a significant presence of adult males who displayed an interest in both child and adult sexual content. Similar results were obtained in tests conducted by the Canadian Centre for Child Protection.</p><p>A spokesperson for Meta responded by stating that The Wall Street Journal’s test does not represent the content seen by billions of users. The company refrained from commenting on why the algorithm would group together different videos featuring children, sex, and advertisements. Instagram removes or limits the visibility of around 4 million videos each month that are suspected of violating its standards.</p><p>Prominent companies such as Match, Bumble, Disney, Walmart, Hims, and Pizza Hut advertise on Instagram’s Reels short video feature, and they either expressed dissatisfaction with Meta’s response or refrained from commenting. It is evident that these well-known brands do not want their advertisements to appear alongside inappropriate content as it would harm their brand image.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:30:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[中国市场对苹果 iPhone 15 的需求依然强劲]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，Wedbush 分析师 Dan Ives 称，苹果公司新发布的 iPhone 15 在节日季需求强劲。该机构调查显示，在进入重要的节日季之际，苹果公司的 iPhone 15 需求仍然非常坚挺，尤其是在中国地区。没有看到亚洲市场对 iPhone 机型的需求有任何重大的负面修正，这说明了 iPhone 15 的消费需求环境非常稳定。这位分析师估计，仅中国就有超过 1 亿部 iPhone 处于 「升级机会的窗口期」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>[The demand for Apple’s iPhone 15 in the Chinese market remains strong] Wedbush analyst Dan Ives said that the newly released iPhone 15 by Apple has strong demand during the holiday season. The survey conducted by this institution shows that the demand for iPhone 15 from Apple remains very robust, especially in China, as it enters an important holiday season. There have been no significant negative revisions to the demand for iPhone models in Asian markets, indicating a stable consumer demand environment for iPhone 15. This analyst estimates that there are over 100 million iPhones in China alone in a 「window of opportunity」 for upgrades.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 07:40:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139100.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139100.html</link>
            <category>iOS</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[下载] 精简版系统 tiny11 2311 发布：基于 Win11 23H2 制作]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，Win11 第三方精简版系统 tiny11 迎来更新，开发者 @NTDEV 现在基于 Windows 11 23H2 制作了新版本 <strong>tiny11 2311</strong>。<strong>tiny11 2311</strong> 包含了 Win11 23H2 的所有新功能，包括 Copilot、RAR 解压缩支持、重新设计的音量滑块、设置应用中的 RGB 控制等。与老版本相比，tiny11 2311 的体积缩小了 20%。并且可以接收微软官方的服务更新。该版本没有预装 Edge 浏览器，删除了 Xbox 相关功能（从微软商店下载游戏后会恢复）。</p><ul><li>读者可从 <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a> 下载 tiny11 2311</li><li>网盘下载：请<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/wxa-6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">点此关注</a>公众号 「软餐」，发送口令&nbsp;<code><strong>139081</strong></code>获取下载链接。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>[[Download] Simplified version system tiny11 2311 released: Based on Win11 23H2 production] The third-party lightweight version of Win11, tiny11, has received an update. Developer @NTDEV has now created a new version, tiny11 2311, based on Windows 11 23H2. Tiny11 2311 includes all the new features of Win11 23H2, including Copilot, RAR decompression support, redesigned volume slider, and RGB control in the Settings app. Compared to the previous version, tiny11 2311 has reduced its size by 20%. It can also receive official service updates from Microsoft. This version does not come pre-installed with Edge browser and removes Xbox-related functions (which will be restored after downloading games from the Microsoft Store).</p><p>Readers can download tiny11 2311 from <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a>.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 05:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
