<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:53:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[電子書網站 Z-Library 入駐中國社交媒體]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GDEOQMNaIAA83wB.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>電子書網站 Z-Library 已入駐中國社交媒體 bilibili 和微信。</strong>該網站入駐後表現活躍，已經在 B 站發佈了一則提醒用户避免訪問仿冒網站的視頻，並在微信公眾號發佈了多篇文章。在微信公號上，其 IP 屬地顯示為捷克，公號註冊主體類型為 「個人」。有觀察人士認為，Z-Library 可能 「又選錯了地方」，這些賬號很可能很快會被平台注意並處置。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The e-book website Z-Library has joined the Chinese social media platforms Bilibili and WeChat. Since its presence on these platforms, the website has been active. It has posted a video on Bilibili, reminding users to avoid visiting counterfeit websites, and has published multiple articles on its WeChat official account. The IP location of the WeChat official account is registered in the Czech Republic, and the account is registered under the category of 「individual.」Some observers believe that Z-Library may have 「chosen the wrong place」 again, and it is likely that these accounts will soon be noticed and dealt with by the platforms.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 08:58:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140846.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140846.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[發佈「日本地震是報應」言論的主持人粉絲激增至 700 萬]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站對所刊內容不持任何立場。</p></div></div></div><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GC_u3AJbkAArgcV.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，因發佈 「日本發生地震是報應」 言論引發爭議的海南廣電總枱主持人肖程皓的抖音粉絲數近日已從 69 萬激增至 700 萬。本週早些時候，這名主持人因上述言論被其供職的海南廣播電視總枱<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140726.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">暫停工作</a>。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 16:32:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140835.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140835.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[撫州網警稱「撫州警方處置加密貨幣」為虛假信息]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站對所刊內容不持任何立場。</p></div></div></div><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/GC9qp8IacAAyu24.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>據官媒<a href="http://www.stcn.com/article/detail/1082106.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">證券時報</a>，江西省撫州市公安局網警通過微博闢謠稱：近日，有網民通過微博、今日頭條等網絡平台傳播 「撫州市公安局獲批處置大額涉案國外數字加密貨幣」 的相關圖文信息。經核實，相關內容為虛假信息。撫州網警提醒廣大網民不造謠、不信謠、不傳謠，公安機關將依法嚴厲打擊網絡謠言，維護清朗網絡環境。</p><p>——此前社交媒體上流傳一份 「會議決議文件」 照片，照片顯示江西撫州公安局獲得批准，將處理涉案的大量比特幣和以太幣，所得資金將被用於地方財政。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The Public Security Bureau Cybersecurity Division of Fuzhou City in Jiangxi Province, China, has debunked rumors through Weibo. Recently, some netizens have been spreading related text and image information on platforms such as Weibo and Toutiao, claiming that the Fuzhou City Public Security Bureau has been authorized to handle a large amount of foreign digital encrypted currencies. After verification, it has been confirmed that this information is false. Fuzhou Cybersecurity Division reminds the public not to create, believe, or spread rumors, as law enforcement agencies will strictly crack down on online rumors and maintain a clean online environment.</p><p>Previously, a photo of a 「meeting resolution document」 circulated on social media. The photo indicated that the Fuzhou Public Security Bureau in Jiangxi had been approved to handle a large amount of Bitcoin and Ethereum related to a case, and the funds obtained would be used for the local financial system.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 16:20:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140831.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140831.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Twitch 禁止直播時暗示身體裸露信息]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>亞馬遜擁有的直播平台 Twitch 再度收緊了裸露政策。現在主播不再被允許 「暗示部分或完全裸體」。</strong>去年 12 月，Twitch 平台曾放寬了該政策。但 Twitch 發現有主播開始使用物體來隱藏身體或衣服，或使用特殊的角度放置攝像頭，以製造裸體的印象，儘管很多主播實際並未裸體。Twitch 認為這種操作會破壞觀眾的體驗。</p><p>去年 12 月，Twitch 曾放寬了裸露政策，新政策允許性暗示內容，但用户必須用 「性主題」 標籤標記自己的直播，以免它們出現在首頁上。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Amazon-owned live streaming platform Twitch has tightened its nudity policy once again. Streamers are no longer allowed to 「imply partial or full nudity.」 The policy was relaxed in December of last year, but Twitch found that some streamers were using objects to hide their bodies or clothing, or utilizing specific camera angles to create the impression of nudity. Despite not actually being nude, Twitch deemed this implication to be detrimental to the viewer experience.</p><p>In December of last year, Twitch relaxed its nudity policy, allowing for sexually suggestive content. However, users were required to label their streams with a 「Sexual Content」 tag to prevent them from appearing on the homepage.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 11:04:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140818.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140818.html</link>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[圖] 新款 Windows 電腦將配備 「Copilot」 鍵]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/20240104174833.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟公司表示，今年發佈的許多 Windows 11 PC 的鍵盤都將配備 Copilot 鍵。</strong>Microsoft Copilot 鍵可以快速打開同名的 Windows Copilot 人工智能應用程序。微軟稱這是近三十年來 Windows PC 鍵盤的首次重大變化。據悉，首批具有 Copilot 測試的 PC 將在 CES（國際消費類電子產品展覽會）前宣佈，並將於 2 月底上市。它還將添加到未來的 Surface 筆記本電腦中。</p><p>該鍵位於右側 alt 鍵旁邊，具體位置可能因製造商而異。如果用户無權訪問 Copilot，則按該鍵將打開 Windows 搜索。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has announced that many Windows 11 PCs released this year will be equipped with a Copilot key. The Microsoft Copilot key allows for quick access to the Windows Copilot artificial intelligence application of the same name. According to Microsoft, this is the first significant change to Windows PC keyboards in nearly three decades. It is reported that the initial batch of PCs featuring Copilot testing will be announced before the CES (Consumer Electronics Show) and will be available for purchase by the end of February. It will also be added to future Surface laptops.</p><p>The key is located next to the right Alt key, although the exact placement may vary depending on the manufacturer. If users do not have access to Copilot, pressing the key will open Windows search.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 09:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140802.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140802.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
