<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:26:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[被广泛批评后，Meta 希望将「去广告」服务价格减半]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，Meta 的一位高管周二表示，<strong>该公司提出将 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月订阅费从 9.99 欧元减半至 5.99 欧元，以消除欧盟监管监管机构的担忧。</strong>此次降价是在隐私活动人士和消费者团体对 Meta 在欧盟的无广告订阅服务提出批评之后进行的，批评者称该服务要求用户付费以确保其隐私。现在，欧盟的隐私保护活动人士并不认可降价方案，他们认为这与价格无关，即使降价到 1.99 欧元或更低，也会导致用户选择 「同意」，即接受在访问 Meta 服务的同时浏览广告。上周，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">39 名欧盟议员发出公开信，希望 Meta 停止提供该付费去广告模式</a>。Meta 于 11 月推出了付费去广告订阅计划，以遵守《数字市场法案》(DMA)，该法案限制了其在未经用户同意的情况下为用户提供个性化广告的能力，从而损害了其主要收入来源。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[iPhone 借力谷歌 Gemini，暗示苹果 AI 研发缓慢]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>我们稍早前<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142426.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">报道</a>，苹果正与 Google 讨论向新款 iPhone 植入后者的 Gemini 人工智能引擎。这无疑对 iPhone 和 Gemini AI 模型都是双赢的局面。但华尔街日报评论说，这 「<strong>同时也可能意味着，苹果公司开发自身 AI 能力的进展可能比投资者希望的要慢。</strong>」</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Earlier, we reported that Apple is in discussions with Google regarding the integration of Google’s Gemini artificial intelligence engine into the new iPhone. This undoubtedly presents a win-win situation for both the iPhone and the Gemini AI model. However, The Wall Street Journal comments, 「It may also imply that Apple’s progress in developing its own AI capabilities could be slower than what investors had hoped for.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:45:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[时间表/链接] 聚焦英伟达 GTC 2024 大会]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>毫无疑问，英伟达 GTC 2024 大会是今年最受瞩目的科技盛会。创始人兼 CEO 黄仁勋将于大会上发布备受关注的主题演讲，主题为 「见证 AI 的变革时刻」，分享展望未来英伟达在 AI 领域的重大突破。</p><ul><li><strong>直播时间：</strong>北京时间 3 月 19 日，星期二 | 4:00 — 6:00 全球首播</li><li><strong>重播时间：</strong>北京时间 3 月 21 日，星期四 | 10:00 — 12:00 中文字幕重播</li></ul><p>届时读者可在<a href="https://www.nvidia.cn/gtc-global/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">英伟达官网</a>或油管搜索观看黄仁勋的演讲直播。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:28:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[亚马逊下周将举办首次春季大促]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本文是普通报道，而非广告，本站不通过报道获利。</p></div></div></div><p>软餐获悉，<strong>电商巨头亚马逊将于 3 月 19 日开启春季大促。</strong>作为亚马逊有史以来第一次春季大促销活动，活动将持续 6 天，3 月 19 日美东时间凌晨 3 点正式开始，一直持续到 3 月 25 日。促销期间将有大幅的商品折扣，涵盖运动/户外/家具/美容/电子产品/服装等品类，包括亚马逊自家的 Kindle 电子书阅读器、Echo 智能音箱和显示器系列等。最高折扣幅度达 50%。该活动比亚马逊夏季的 Prime 会员日和秋季的 Big Deal Days 持续时间更长。更重要的是，这次大促将适用于任何互联网用户，而不局限于 Prime 会员。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>E-commerce giant Amazon will kick off its spring promotion on March 19. As Amazon’s first-ever spring promotion event, the event will last for 6 days, starting officially at 3:00 am Eastern Time on March 19 and running until March 25. During the promotion period, there will be significant discounts on a wide range of products, including sports/outdoor/furniture/beauty/electronics/clothing categories, as well as Amazon’s own Kindle e-readers, Echo smart speakers, and display series. The highest discount rate reaches up to 50%. This event lasts longer than Amazon’s summer Prime Day and fall Big Deal Days events. More importantly, this major promotion will apply to any internet user, not just Prime members.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Firefox for iOS 在欧洲的安装量大幅增长]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p class="post-modified-info"><font color="#34A9E5">[ 更新于 2024 年 3 月 16 日 15:07 ]</font></p><p>软餐获悉，<strong>Firefox 浏览器的 iOS 版本在欧洲的安装量显著增长——Firefox for iOS 在德国的安装量增长了 50%，在法国增长了 30%。</strong>增长是在苹果开始在 iOS 中提供浏览器选择界面之后发生的。Mozilla 没有披露其他地区的数据。随着 iOS 将在欧盟开放浏览器的引擎，WebKit 引擎的垄断局面即将彻底改变。例如 Brave 正在考虑为 iOS 发布基于 Chromium 的浏览器版本，其他厂商也正在推进类似计划。但这也将提高浏览器厂商的开发维护成本，因为它们不得不同时在全球维护两个引擎版本。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The installation of Firefox browser for iOS has seen a significant increase in Europe. Firefox for iOS experienced a 50% growth in installations in Germany and a 30% growth in France. This growth occurred after Apple introduced a browser choice screen in iOS. Mozilla did not disclose data for other regions. The monopoly of the WebKit engine in iOS is expected to change with the opening of browser engines in the European Union. For instance, Brave is considering releasing a version of its browser based on Chromium for iOS, and other vendors are also pursuing similar plans. However, this will raise the development and maintenance costs for browser vendors as they will need to maintain two engine versions simultaneously on a global scale.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 04:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142377.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142377.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
