<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:05:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[iPhone 借力谷歌 Gemini，暗示蘋果 AI 研發緩慢]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>我們稍早前<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142426.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">報道</a>，蘋果正與 Google 討論向新款 iPhone 植入後者的 Gemini 人工智能引擎。這無疑對 iPhone 和 Gemini AI 模型都是雙贏的局面。但華爾街日報評論説，這 「<strong>同時也可能意味着，蘋果公司開發自身 AI 能力的進展可能比投資者希望的要慢。</strong>」</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Earlier, we reported that Apple is in discussions with Google regarding the integration of Google’s Gemini artificial intelligence engine into the new iPhone. This undoubtedly presents a win-win situation for both the iPhone and the Gemini AI model. However, The Wall Street Journal comments, 「It may also imply that Apple’s progress in developing its own AI capabilities could be slower than what investors had hoped for.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:45:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</link>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[時間表/鏈接] 聚焦英偉達 GTC 2024 大會]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>毫無疑問，英偉達 GTC 2024 大會是今年最受矚目的科技盛會。創始人兼 CEO 黃仁勳將於大會上發佈備受關注的主題演講，主題為 「見證 AI 的變革時刻」，分享展望未來英偉達在 AI 領域的重大突破。</p><ul><li><strong>直播時間：</strong>北京時間 3 月 19 日，星期二 | 4:00 — 6:00 全球首播</li><li><strong>重播時間：</strong>北京時間 3 月 21 日，星期四 | 10:00 — 12:00 中文字幕重播</li></ul><p>屆時讀者可在<a href="https://www.nvidia.cn/gtc-global/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">英偉達官網</a>或油管搜索觀看黃仁勳的演講直播。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:28:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142432.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[亞馬遜下週將舉辦首次春季大促]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本文是普通報道，而非廣告，本站不通過報道獲利。</p></div></div></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>電商巨頭亞馬遜將於 3 月 19 日開啓春季大促。</strong>作為亞馬遜有史以來第一次春季大促銷活動，活動將持續 6 天，3 月 19 日美東時間凌晨 3 點正式開始，一直持續到 3 月 25 日。促銷期間將有大幅的商品折扣，涵蓋運動/戶外/傢俱/美容/電子產品/服裝等品類，包括亞馬遜自家的 Kindle 電子書閲讀器、Echo 智能音箱和顯示器系列等。最高折扣幅度達 50%。該活動比亞馬遜夏季的 Prime 會員日和秋季的 Big Deal Days 持續時間更長。更重要的是，這次大促將適用於任何互聯網用戶，而不侷限於 Prime 會員。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>E-commerce giant Amazon will kick off its spring promotion on March 19. As Amazon’s first-ever spring promotion event, the event will last for 6 days, starting officially at 3:00 am Eastern Time on March 19 and running until March 25. During the promotion period, there will be significant discounts on a wide range of products, including sports/outdoor/furniture/beauty/electronics/clothing categories, as well as Amazon’s own Kindle e-readers, Echo smart speakers, and display series. The highest discount rate reaches up to 50%. This event lasts longer than Amazon’s summer Prime Day and fall Big Deal Days events. More importantly, this major promotion will apply to any internet user, not just Prime members.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142419.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Firefox for iOS 在歐洲的安裝量大幅增長]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p class="post-modified-info"><font color="#34A9E5">[ 更新於 2024 年 3 月 16 日 15:07 ]</font></p><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>Firefox 瀏覽器的 iOS 版本在歐洲的安裝量顯著增長——Firefox for iOS 在德國的安裝量增長了 50%，在法國增長了 30%。</strong>增長是在蘋果開始在 iOS 中提供瀏覽器選擇界面之後發生的。Mozilla 沒有披露其他地區的數據。隨着 iOS 將在歐盟開放瀏覽器的引擎，WebKit 引擎的壟斷局面即將徹底改變。例如 Brave 正在考慮為 iOS 發佈基於 Chromium 的瀏覽器版本，其他廠商也正在推進類似計劃。但這也將提高瀏覽器廠商的開發維護成本，因為它們不得不同時在全球維護兩個引擎版本。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The installation of Firefox browser for iOS has seen a significant increase in Europe. Firefox for iOS experienced a 50% growth in installations in Germany and a 30% growth in France. This growth occurred after Apple introduced a browser choice screen in iOS. Mozilla did not disclose data for other regions. The monopoly of the WebKit engine in iOS is expected to change with the opening of browser engines in the European Union. For instance, Brave is considering releasing a version of its browser based on Chromium for iOS, and other vendors are also pursuing similar plans. However, this will raise the development and maintenance costs for browser vendors as they will need to maintain two engine versions simultaneously on a global scale.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 04:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142377.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142377.html</link>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[VLC 播放器下載破 50 億次，4.0 版將重構核心]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p class="post-modified-info"><font color="#34A9E5">[ 更新於 2024 年 3 月 16 日 15:07 ]</font></p><p>軟餐獲悉，Videolan 總裁 Jean-Baptiste Kempf 透露，<strong>發佈於 2001 年的開源視頻播放器 VLC 的下載量已超過 50 億次。Videolan 正在開發重大版本 v4.0，該版本中整個 VLC 的核心已被重構。</strong>他們還在開發一個基於 WebAssembly 的 VLC 版本，以允許用戶在 Web 上使用該媒體播放器，而無需事先下載任何內容。此外，官方還開發了適用於 Apple Vision Pro 的版本（尚未公開發布），以及計劃為 Meta 的 Quest 頭戴設備開發適用版本。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Videolan President Jean-Baptiste Kempf revealed that the open-source video player VLC, released in 2001, has surpassed 5 billion downloads. Simultaneously, Videolan is developing a major version, v4.0, with a complete refactoring of VLC’s core. They are also working on a WebAssembly-based version of VLC, allowing users to use the media player on the web without the need to download any content beforehand. Additionally, they have developed a version for Apple Vision Pro (not yet publicly released) and have plans to develop a compatible version for Meta’s Quest headsets.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 09:49:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142268.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142268.html</link>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
