<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 16:37:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google 播客將關閉，提醒用户遷移數據</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;軟餐收到了 Google 郵件通知，該公司再次提醒即將停止 Google 播客服務，並建議用户將已訂閲的播客遷至 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music 或下載到本地。&lt;/strong&gt;Google 在郵件中寫道：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;謹在此提醒您，2024 年 4 月 2 日之後，您無法再在 Google 播客中收聽播客了。在 2024 年 7 月 29 日之前，您仍然可以將訂閲的播客節目遷移到 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music，或者將訂閲的節目下載到本地，然後上傳到支持導入該文件的應用中。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;若要使用遷移和導出工具，您需要使用最新版本的 Google 搜索和 Google 播客應用，並擁有&lt;a href=&quot;https://notifications.google.com/g/p/ANiao5oBIBrIhJBFxKM1oW6L2Q0YoUTl-evLUjbi8w32zGHJlk7nwCmxT-k-BEwVFUR3blInqRvUQY15ss4h9Ev9-gHt4Nr8iJs6dxfn0Mg8iSbP7N7Ty1HPTzygHlnb1Q0ywCNyAt_Cr7LEiC-HGbbUQYSVBT0J9yHtEmSUHO5hJeetLWwA3ULq94nPgQJKaYo-J1nvrSgdMs9ammPvrXDYBwZXVxIqmOBHUfVX9Qg3H5cumJ_FMLhWXJM7ynXShC5NyvU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;有效的賬號類型&lt;/a&gt;。如果您使用的是不受支持的應用版本，那麼只能針對網頁版 Google 播客使用遷移和導出工具。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google 於去年 9 月&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/137956.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;宣佈&lt;/a&gt;將關閉播客應用程序 Google Podcasts，播客功能將由 YouTube Music 承接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have received a notification email from Google informing us once again that they will be discontinuing the Google Podcasts service. They advised users to migrate their subscribed podcasts to YouTube Music or download them locally. In the email, Google stated:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to remind you that starting from April 2, 2024, you will no longer be able to listen to podcasts on Google Podcasts. Until July 29, 2024, you can still migrate your subscribed podcast programs to YouTube Music or download the subscribed episodes locally and then upload them to an app that supports importing such files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To use the migration and export tools, you will need to have the latest versions of Google Search and Google Podcasts applications and have a valid account type. If you are using an unsupported app version, you can only use the migration and export tools for the web version of Google Podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google announced in September of last year that they would be shutting down the Google Podcasts application, and the podcast functionality would be taken over by YouTube Music.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>被廣泛批評後，Meta 希望將「去廣告」服務價格減半</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，Meta 的一位高管週二表示，&lt;strong&gt;該公司提出將 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月訂閲費從 9.99 歐元減半至 5.99 歐元，以消除歐盟監管監管機構的擔憂。&lt;/strong&gt;此次降價是在隱私活動人士和消費者團體對 Meta 在歐盟的無廣告訂閲服務提出批評之後進行的，批評者稱該服務要求用户付費以確保其隱私。現在，歐盟的隱私保護活動人士並不認可降價方案，他們認為這與價格無關，即使降價到 1.99 歐元或更低，也會導致用户選擇 「同意」，即接受在訪問 Meta 服務的同時瀏覽廣告。上週，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;39 名歐盟議員發出公開信，希望 Meta 停止提供該付費去廣告模式&lt;/a&gt;。Meta 於 11 月推出了付費去廣告訂閲計劃，以遵守《數字市場法案》(DMA)，該法案限制了其在未經用户同意的情況下為用户提供個性化廣告的能力，從而損害了其主要收入來源。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>7-Zip 已支持解壓縮.zst 格式文件</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;開源解壓縮軟件 7-Zip 已增加了對 ZSTD 或 Zstandard 數據壓縮算法的支持，7-Zip 現在可以解壓縮.zst 文件，以及使用 ZSTD 壓縮方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存檔。&lt;/strong&gt;這項支持最早在 1 月底發佈的 beta 版 24.01 中推出。7-Zip 聲稱它沒有使用 Facebook 的原始 Zstandard (ZSTD) 代碼。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows 11 此前已支持 Zst 和 Tzst 格式，它基於開源的 libarchive 項目實現了該功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;7-Zip 24.01 的更新日誌：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包 ZSTD 存檔（.zst 文件擴展名）。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包使用 ZSTD 壓縮方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在支持在 ZSTD 中使用的快速哈希算法 XXH64。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包由新版 WinRAR 7.00 創建的使用大於 4 GB 字典的 RAR 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包使用 XZ（ULMO/LZMA）壓縮方法的 DMG 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包具有大於 64 KB 簇大小的 NTFS 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包具有 4 KB 扇區的 MBR 和 GDP 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;存檔解包的速度優化：rar、cab、wim、zip、gz。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;哈希計算的速度優化：CRC-32、CRC-64、Blake2sp。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修復了一個錯誤：Linux 上的 7-Zip 在某些情況下無法創建多卷。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修復了一些錯誤。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 10:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>系統工具</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mozilla 推出個人興趣分享應用 Didthis</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006571970.webp&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla 推出了新的應用程序 Didthis，這是一款用於追蹤和與感興趣的人分享個人興趣項目進展的應用和服務。&lt;/strong&gt;Mozilla 稱該服務目前只是一個實驗，仍處於測試階段。Didthis 提供網站（&lt;a href=&quot;https://didthis.app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;官網&lt;/a&gt;）和 iOS 應用，未來還將推出 Android 版本。用户可以上傳照片、視頻和文字，並將它們組織到不同的個人興趣項目中，這些內容默認為私密，未來計劃添加社區功能。用户可以與其他用户或聯繫人共享自己的項目。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has launched a new application called Didthis, which is designed to track and share the progress of personal hobby projects with like-minded individuals. Mozilla describes this service as an experimental project that is currently in the testing phase. Didthis is available as a website and an iOS app, with plans to release an Android version in the future. Users can upload photos, videos, and text, organizing them into various personal interest projects. By default, these contents are kept private, but there are plans to incorporate community features in the future. Users have the option to share their projects with other users or contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142465.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142465.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 16:04:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>WhatsApp 將添加聊天搜索欄</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006571972.jpeg.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;WhatsApp 測試版（2.23.21.12）顯示，Meta 正向該應用添加一個聊天搜索欄。&lt;/strong&gt;它將位於會話列表的上方，加入搜索欄是為了符合 Google 建議的 Material Design 設計原則（目前用户可以通過點擊放大鏡按鈕來搜索）。此外，搜索欄還可以顯示多個對話，無需滾動。目前尚不清楚搜索欄何時會出現在該應用的穩定版本中。同時，WhatsApp 還在開發通過滑動來切換選項卡的功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The beta version (2.23.21.12) of WhatsApp reveals that Meta is adding a chat search bar to the application. The search bar will be positioned above the conversation list, and its inclusion aligns with Google’s recommended Material Design principles (users can currently perform searches by clicking the magnifying glass button). Additionally, the search bar will have the capability to display multiple conversations without requiring scrolling. It is currently unknown when the search bar will appear in the stable version of the application. Furthermore, WhatsApp is also developing a feature that allows tab switching through swiping.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142460.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142460.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 15:57:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>