<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 20:34:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[iOS 17.4 發佈，在歐盟支持第三方應用商店]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>蘋果發佈了 iOS 17.4，為 iPhone 提供了支持第三方應用商店的功能。</strong>此外，蘋果還開放了 iPhone 的 NFC 芯片給外部開發者使用。通過這些變化，蘋果希望符合歐盟的 DMA 法律要求。通過擁有自己的應用商店，開發者可以使用自己的支付方式，從而減少向蘋果支付的佣金。在發佈 iOS 應用之前，開發者仍需經過蘋果的審核，並且對於下載次數超過一百萬的應用，他們需要支付每次安裝 50 歐分的費用。軟餐早前報道，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">德國的數字服務提供商 Mobivention 將於本週三發佈首個替代性 iOS 應用商店</a>。Epic Games 也希望將 Epic Games Store 引入 iOS。</p><p>此外，瀏覽器開發商還可以發佈不使用蘋果 WebKit 內核的瀏覽器；iMessage 將獲得改進的加密協議；Podcasts 應用將具備自動音頻轉錄功能；還有新的表情符號發佈；Siri 可以朗讀收到的消息；iPhone 15 設備還可以分享更多有關電池健康狀態的信息，例如充電週期數據。iOS 17.4 和 iPadOS 17.4 適用於支持 iOS 17 或 iPadOS 17 的所有設備。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Apple has released iOS 17.4, which brings support for third-party app stores to iPhones. Additionally, Apple has opened up the NFC chip on iPhones for external developers. With these changes, Apple aims to comply with the EU’s DMA (Digital Markets Act) regulations.</p><p>By having their own app stores, developers can use their own payment methods, thereby reducing the commission they pay to Apple. Developers still need to go through Apple’s approval process before releasing iOS apps, and for apps that are downloaded more than one million times, they are required to pay 50 euro cents per installation.</p><p>According to recent reports, German digital service provider Mobivention plans to launch the first alternative iOS app store this Wednesday. Epic Games also intends to bring the Epic Games Store to iOS.</p><p>Furthermore, browser developers will have the option to release browsers that don’t utilize the Apple WebKit engine. iMessage will receive an improved encryption protocol, the Podcasts app will have automatic audio transcripts, new emojis will be introduced, Siri will be able to read incoming messages, and iPhone 15 devices will be able to share more information about battery health, such as the number of charging cycles. iOS 17.4 and iPadOS 17.4 are available for all devices that support iOS 17 or iPadOS 17.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</link>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Telegram 開始推出商家賬戶]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>Telegram 創始人帕維爾·杜羅夫（Pavel Durov）稱，<strong>本週開始，該應用推出了 Telegram Business 的第一批功能。</strong>即 Telegram 個人賬戶可轉為商業賬戶，商業賬戶可添加位置和營業時間，使用帶有顏色標籤的聊天組織，使用自動問候/離開消息和快速回復的快捷方式等。</p><p>本月晚些時候，更多的 Telegram Business 功能還將推出。包括 Telegram Business 賬戶將可無縫地將聊天機器人添加到所有或特定的聊天中以進行回覆，以幫助客戶提升客服自動化水平。開發者可在本月後期還可免費使用新的機器人 API。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Telegram founder Pavel Durov announced that this week, the app has launched the first batch of Telegram Business features. Users now have the ability to convert their personal Telegram accounts into business accounts, which allows them to add location and business hours, organize chats with color labels, and utilize shortcuts for automatic greetings, away messages, and quick replies.</p><p>More Telegram Business features are set to be released later this month. One notable feature is the seamless integration of chatbots into Telegram Business accounts, enabling them to respond to all or specific chats, thereby enhancing customer service automation. Additionally, developers will have access to the new Bot APIs, which will be available free of charge later this month.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:45:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[聊天軟件 Signal 7.0 發佈，全面支持用戶名]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/aJs-5Go4.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>Signal 官方宣佈，<strong>已在最新版本 Signal 7.0 中<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141681.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">按原定計劃</a>推出其用戶名功能。Signal 用戶可創建一個用戶名，以隱藏自己的手機號碼</strong>。該功能可有效保護用戶的隱私。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>電話號碼隱私和用戶名功能現已在使用 Signal 7.0 版本的所有人中推出！更新您的應用程序以利用這些新功能。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[清單] 本週起 Pixel 手機、手錶和平板獲多項新功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>本週一開始，部分 Pixel 手機、手錶和平板電腦獲得了一系列新功能。</strong>這些更新將在未來幾周內完成：</p><ul><li><strong>Google Pixel 7 和 Pixel Pro 將獲得 「圈選搜索」（Circle to search）功能。</strong>用戶可以通過在屏幕上圈出物體來進行搜索。上個月，這一功能已經應用於 Pixel 8 和 Pixel 8 Pro。</li><li><strong>Pixel 7 和 Pixel 8 的用戶現在可以在 Instagram Reels 中製作更好的視頻。</strong>現在可以使用 10 位 HDR 視頻錄製。還可以直接將照片以 Google 的 Ultra HDR 格式上傳到 Instagram Feed。這兩個設置需要在 Pixel 相機應用中先打開。目前尚不清楚這些功能將在哪些市場上可用。</li><li><strong>谷歌還將 Pixel Watch 2 的新功能添加到初代 Pixel 手錶中。</strong>其中包括增強的運動模式，如一致節奏的 Pace Training 以及當用戶步行速度過快或過慢時的振動通知。第一代 Pixel 手錶現在還可以在檢測到工作開始時自動啓動和停止。用戶現在還可以在 Pixel 手錶上直接獲取公共交通的路線指引。</li><li><strong>Pixel 手機或平板電腦的用戶現在共享屏幕時可選擇僅共享一個應用程序，而不是整個屏幕。</strong>此功能適用於 Pixel Tablet、Pixel Fold 和 Pixel 5a 與 5G 及更高版本的手機。</li><li><strong>谷歌簡化了先前使用過的設備的配對過程。</strong>在更新後，Pixel 平板電腦的用戶可以在 Google Docs 中使用註釋和批註進行評論。</li><li><strong>谷歌將為 Pixel 6 及更高版本的手機在美國推出更新版本的通話屏幕（Call Screen）。</strong>當來電者保持沉默時，用戶將看到一個 「你好」 按鈕。按下按鈕後，谷歌助手會要求來電者開口。這樣用戶就可以知道為什麼要聯繫他們。如果用戶無法回答，谷歌助手會告知來電者稍等片刻。目前尚不清楚這一功能是否會在全球範圍內推出，以及何時推出。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><ul><li>Google Pixel 7 and Pixel Pro will receive the 「Circle to search」 feature. Users can search by circling an object on the screen. Last month, this feature was already applied to Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro.</li><li>Users of Pixel 7 and Pixel 8 can now create better videos on Instagram Reels. 10-bit HDR video recording is now available. It is also possible to directly upload photos in Google’s Ultra HDR format to Instagram Feed. These two settings need to be enabled in the Pixel Camera app. It is currently unclear in which markets these features will be available.</li><li>Google has also added new features from Pixel Watch 2 to the first-generation Pixel Watch. This includes enhanced motion modes such as consistent rhythm Pace Training and vibration notifications when the user’s walking speed is too fast or too slow. The first-gen Pixel Watch can now also automatically start and stop when work is detected. Users can now also directly access public transit directions on the Pixel Watch.</li><li>Users of Pixel phones or tablets can now choose to share only one application instead of the entire screen when screen sharing. This feature is available for Pixel Tablet, Pixel Fold, Pixel 5a with 5G, and higher versions of Pixel phones.</li><li>Google has simplified the pairing process for previously used devices. After the update, users of Pixel tablets can use comments and annotations in Google Docs.</li><li>Google will release an updated version of Call Screen for Pixel 6 and higher versions of the phone in the United States. When the caller remains silent, users will see a 「Hi」 button. Pressing the button will prompt the Google Assistant to ask the caller to speak. This way, users can know why they are being contacted. If the user is unable to answer, the Google Assistant will inform the caller to wait for a moment. It is currently unclear if and when this feature will be launched globally.</li></ul>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 10:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142050.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142050.html</link>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[重磅：微軟宣佈停止支持 Windows 安卓子系統]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟公司宣佈將於 2025 年初結束對 Windows 安卓子系統（WSA）的支持。</strong>該工具允許用戶在 Windows 11 中運行 Android 應用程序。自 2025 年 3 月 5 日起，將不再支持所有依賴 WSA 的應用程序和遊戲。在 2024 年 3 月 6 日之前安裝了 Amazon Appstore 或 Android 應用的用戶，可以繼續使用它們並獲得技術支持，直到明年初。在 2021 年 6 月首次發佈 Windows 11 時，微軟透露了對 Android 應用程序的支持。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Microsoft 將終止對 Windows Subsystem for Android™️（WSA）的支持。因此，從 2025 年 3 月 5 日開始，將不再支持 Windows 上的 Amazon Appstore 以及所有依賴於 WSA 的應用程序和遊戲。在此之前，仍將為客戶提供技術支持。</p><p>在 2024 年 3 月 5 日之前安裝了亞馬遜應用商店或 Android 應用的客戶，在 2025 年 3 月 5 日的棄用日期之前，將繼續有權訪問這些應用。如有其他問題，請聯繫我們的支持團隊，網址為 support.microsoft.com。我們感謝開發者社區的支持，並將繼續致力於在改進體驗的過程中聽取反饋。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:29:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
