<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 20:14:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[遊戲工委人士稱可對「網遊新規」意見稿暢所欲言]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-exclamation-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>文中涉及觀點不代表本站。本站對報道對象不持任何觀點。</p></div></div></div><p>今日，新聞出版署最新發布的《網絡遊戲管理辦法（草案徵求意見稿）》引發熱議。其中提到，網絡遊戲不得設置每日登錄、首次充值、連續充值等誘導性獎勵；所有網絡遊戲須設置用戶充值限額。這些規定或將直接影響遊戲的日活與盈利能力。據澎湃新聞，針對意見稿引發的反應，<strong>中國音數協遊戲工委內部人士表示，既然是徵求意見稿，表明目前階段各界均可暢所欲言，以使其切實可行，更為完善。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Today, the latest 「Administrative Measures for Online Game Management (Draft for Soliciting Opinions)」 released by the National Press and Publication Administration has sparked heated discussions. It mentions that online games should not have inducement rewards such as daily login rewards, first-time recharge rewards, and consecutive recharge rewards; all online games must set user recharge limits. These regulations may directly affect the daily active users and profitability of games. According to The Paper, an insider from the China Audio-Video and Digital Publishing Association’s Games Committee stated that since it is a draft for soliciting opinions, it indicates that at this stage, everyone can freely express their views in order to make it practical and more perfect.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 10:50:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140454.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140454.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟修復了 Win11 的一個「老大難」問題]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231219184152.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>2023-適用於 Windows 11 Version 22H2 的 11 累積更新，適合基於 x64 的系統 (KB5032288)</p></blockquote><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>此更新解決了影響文件資源管理器窗口的問題。即當您不希望它們出現時，它們會在前台顯示。</p></blockquote><p>軟餐獲悉，在 12 月 4 日發佈的 Windows 11 可選非安全更新 KB5032288 中，微軟終於修復了一個存在於 Windows 11 文件資源管理器上的 「老大難」 問題——<strong>用戶在使用 Windows 11 時，無論是使用瀏覽器、玩遊戲或寫代碼，文件資源管理器經常莫名其妙的獲取焦點並出現在屏幕上。這次更新已經修復了該問題。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the Windows 11 optional non-security update KB5032288 released on December 4th, Microsoft finally fixed a 「difficult」 issue that existed in the Windows 11 File Explorer. When using Windows 11, whether it’s browsing the internet, playing games, or coding, the File Explorer would frequently and inexplicably gain focus and appear on the screen. This update has resolved this problem.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>2023 – Cumulative Update for Windows 11 Version 22H2 for x64-based Systems (KB5032288)</p></blockquote><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>This update addresses an issue affecting File Explorer windows where they would appear in the foreground when you don’t want them to.</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 10:42:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140234.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140234.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[實測] Edge 瀏覽器終於迎來「超級拖拽」功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231219171317.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟終於為 Edge 瀏覽器帶來了超級拖放（Super Drag and Drop）功能。軟餐實測發現，它已出現在 Edge 121 穩定版（121.0.2277.4&nbsp;）中。</strong>只需在鏈接、文本或圖片上單擊鼠標，同時向瀏覽器地址欄方向拖動，即可在新標籤頁中打開它。如果拖拽的對象是文本，Edge 瀏覽器則會打開默認搜索引擎搜索文本——超級拖放功能對於 Chrome 或 Firefox 用戶並不陌生。</p><p>目前需要手動啓用 Edge 超級拖拽功能，方法是訪問 edge://flags/#edge-super-drag-drop 並將標誌啓用，重啓 Edge 瀏覽器，然後進入設置 – 外觀 – 將 「啓用超級拖放」 開關開啓即可。你還可以在設置中選擇在後台或前台打開超級拖拽的頁面。<strong>我們的測試顯示，該功能在 Edge 穩定版上運行良好。</strong><a href="https://cdn.neowin.com/news/images/uploaded/2023/12/1702926184_microsoft_edge_super_drag_and_drop.jpg"></a></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has finally brought the Super Drag and Drop feature to the Edge browser. Soft meal testing found that it has appeared in the stable, Dev, and Canary versions of Edge. Simply right-click or click on a link, text, or image and drag it towards the browser address bar to open it in a new tab. If the dragged object is text, Edge will use the default search engine to search for the text – Super Drag and Drop is not unfamiliar to Chrome or Firefox users.</p><p>Currently, you need to manually enable the Edge Super Drag and Drop feature by visiting edge://flags/#edge-super-drag-drop and enabling the flag, restarting Edge browser, then going into Settings – Appearance – toggle on 「Enable super drag and drop」. You can also choose whether to open super drag and drop pages in background or foreground in settings. Our tests show that this feature works well on the stable version of Edge.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 09:16:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140217.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140217.html</link>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[幾所大學建議卸載 12 月「週二補丁日」更新，以修復 Wi-Fi 連接問題]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟在 2023 年 12 月 Windows 11「補丁星期二」 發佈的更新 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140051.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KB5033375</a>，又 「惹禍」 了。</strong>很多用戶反饋説，更新 KB5033375 後，Win11 設備無法連接到 Wi-Fi 網絡，或者性能急劇下降，導致無法訪問互聯網。<strong>幾所大學建議其校園用戶暫時卸載 KB5033375 更新以修復問題，紐黑文大學、倫敦布魯內爾大學等高校都發布了類似的公告。</strong>微軟官方尚未對該問題提供迴應。</p><p>要卸載 Windows 11 更新，請打開 「設置」 – 「Windows 更新」，找到 「更新歷史記錄」 並卸載對應的更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft’s update KB5033375, released on 「Patch Tuesday」 in December 2023 for Windows 11, has caused trouble again. Many users have reported that after installing the KB5033375 update, their Win11 devices are unable to connect to Wi-Fi networks or experience a significant decrease in network performance, resulting in an inability to access the internet. Several universities have advised their campus users to temporarily uninstall the KB5033375 update to fix the issue. Universities such as Yale University and Brunel University London have issued similar announcements. Microsoft has not yet responded officially to this problem.</p><p>To uninstall a Windows 11 update, open 「Settings」 – 「Windows Update,」 find 「Update History,」 and uninstall the corresponding update.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 16:24:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140192.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140192.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟將允許歐盟用戶登錄 Windows 應用時選擇帳戶]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/2006302776.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>2024 年初開始，首次登錄 Windows 應用程序時，位於歐盟的 Windows 10 和 11 用戶很快將被要求選擇使用哪個帳戶登錄該應用。</strong>你可以選擇使用已經在 Windows 上登錄的帳戶或其他帳戶。微軟稱，這一調整是為了遵守歐盟數字市場法案（DMA）。到 2024 年 3 月，該功能將對所有歐盟用戶可用。該通知將出現在用戶第一次打開 Windows 應用程序時，用戶可以使用個人 Microsoft 賬戶或 Microsoft Entra Verified ID 進行登錄。如果用戶選擇使用與其在 Windows 上註冊的相同登錄憑據，則下次使用應用時不會再顯示通知。<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139574.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>最近更新的 Windows 11 小部件已支持類似選項</em></a></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 08:02:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140164.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140164.html</link>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
