<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 23:26:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[传微软 2024 年夏天发布 Windows 12]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，据台湾商业时报 (CTEE) ，微软将于 2024 年 6 月发布其下一代操作系统 <strong>Windows 12</strong>，以及各种基于人工智能的 PC。这一消息的来源是广达电脑董事长林百里和宏碁董事长兼首席执行官陈俊圣最近在台湾医疗技术展览会上的发言。林百里预期明年夏季随着新一代的 Windows 作业系统时，AI PC 也将陆续推出。他看好这对 PC 硬件产业的机会。</p><p>这不是第一次出现有关 Windows 12 的传闻。英特尔首席财务官最近也声称 Windows 12 将于 2024 年问世。更早前有德国媒体报道，微软计划<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138116.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">将 Windows 12 打造为一个基于订阅的操作系统</a>。已经离开微软的前 Windows 负责人 Panos Panay 也曾暗示，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/117042.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 12 将由 AI 深度驱动</a>。</p><p>与此同时，微软还在紧锣密鼓的开发 Windows 11 24H2，这是 Windows 11 的下一个功能更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Taiwan Business Times (CTEE), Microsoft will release its next-generation operating system, Windows 12, and various AI-based PCs in June 2024. The source of this news is the speeches given by Lin Baili, Chairman of Quanta Computer, and Chen Junsheng, Chairman and CEO of Acer, at a recent medical technology exhibition in Taiwan. Lin Baili expects that with the new generation of Windows operating system next summer, AI PCs will also be launched one after another. He sees this as an opportunity for the PC hardware industry.</p><p>This is not the first time rumors about Windows 12 have surfaced. Recently, Intel’s CFO also claimed that Windows 12 will be released in 2024. Earlier reports from German media stated that Microsoft plans to develop Windows 12 as a subscription-based operating system. Former head of Windows at Microsoft who has since left the company, Panos Panay, also hinted that Windows 12 would be driven by AI.</p><p>Meanwhile, Microsoft is also actively developing Windows 11 24H2, which is the next feature update for Windows 11.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 07:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[「微软画图」应用全面迎来 AI 作图功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/GABtxPAX0AIpVe7.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软已低调向所有 「微软画图」（Microsoft Paint）用户开放基于 AI 的 Cocreator（共同创作者）功能。</strong>这是一项人工智能生成图像功能，基于 OpenAI 的 DALL-E 3 模型。现在用户无需进行任何申请，即可直接访问该功能。<strong>软餐在我们的测试设备上已经获得该功能。</strong></p><p>用户必须登录微软账户才能使用此功能。用户将自动获得 50 个积分，用于在 Cocreator 中创作图像。目前，Cocreator 仅支持英语，并且目前在美国、法国、英国、澳大利亚、加拿大、意大利和德国可用。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>要使用 Cocreator，请打开 Microsoft Paint，然后选择工具栏上的 Cocreator 图标以查看 Cocreator（共同创作者）侧面板。在文本框中，输入要创建的图像的描述。例如，您可以输入 「一只戴红帽子的蓝猫」 或 「有山和湖的风景」。尽可能具有描述性，以生成符合您期望的结果。</p><p>输入文本后，选择要创建图像的样式，然后选择 「创建」 按钮。 Cocreator 将生成您请求的图像的三种不同变体，您可以单击任何变体以将该图像应用到 Paint 画布并开始创建。</p></blockquote><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has quietly opened up its AI-based Cocreator feature to all Microsoft Paint users. This is an artificial intelligence-generated image creation feature based on OpenAI’s DALL-E 3 model. Users can now access this feature directly without any application process. The software update has already been received on our testing devices.</p><p>Users must log in to their Microsoft accounts in order to use this feature. Upon logging in, users will automatically receive 50 points for creating images in Cocreator. Currently, Cocreator only supports English and is available in the United States, France, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, Italy, and Germany.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>To use Cocreator, open Microsoft Paint and select the Cocreator icon on the toolbar to see the Cocreator side panel. In the text box, enter a description of the image you want to create. For example, you can type 「a blue cat with a red hat」 or 「a landscape with mountains and a lake」. Be as descriptive as possible to generate results matching your expectations.</p><p>After you enter the text, choose a style in which you want to create your image and then select the Create button. Cocreator will generate three different variants of the image you requested, you can click on any of the variants to apply that image to Paint canvas and start creating.</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:11:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>图形图像</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软有意禁止 Win11 用户恢复 Win10 任务栏]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，微软似乎有意禁止用户在 Windows 11 上恢复 Win10 时代的任务栏。——正在向 Canary 通道上推送的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139405.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 11 build 26002</a> 中包含一个名为 「DisableWin10Taskbar」 的隐藏功能。顾名思义，启用其 ID（42537950）后会阻止加载 Windows 10 任务栏。此外它还会破坏第三方应用程序，例如 StartAllBack 或 ExplorerPatcher。</p><p>由于微软并未默认开启这项功能，因此很难判断微软最终决定阻止 Windows 11 用户恢复旧的任务栏。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft seems to be intentionally preventing users from restoring the Windows 10 era taskbar on Windows 11. In the Windows 11 build 26002 being pushed to the Canary channel, there is a hidden feature called 「DisableWin10Taskbar」. As the name suggests, enabling its ID (42537950) will prevent loading of the Windows 10 taskbar. Additionally, it will break third-party applications such as StartAllBack or ExplorerPatcher.</p><p>Since Microsoft has not enabled this feature by default, it is difficult to determine whether Microsoft has actually decided to block Windows 11 users from restoring the old taskbar.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:46:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139414.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139414.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[图] 微软发布 2023 款「丑毛衣」Windows Ugly Sweater]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/1701176110_bliss_ugly_sweaters_image_story.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，在西方假日季临近之际，微软按照传统推出了 2023 年的 「Windows 丑陋毛衣」(Windows Ugly Sweater)。微软没有停止怀旧，这次在毛衣上印上了经典的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/131375.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows XP 默认的 Bliss 壁纸</a>。过去几年，微软还曾在丑陋毛衣上印制 Windows 95、扫雷游戏、微软画图（MS Paint）和 Clippy（大眼夹/回形针）等形象。消费者可通过 windowsuglysweater.com 网站购买 「丑陋毛衣」，微软将把销售所得的 10 万美元捐给大自然保护协会（The&nbsp;Nature&nbsp;Conservancy）。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>As the Western holiday season approaches, Microsoft has traditionally released the 「Windows Ugly Sweater」 for 2023. Microsoft continues its nostalgia by printing the classic Windows XP default Bliss wallpaper on the sweater. In recent years, Microsoft has also printed Windows 95, Minesweeper game, MS Paint, and Clippy (the paperclip) images on ugly sweaters. Consumers can purchase the 「ugly sweater」 through the website windowsuglysweater.com, and Microsoft will donate $100,000 of sales proceeds to The Nature Conservancy (TNC).</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:52:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[链接] 三星浏览器 Windows 版发布：非三星电脑也能用]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/693292.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，三星刚刚向<a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">微软商店</a>上架了适用于 Windows 系统的浏览器 <strong>Samsung Internet</strong>。该浏览器支持 64 位 Windows 10 及以上版本系统，即使不是三星品牌设备也可运行。三星对该浏览器的描述只有一句话：「Samsung Internet 通过各种功能和保护您的隐私，为您提供最佳的网络浏览体验。」 据悉，该浏览器支持部分同步功能，可从安卓版 Samsung Internet 浏览器同步浏览历史记录、书签、保存的页面和打开的标签等数据，但尚不支持同步保存的密码。</p><p>同时，PC 版 Samsung Internet 支持隐身模式、广告拦截器，支持从其他浏览器（包括 Edge 和 Chrome）导入浏览历史记录/书签和搜索引擎。</p><p>三星之前在安卓平台上发布的 Samsung Internet 浏览器拥有众多忠实的粉丝。这将有助于三星获取桌面浏览器的份额。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Samsung has just released the browser Samsung Internet on the <a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Store</a> for Windows systems. This browser supports 64-bit Windows 10 and above, and can be run even on non-Samsung devices. The description of this browser by Samsung is only one sentence: 「Samsung Internet provides you with the best web browsing experience through various features and protecting your privacy.」 It is reported that this browser supports partial synchronization, allowing users to sync browsing history, bookmarks, saved pages, and open tabs from the Android version of Samsung Internet browser. However, syncing saved passwords is not yet supported.</p><p>In addition, the PC version of Samsung Internet supports incognito mode and ad blocker, as well as importing browsing history/bookmarks and search engines from other browsers (including Edge and Chrome).</p><p>Samsung’s previously released Samsung Internet browser on the Android platform has a large number of loyal fans. This will help Samsung gain market share in desktop browsers.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</link>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
