<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 12:30:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google 播客将关闭，提醒用户迁移数据</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;软餐收到了 Google 邮件通知，该公司再次提醒即将停止 Google 播客服务，并建议用户将已订阅的播客迁至 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music 或下载到本地。&lt;/strong&gt;Google 在邮件中写道：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谨在此提醒您，2024 年 4 月 2 日之后，您无法再在 Google 播客中收听播客了。在 2024 年 7 月 29 日之前，您仍然可以将订阅的播客节目迁移到 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music，或者将订阅的节目下载到本地，然后上传到支持导入该文件的应用中。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;若要使用迁移和导出工具，您需要使用最新版本的 Google 搜索和 Google 播客应用，并拥有&lt;a href=&quot;https://notifications.google.com/g/p/ANiao5oBIBrIhJBFxKM1oW6L2Q0YoUTl-evLUjbi8w32zGHJlk7nwCmxT-k-BEwVFUR3blInqRvUQY15ss4h9Ev9-gHt4Nr8iJs6dxfn0Mg8iSbP7N7Ty1HPTzygHlnb1Q0ywCNyAt_Cr7LEiC-HGbbUQYSVBT0J9yHtEmSUHO5hJeetLWwA3ULq94nPgQJKaYo-J1nvrSgdMs9ammPvrXDYBwZXVxIqmOBHUfVX9Qg3H5cumJ_FMLhWXJM7ynXShC5NyvU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;有效的账号类型&lt;/a&gt;。如果您使用的是不受支持的应用版本，那么只能针对网页版 Google 播客使用迁移和导出工具。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google 于去年 9 月&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/137956.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;宣布&lt;/a&gt;将关闭播客应用程序 Google Podcasts，播客功能将由 YouTube Music 承接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have received a notification email from Google informing us once again that they will be discontinuing the Google Podcasts service. They advised users to migrate their subscribed podcasts to YouTube Music or download them locally. In the email, Google stated:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to remind you that starting from April 2, 2024, you will no longer be able to listen to podcasts on Google Podcasts. Until July 29, 2024, you can still migrate your subscribed podcast programs to YouTube Music or download the subscribed episodes locally and then upload them to an app that supports importing such files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To use the migration and export tools, you will need to have the latest versions of Google Search and Google Podcasts applications and have a valid account type. If you are using an unsupported app version, you can only use the migration and export tools for the web version of Google Podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google announced in September of last year that they would be shutting down the Google Podcasts application, and the podcast functionality would be taken over by YouTube Music.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>3 月安全更新能让 Windows Server 崩溃</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微软表示，在安装了 2024 年 3 月的安全更新 (KB5035857) 后，会导致 Windows Server 出现死机问题。&lt;/strong&gt;由于这个内存问题，服务器会意外重启或卡住。该 bug 存在于所有现代版本的软件中。受影响的版本包括 Windows Server 2012 R2、2016、2019 和 2022。微软表示正在努力修复这个问题。上周，在安装更新后，一些系统管理员在线投诉服务器操作系统出现问题。微软介绍，如果在域控制器上安装了 Windows Server，并且同时使用本地安全性子系统服务（Local Security Authority Subsystem Service）或 Lsass 和基于云的 Active Directory 的本地域控制器通过 Kerberos 进行身份验证请求，可能会发生内存泄漏。由于 「极端的内存泄漏」，Lsass 可能会崩溃。微软表示，这会导致域控制器重新启动，尽管许多管理员报告称域控制器也会卡住。&lt;strong&gt;微软表示已经找到了主要原因，但对此并未提供更多细节。公司写道：「我们正在研究解决方案，并将在未来几天内提供。」&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has stated that installing the security update (KB5035857) for March 2024 can cause Windows Server to experience freezing issues. Due to this memory problem, servers may unexpectedly restart or become stuck. This bug exists in all modern versions of the software. The affected versions include Windows Server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019, and 2022. Microsoft is actively working to fix this problem. Last week, after installing the update, some system administrators complained online about issues with the server operating system. Microsoft explains that if Windows Server is installed on a domain controller and both the Local Security Authority Subsystem Service (Lsass) and cloud-based Active Directory are used for Kerberos authentication requests, a memory leak may occur. Due to an 「extreme memory leak,」 Lsass may crash. Microsoft states that this leads to the domain controller restarting, although many administrators have reported that the domain controllers also become stuck. Microsoft claims to have identified the primary cause but has not provided further details. The company writes, 「We are investigating a solution and will provide it in the coming days.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 16:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GitHub 推出可自动改 Bug 的 AI 工具</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub 发布了一款新的 AI 工具，可以自动修复代码中的漏洞。&lt;/strong&gt;名为 code scanning autofix 的工具的公开测试版已向所有 GitHub Advanced Security 用户开放。GitHub 长期以来一直使用名为 CodeQl 的工具自动扫描存储库以查找潜在的安全问题。该引擎现在与 GitHub Copilot API 结合使用，不仅可以自动查找漏洞，还可以建议开发人员如何修复发现的漏洞。代码扫描自动修复还提供了所提出建议的解释。有关如何修复错误的建议不限於单个文件，还可以包括对多个文件的更改。它还可能包含需要添加到项目中的依赖项。 GitHub 在一份公告中解释说，开发人员可以接受、修改或拒绝建议。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;code scanning autofix 现在可以处理 JavaScript、Typescript、Java 和 Python 90% 以上的警报类型。该公司还表示，该系统可以修复超过三分之二的已发现错误，而开发人员自己几乎不需要进行任何调整。稍后将支持更多语言，首先会添加 C# 和 Go。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;参考：https://github.blog/2024-03-20-found-means-fixed-introducing-code-scanning-autofix-powered-by-github-copilot-and-codeql/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitHub has released a new AI tool that can automatically fix vulnerabilities in code. The tool, called code scanning autofix, has been made available in a public beta to all GitHub Advanced Security users. GitHub has long used a tool called CodeQL to automatically scan repositories for potential security issues. The engine now integrates with the GitHub Copilot API, allowing it not only to identify vulnerabilities automatically but also to suggest how developers can fix the discovered issues. The code scanning autofix also provides explanations for the proposed fixes. The suggested fixes are not limited to individual files and can include changes across multiple files. It may also include dependencies that need to be added to the project. According to GitHub’s announcement, developers have the option to accept, modify, or reject the suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Currently, code scanning autofix can handle over 90% of alert types for JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, and Python. The company also stated that the system can fix over two-thirds of the identified errors with minimal adjustments required from developers. Support for additional languages will be added later, with C# and Go being the first to be included.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142540.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142540.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 16:12:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>办公/生产力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>SpaceX 星链业务实现盈利</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;太空探索公司 SpaceX 的 CFO 表示，星链在 2023 年底实现了正向现金流，并实现了盈利。&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142490.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142490.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 21:49:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>被广泛批评后，Meta 希望将「去广告」服务价格减半</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，Meta 的一位高管周二表示，&lt;strong&gt;该公司提出将 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月订阅费从 9.99 欧元减半至 5.99 欧元，以消除欧盟监管监管机构的担忧。&lt;/strong&gt;此次降价是在隐私活动人士和消费者团体对 Meta 在欧盟的无广告订阅服务提出批评之后进行的，批评者称该服务要求用户付费以确保其隐私。现在，欧盟的隐私保护活动人士并不认可降价方案，他们认为这与价格无关，即使降价到 1.99 欧元或更低，也会导致用户选择 「同意」，即接受在访问 Meta 服务的同时浏览广告。上周，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;39 名欧盟议员发出公开信，希望 Meta 停止提供该付费去广告模式&lt;/a&gt;。Meta 于 11 月推出了付费去广告订阅计划，以遵守《数字市场法案》(DMA)，该法案限制了其在未经用户同意的情况下为用户提供个性化广告的能力，从而损害了其主要收入来源。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>