<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google 播客將關閉，提醒用户遷移數據</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;軟餐收到了 Google 郵件通知，該公司再次提醒即將停止 Google 播客服務，並建議用户將已訂閲的播客遷至 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music 或下載到本地。&lt;/strong&gt;Google 在郵件中寫道：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;謹在此提醒您，2024 年 4 月 2 日之後，您無法再在 Google 播客中收聽播客了。在 2024 年 7 月 29 日之前，您仍然可以將訂閲的播客節目遷移到 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music，或者將訂閲的節目下載到本地，然後上傳到支持導入該文件的應用中。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;若要使用遷移和導出工具，您需要使用最新版本的 Google 搜索和 Google 播客應用，並擁有&lt;a href=&quot;https://notifications.google.com/g/p/ANiao5oBIBrIhJBFxKM1oW6L2Q0YoUTl-evLUjbi8w32zGHJlk7nwCmxT-k-BEwVFUR3blInqRvUQY15ss4h9Ev9-gHt4Nr8iJs6dxfn0Mg8iSbP7N7Ty1HPTzygHlnb1Q0ywCNyAt_Cr7LEiC-HGbbUQYSVBT0J9yHtEmSUHO5hJeetLWwA3ULq94nPgQJKaYo-J1nvrSgdMs9ammPvrXDYBwZXVxIqmOBHUfVX9Qg3H5cumJ_FMLhWXJM7ynXShC5NyvU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;有效的賬號類型&lt;/a&gt;。如果您使用的是不受支持的應用版本，那麼只能針對網頁版 Google 播客使用遷移和導出工具。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google 於去年 9 月&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/137956.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;宣佈&lt;/a&gt;將關閉播客應用程序 Google Podcasts，播客功能將由 YouTube Music 承接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have received a notification email from Google informing us once again that they will be discontinuing the Google Podcasts service. They advised users to migrate their subscribed podcasts to YouTube Music or download them locally. In the email, Google stated:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to remind you that starting from April 2, 2024, you will no longer be able to listen to podcasts on Google Podcasts. Until July 29, 2024, you can still migrate your subscribed podcast programs to YouTube Music or download the subscribed episodes locally and then upload them to an app that supports importing such files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To use the migration and export tools, you will need to have the latest versions of Google Search and Google Podcasts applications and have a valid account type. If you are using an unsupported app version, you can only use the migration and export tools for the web version of Google Podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google announced in September of last year that they would be shutting down the Google Podcasts application, and the podcast functionality would be taken over by YouTube Music.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>3 月安全更新能讓 Windows Server 崩潰</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微軟表示，在安裝了 2024 年 3 月的安全更新 (KB5035857) 後，會導致 Windows Server 出現死機問題。&lt;/strong&gt;由於這個內存問題，服務器會意外重啓或卡住。該 bug 存在於所有現代版本的軟件中。受影響的版本包括 Windows Server 2012 R2、2016、2019 和 2022。微軟表示正在努力修復這個問題。上週，在安裝更新後，一些系統管理員在線投訴服務器操作系統出現問題。微軟介紹，如果在域控制器上安裝了 Windows Server，並且同時使用本地安全性子系統服務（Local Security Authority Subsystem Service）或 Lsass 和基於雲的 Active Directory 的本地域控制器通過 Kerberos 進行身份驗證請求，可能會發生內存泄漏。由於 「極端的內存泄漏」，Lsass 可能會崩潰。微軟表示，這會導致域控制器重新啓動，儘管許多管理員報告稱域控制器也會卡住。&lt;strong&gt;微軟表示已經找到了主要原因，但對此並未提供更多細節。公司寫道：「我們正在研究解決方案，並將在未來幾天內提供。」&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has stated that installing the security update (KB5035857) for March 2024 can cause Windows Server to experience freezing issues. Due to this memory problem, servers may unexpectedly restart or become stuck. This bug exists in all modern versions of the software. The affected versions include Windows Server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019, and 2022. Microsoft is actively working to fix this problem. Last week, after installing the update, some system administrators complained online about issues with the server operating system. Microsoft explains that if Windows Server is installed on a domain controller and both the Local Security Authority Subsystem Service (Lsass) and cloud-based Active Directory are used for Kerberos authentication requests, a memory leak may occur. Due to an 「extreme memory leak,」 Lsass may crash. Microsoft states that this leads to the domain controller restarting, although many administrators have reported that the domain controllers also become stuck. Microsoft claims to have identified the primary cause but has not provided further details. The company writes, 「We are investigating a solution and will provide it in the coming days.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 16:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GitHub 推出可自動改 Bug 的 AI 工具</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub 發佈了一款新的 AI 工具，可以自動修復代碼中的漏洞。&lt;/strong&gt;名為 code scanning autofix 的工具的公開測試版已向所有 GitHub Advanced Security 用户開放。GitHub 長期以來一直使用名為 CodeQl 的工具自動掃描存儲庫以查找潛在的安全問題。該引擎現在與 GitHub Copilot API 結合使用，不僅可以自動查找漏洞，還可以建議開發人員如何修復發現的漏洞。代碼掃描自動修復還提供了所提出建議的解釋。有關如何修復錯誤的建議不限於單個文件，還可以包括對多個文件的更改。它還可能包含需要添加到項目中的依賴項。 GitHub 在一份公告中解釋説，開發人員可以接受、修改或拒絕建議。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;code scanning autofix 現在可以處理 JavaScript、Typescript、Java 和 Python 90% 以上的警報類型。該公司還表示，該系統可以修復超過三分之二的已發現錯誤，而開發人員自己幾乎不需要進行任何調整。稍後將支持更多語言，首先會添加 C# 和 Go。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;參考：https://github.blog/2024-03-20-found-means-fixed-introducing-code-scanning-autofix-powered-by-github-copilot-and-codeql/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;GitHub has released a new AI tool that can automatically fix vulnerabilities in code. The tool, called code scanning autofix, has been made available in a public beta to all GitHub Advanced Security users. GitHub has long used a tool called CodeQL to automatically scan repositories for potential security issues. The engine now integrates with the GitHub Copilot API, allowing it not only to identify vulnerabilities automatically but also to suggest how developers can fix the discovered issues. The code scanning autofix also provides explanations for the proposed fixes. The suggested fixes are not limited to individual files and can include changes across multiple files. It may also include dependencies that need to be added to the project. According to GitHub’s announcement, developers have the option to accept, modify, or reject the suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Currently, code scanning autofix can handle over 90% of alert types for JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, and Python. The company also stated that the system can fix over two-thirds of the identified errors with minimal adjustments required from developers. Support for additional languages will be added later, with C# and Go being the first to be included.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142540.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142540.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 16:12:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>辦公/生產力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>雷軍在 X 上發文預熱小米 SU7</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文是常規報道，而非軟文或廣告。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/GJE_ki3bIAEx9x0.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;雷軍今天發推：「我們身着新的工廠制服，正為小米 SU7 做國內發佈的準備。迫不及待地想要揭示我們一直在努力研發的成果！」 並附上了一張他身穿小米汽車工服的照片。小米 SU7 是小米汽車首款產品。雷軍在 X（Twitter）上擁有 20 萬關注者，他在該平台上表現比較活躍，多次發文推介小米 14 Ultra 和小米汽車等產品。小米此前剛剛發佈了 2023 年第四季度財報，小米 2023 年全年實現淨利潤人民幣 174.8 億元，與 2022 年的人民幣 24.7 億元相比大幅增長。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lei Jun tweeted today, 「We are dressed in new factory uniforms, preparing for the domestic launch of Xiaomi SU7. Can’t wait to unveil the results of our long-term research and development efforts!」 He attached a photo of himself wearing Xiaomi Automotive Factory uniform, with a workshop in the background. Xiaomi SU7 is Xiaomi’s first automotive product. Lei Jun has 200,000 followers on Twitter and is quite active on the platform, frequently promoting products such as Xiaomi 14 Ultra and Xiaomi Automotive. Xiaomi recently released its Q4 2023 financial report, achieving a net profit of RMB 17.48 billion for the full year of 2023, a significant increase compared to RMB 2.47 billion in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142510.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142510.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 15:02:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 124 穩定版發佈</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla 發佈了 Firefox 124 穩定版。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox View 頁面顯示了打開的標籤頁和最近關閉的標籤頁的概覽。&lt;strong&gt;Firefox 124 中，這些標籤頁可按照最近的活動或在瀏覽器中的順序進行排序。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pull to Refresh（下拉刷新）功能現在已為 Android 用户默認啓用，他們可以通過下拉頁面來刷新頁面。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Caret Browsing 模式允許用户使用鍵盤箭頭鍵瀏覽網頁，在瀏覽器中查看 PDF 文檔時也可使用該模式。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;在 Firefox 124 中，Mozilla 還增加了對 Screen Wake Lock API 的支持。這使用户可以防止設備在不需要時調暗或鎖定屏幕。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Firefox 還在使用鼠標時添加了對 HTML 拖放 API 的支持，使用户可以使用鼠標將文本或 HTML 文本從其他程序拖放到瀏覽器中。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;對於 macOS 用户，Firefox 現在默認對所有佔滿屏幕的窗口使用全屏 API。用户可通過在 「about:config」 中將 「full-screen-api.macos-native-full-screen」 設置為 「false」 來關閉此功能。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Firefox 124 不包含 Cookie Banner Blocker 功能，該功能在最近的 Firefox Beta 版本中存在。用户可以使用該功能自動拒絕 Cookie 橫幅。Quick Action 功能也不可用，該功能允許用户通過地址欄快速執行不同的操作。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has released Firefox 124 stable version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox View displays an overview of open and recently closed tabs. In Firefox 124, these tabs can be sorted based on recent activity or their order in the browser.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Pull to Refresh feature is now enabled by default for Android users, allowing them to refresh pages by pulling them down.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Caret Browsing mode enables users to navigate web pages using keyboard arrow keys, and it can also be used when viewing PDF documents in the browser.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;In Firefox 124, Mozilla has added support for the Screen Wake Lock API, which allows users to prevent devices from dimming or locking the screen when not necessary.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Firefox has also introduced support for the HTML drag-and-drop API when using a mouse, enabling users to drag and drop text or HTML content from other programs into the browser.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;For macOS users, Firefox now defaults to using the fullscreen API for all windows that fill the screen. Users can disable this feature by setting 「full-screen-api.macos-native-full-screen」 to 「false」 in 「about:config」.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Firefox 124 does not include the Cookie Banner Blocker feature, which exists in recent Firefox Beta versions. This feature allows users to automatically reject cookie banners. The Quick Action feature is also not available, which enables users to quickly perform different actions from the address bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142492.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142492.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:31:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>