<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 16:38:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[iOS 17.4 发布，在欧盟支持第三方应用商店]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>苹果发布了 iOS 17.4，为 iPhone 提供了支持第三方应用商店的功能。</strong>此外，苹果还开放了 iPhone 的 NFC 芯片给外部开发者使用。通过这些变化，苹果希望符合欧盟的 DMA 法律要求。通过拥有自己的应用商店，开发者可以使用自己的支付方式，从而减少向苹果支付的佣金。在发布 iOS 应用之前，开发者仍需经过苹果的审核，并且对于下载次数超过一百万的应用，他们需要支付每次安装 50 欧分的费用。软餐早前报道，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">德国的数字服务提供商 Mobivention 将于本周三发布首个替代性 iOS 应用商店</a>。Epic Games 也希望将 Epic Games Store 引入 iOS。</p><p>此外，浏览器开发商还可以发布不使用苹果 WebKit 内核的浏览器；iMessage 将获得改进的加密协议；Podcasts 应用将具备自动音频转录功能；还有新的表情符号发布；Siri 可以朗读收到的消息；iPhone 15 设备还可以分享更多有关电池健康状态的信息，例如充电周期数据。iOS 17.4 和 iPadOS 17.4 适用于支持 iOS 17 或 iPadOS 17 的所有设备。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Apple has released iOS 17.4, which brings support for third-party app stores to iPhones. Additionally, Apple has opened up the NFC chip on iPhones for external developers. With these changes, Apple aims to comply with the EU’s DMA (Digital Markets Act) regulations.</p><p>By having their own app stores, developers can use their own payment methods, thereby reducing the commission they pay to Apple. Developers still need to go through Apple’s approval process before releasing iOS apps, and for apps that are downloaded more than one million times, they are required to pay 50 euro cents per installation.</p><p>According to recent reports, German digital service provider Mobivention plans to launch the first alternative iOS app store this Wednesday. Epic Games also intends to bring the Epic Games Store to iOS.</p><p>Furthermore, browser developers will have the option to release browsers that don’t utilize the Apple WebKit engine. iMessage will receive an improved encryption protocol, the Podcasts app will have automatic audio transcripts, new emojis will be introduced, Siri will be able to read incoming messages, and iPhone 15 devices will be able to share more information about battery health, such as the number of charging cycles. iOS 17.4 and iPadOS 17.4 are available for all devices that support iOS 17 or iPadOS 17.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:11:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142074.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Telegram 开始推出商家账户]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>Telegram 创始人帕维尔·杜罗夫（Pavel Durov）称，<strong>本周开始，该应用推出了 Telegram Business 的第一批功能。</strong>即 Telegram 个人账户可转为商业账户，商业账户可添加位置和营业时间，使用带有颜色标签的聊天组织，使用自动问候/离开消息和快速回复的快捷方式等。</p><p>本月晚些时候，更多的 Telegram Business 功能还将推出。包括 Telegram Business 账户将可无缝地将聊天机器人添加到所有或特定的聊天中以进行回复，以帮助客户提升客服自动化水平。开发者可在本月后期还可免费使用新的机器人 API。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Telegram founder Pavel Durov announced that this week, the app has launched the first batch of Telegram Business features. Users now have the ability to convert their personal Telegram accounts into business accounts, which allows them to add location and business hours, organize chats with color labels, and utilize shortcuts for automatic greetings, away messages, and quick replies.</p><p>More Telegram Business features are set to be released later this month. One notable feature is the seamless integration of chatbots into Telegram Business accounts, enabling them to respond to all or specific chats, thereby enhancing customer service automation. Additionally, developers will have access to the new Bot APIs, which will be available free of charge later this month.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:45:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142070.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[聊天软件 Signal 7.0 发布，全面支持用户名]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/aJs-5Go4.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>Signal 官方宣布，<strong>已在最新版本 Signal 7.0 中<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141681.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">按原定计划</a>推出其用户名功能。Signal 用户可创建一个用户名，以隐藏自己的手机号码</strong>。该功能可有效保护用户的隐私。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>电话号码隐私和用户名功能现已在使用 Signal 7.0 版本的所有人中推出！更新您的应用程序以利用这些新功能。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142060.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[重磅：微软宣布停止支持 Windows 安卓子系统]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软公司宣布将于 2025 年初结束对 Windows 安卓子系统（WSA）的支持。</strong>该工具允许用户在 Windows 11 中运行 Android 应用程序。自 2025 年 3 月 5 日起，将不再支持所有依赖 WSA 的应用程序和游戏。在 2024 年 3 月 6 日之前安装了 Amazon Appstore 或 Android 应用的用户，可以继续使用它们并获得技术支持，直到明年初。在 2021 年 6 月首次发布 Windows 11 时，微软透露了对 Android 应用程序的支持。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Microsoft 将终止对 Windows Subsystem for Android™️（WSA）的支持。因此，从 2025 年 3 月 5 日开始，将不再支持 Windows 上的 Amazon Appstore 以及所有依赖于 WSA 的应用程序和游戏。在此之前，仍将为客户提供技术支持。</p><p>在 2024 年 3 月 5 日之前安装了亚马逊应用商店或 Android 应用的客户，在 2025 年 3 月 5 日的弃用日期之前，将继续有权访问这些应用。如有其他问题，请联系我们的支持团队，网址为 support.microsoft.com。我们感谢开发者社区的支持，并将继续致力于在改进体验的过程中听取反馈。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:29:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142033.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[苹果未来几周将推出多款新品]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>据彭博社作者马克·古尔曼，<strong>苹果将在未来几周内宣布许多新产品。</strong>苹果将通过官网发布这些新品，而不会为此举办发布活动。新的 MacBook Air 将以 13 英寸和 15 英寸的 M3 芯片版本问世，还将推出首款配备 OLED 屏幕的 iPad Pro，以及新版本的 Apple Pencil 和 Magic Keyboard。古尔曼估计，这些新产品可能会在 3 月底或最迟在 4 月初发布。他推测苹果之所以不选择举办活动，是因为这些设备没有足够的内容来支持举办实体发布会。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Bloomberg author Mark Gurman, Apple will announce many new products in the coming weeks. Instead of holding an event, Apple will unveil these new items through its official website. The new MacBook Air models will come in 13-inch and 15-inch versions with M3 chips, and there will also be the first iPad Pro with an OLED screen, as well as new versions of the Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard. Gurman estimates that these new products will be released by the end of March or early April at the latest. He speculates that Apple has chosen not to hold an event because the devices do not have enough content to justify a physical presentation.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:17:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142031.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142031.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
