<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:21:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[游戏直播服务 Twitch 将退出韩国]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，亚马逊旗下游戏直播服务 Twitch 宣布将于 2024 年 2 月 27 日停止在韩国运营。其首席执行官 Dan Clancy 表示，做出这一决定是因为在该国运营 Twitch 的成本极高。Twitch 在韩国运营多年都是亏损的，因为该国的网络费用比世界其他地区高出 10 倍。该公司曾尝试多种方法来降低成本，例如使用 P2P 技术来提高片源质量，甚至将流的分辨率降低到 720p，但收效甚微。韩国是全球最大的视频游戏市场之一，退出该市场让 Twitch「深感悲痛」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Amazon’s game streaming service Twitch announced that it will cease operations in South Korea on February 27, 2024. CEO Dan Clancy stated that this decision was made due to the extremely high operating costs in the country. Twitch has been running at a loss in South Korea for many years because the internet fees are ten times higher than other regions worldwide. The company had tried various methods to reduce costs, such as using P2P technology to improve video quality and even lowering the stream resolution to 720p, but with little success. South Korea is one of the largest video game markets globally, and withdrawing from this market has left Twitch 「deeply saddened.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 08:08:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139593.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139593.html</link>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软再次「阉割」了 new Bing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐实测发现，微软再次 「阉割了」new Bing（Bing Chat）——<strong>每个会话现在仅支持 5 个回合，5 个回合后就会返回话题结束的提示</strong>。「&nbsp;很抱歉，此对话已达到其限制。使用 「扫除」 按钮清除此内容并进行更多聊天。」</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has once again 「castrated」 new Bing (Bing Chat) – each conversation now only supports 5 rounds, and will return a prompt when the topic ends: 「Sorry, this conversation has reached its limit. Use the ‘clear’ button to clear this content and chat more.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:24:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139491.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139491.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[实测] 过去几个月微软 new Bing 进步缓慢]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231204141906.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐针对 new Bing 进行的大量测试还显示，尽管微软为它引入了很多新功能，<strong>但和几个月之前相比，微软 new Bing 的 「智商」 似乎并没有显著提高。和以前一样，new Bing 频繁地捏造答案、经常捏造并不存在的 「事实」，在指出错误之后，new Bing 会被 「激怒」 并立即结束当前会话。</strong></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Our extensive testing of new Bing also shows that although Microsoft has introduced many new features for it, compared to a few months ago, the 「intelligence」 of Microsoft’s new Bing does not seem to have significantly improved. Like before, new Bing frequently fabricates answers and often fabricates non-existent 「facts」. After pointing out the errors, new Bing will be 「angered」 and immediately end the current session.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:18:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139483.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139483.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[海量的「虚拟人」色情视频正涌向互联网]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/20231203183155.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐监控的数据显示，<strong>成千上万个由 AI 生成的 「虚拟人」 短视频正在蜂拥涌向 YouTube、Facebook、TikTok、Instagram、X（Twitter）等主流社交媒体平台。</strong>我们重点追踪的几百个账号正在日夜不停的利用 AI 创建视频内容，这些内容相当一部分来自中国。为了快速获取流量，<strong>这些账号的操纵者从搜索引擎上批量获取色情内容，并由 AI 虚拟人以自述的方式阅读并生成视频。我们发现某些视频的播放量已突破千万。由于这些视频画面中的虚拟人声情并茂，不仔细甄别很容易误以为是真人。</strong>大量不明真相的观众对这些视频发表了评论。</p><p>社交媒体不会完全阻止虚拟人视频，但可能会要求创作者向观众声明视频主角是虚拟人，并且仍会沿用当前的内容审核政策来审核这些视频。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Thousands of AI-generated 「virtual human」 short videos are flooding towards mainstream social media platforms such as YouTube, Facebook, TikTok, Instagram, and X (Twitter). We have been closely monitoring hundreds of accounts that continuously use AI to create video content, with a significant portion originating from China. In order to quickly gain traffic, the operators of these accounts disclose obtaining pornographic content from search engines and generate videos in a self-narrative manner through AI virtual humans. We have found that the views on certain videos have already surpassed tens of millions. Due to the vivid portrayal of emotions by virtual humans in these videos, it is easy for uninformed viewers to mistake them for real people without careful discernment. A large number of unsuspecting audiences have commented on these videos.</p><p>Social media platforms may not completely block virtual human videos but may require creators to declare to the audience that the protagonist in the video is a virtual human. They will continue using their current content moderation policies to review these videos.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:33:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139471.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139471.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[传微软 2024 年夏天发布 Windows 12]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，据台湾商业时报 (CTEE) ，微软将于 2024 年 6 月发布其下一代操作系统 <strong>Windows 12</strong>，以及各种基于人工智能的 PC。这一消息的来源是广达电脑董事长林百里和宏碁董事长兼首席执行官陈俊圣最近在台湾医疗技术展览会上的发言。林百里预期明年夏季随着新一代的 Windows 作业系统时，AI PC 也将陆续推出。他看好这对 PC 硬件产业的机会。</p><p>这不是第一次出现有关 Windows 12 的传闻。英特尔首席财务官最近也声称 Windows 12 将于 2024 年问世。更早前有德国媒体报道，微软计划<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138116.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">将 Windows 12 打造为一个基于订阅的操作系统</a>。已经离开微软的前 Windows 负责人 Panos Panay 也曾暗示，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/117042.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 12 将由 AI 深度驱动</a>。</p><p>与此同时，微软还在紧锣密鼓的开发 Windows 11 24H2，这是 Windows 11 的下一个功能更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Taiwan Business Times (CTEE), Microsoft will release its next-generation operating system, Windows 12, and various AI-based PCs in June 2024. The source of this news is the speeches given by Lin Baili, Chairman of Quanta Computer, and Chen Junsheng, Chairman and CEO of Acer, at a recent medical technology exhibition in Taiwan. Lin Baili expects that with the new generation of Windows operating system next summer, AI PCs will also be launched one after another. He sees this as an opportunity for the PC hardware industry.</p><p>This is not the first time rumors about Windows 12 have surfaced. Recently, Intel’s CFO also claimed that Windows 12 will be released in 2024. Earlier reports from German media stated that Microsoft plans to develop Windows 12 as a subscription-based operating system. Former head of Windows at Microsoft who has since left the company, Panos Panay, also hinted that Windows 12 would be driven by AI.</p><p>Meanwhile, Microsoft is also actively developing Windows 11 24H2, which is the next feature update for Windows 11.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 07:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
