<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 19:22:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Instagram 推送了數量驚人的不雅短視頻]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，華爾街日報的一項測試顯示，Meta 旗下社交媒體 <strong>Instagram 的 Reels 視頻服務向該媒體建立的測試賬號推送了數量驚人的不雅內容。</strong>這包括兒童不雅視頻和露骨的成人色情視頻，以及一些美國大品牌的廣告。該媒體還觀察到，在青少年網紅賬户的成千上萬名粉絲中，經常包含有大量成年男性，後者也表現出對兒童和成人性內容的興趣。兒童保護組織加拿大兒童保護中心 (Canadian Centre for Child Protection) 進行的測試也得出了類似的結果。</p><p>Meta 發言人迴應稱，《華爾街日報》的測試並不代表數十億用户所看到的內容。對於為什麼算法會將顯示兒童、性和廣告的不同視頻編排在一起，該公司不予置評，Instagram 每個月都會對 400 萬個涉嫌違反其標準的視頻進行刪除或限流。</p><p>Instagram Reels 短視頻的廣告主包括 Match、Bumble、迪士尼、沃爾瑪、Hims、必勝客等知名公司，這些公司要麼對 Meta 的迴應表示不滿，要麼不予置評。可以肯定的是，這些知名品牌都不希望在不當內容旁投放廣告，因為這有損其品牌形象。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A test conducted by The Wall Street Journal revealed that Meta’s social media platform, Instagram, pushed an alarming amount of explicit content to a test account created by the media outlet. This included inappropriate videos involving children, explicit adult content, as well as advertisements from some major American brands. The media outlet also observed that among the tens of thousands of followers of teenage influencer accounts, there was a significant presence of adult males who displayed an interest in both child and adult sexual content. Similar results were obtained in tests conducted by the Canadian Centre for Child Protection.</p><p>A spokesperson for Meta responded by stating that The Wall Street Journal’s test does not represent the content seen by billions of users. The company refrained from commenting on why the algorithm would group together different videos featuring children, sex, and advertisements. Instagram removes or limits the visibility of around 4 million videos each month that are suspected of violating its standards.</p><p>Prominent companies such as Match, Bumble, Disney, Walmart, Hims, and Pizza Hut advertise on Instagram’s Reels short video feature, and they either expressed dissatisfaction with Meta’s response or refrained from commenting. It is evident that these well-known brands do not want their advertisements to appear alongside inappropriate content as it would harm their brand image.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:30:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[下載] 精簡版系統 tiny11 2311 發佈：基於 Win11 23H2 製作]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，Win11 第三方精簡版系統 tiny11 迎來更新，開發者 @NTDEV 現在基於 Windows 11 23H2 製作了新版本 <strong>tiny11 2311</strong>。<strong>tiny11 2311</strong> 包含了 Win11 23H2 的所有新功能，包括 Copilot、RAR 解壓縮支持、重新設計的音量滑塊、設置應用中的 RGB 控制等。與老版本相比，tiny11 2311 的體積縮小了 20%。並且可以接收微軟官方的服務更新。該版本沒有預裝 Edge 瀏覽器，刪除了 Xbox 相關功能（從微軟商店下載遊戲後會恢復）。</p><ul><li>讀者可從 <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a> 下載 tiny11 2311</li><li>網盤下載：請<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/wxa-6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">點此關注</a>公眾號 「軟餐」，發送口令&nbsp;<code><strong>139081</strong></code>獲取下載鏈接。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>[[Download] Simplified version system tiny11 2311 released: Based on Win11 23H2 production] The third-party lightweight version of Win11, tiny11, has received an update. Developer @NTDEV has now created a new version, tiny11 2311, based on Windows 11 23H2. Tiny11 2311 includes all the new features of Win11 23H2, including Copilot, RAR decompression support, redesigned volume slider, and RGB control in the Settings app. Compared to the previous version, tiny11 2311 has reduced its size by 20%. It can also receive official service updates from Microsoft. This version does not come pre-installed with Edge browser and removes Xbox-related functions (which will be restored after downloading games from the Microsoft Store).</p><p>Readers can download tiny11 2311 from <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a>.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 05:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[復旦教授肖仰華：我們與 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>復旦大學計算機科學技術學院教授、上海市數據科學重點實驗室主任肖仰華推測，ChatGPT 或許使用了大小模型結合的技術，多模型協同可以很大程度上解決成本問題。「讓大模型去解決複雜問題，但普通用户一般都是簡單的問題，用小模型就可以了。」 他形容，ChatGPT 的 AI 技術已形成一種 「飛輪效應」，迭代和優化正推動技術進入一個自我強化的快速發展階段行業或將變成 「只有第一，沒有第二」 的局面。「我們的文化中，聰明人太多，總想抄近路。有時候就是要堅持，要笨一點，才能做出真正的大殺器。<strong>我們與 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大，不是在縮小。</strong>」 肖教授指出，還有很多如機器人、環境交互技術、醫療大模型、科學大模型等其他方向，都是大趨勢。企業可以在這些新領域找到自己的優勢。肖仰華指出，AI 技術的進步可能導致人類智力的相對退化。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Recently, Professor Xiaoyanghua, from the School of Computer Science and Technology at Fudan University and Director of the Shanghai Key Laboratory of Data Science, speculated that ChatGPT may have used a combination of large and small models to address cost issues. 「Let the large model solve complex problems, but ordinary users usually have simple questions that can be answered with a small model,」 he described. The AI technology of ChatGPT has formed a 「flywheel effect」, where iteration and optimization are driving the technology into a self-reinforcing rapid development stage. The industry may become a situation where there is only one leader without any competitors. 「In our culture, there are too many smart people who always want shortcuts. Sometimes we need to persist and be a little foolish in order to create truly powerful tools. The gap between us and OpenAI is widening rather than narrowing,」 Professor Xiao pointed out. He also mentioned that there are other emerging trends such as robotics, interactive environmental technologies, large-scale medical models, scientific models, etc., where companies can find their own advantages. Professor Xiaoyanghua indicated that advancements in AI technology could potentially lead to relative decline in human intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Auto Dark Mode：自動切換 Windows 暗黑模式]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/dark-light-mode-640x589.png.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p><strong>Auto Dark Mode</strong> 是一款可自動調節 Windows 夜間模式的開源小軟件，可實現在預定時間裏自動切換 Windows 的深色和淺色主題，適用於 Windows 11 和 Windows 10。最新版本修復了在禁用自動模式時主題切換仍然生效的問題，還包含了許多新的翻譯。該軟件還支持切換強調色、鼠標光標、桌面壁紙、Windows 主題或 Office 主題等功能。該軟件是微軟商店 2022 年度 「社區選擇獎」 的獲得者。</p><ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://apps.microsoft.com/store/detail/auto-dark-mode/XP8JK4HZBVF435" target="_blank">從微軟商店下載</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/AutoDarkMode/Windows-Auto-Night-Mode/releases" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">從 GitHub 下載</a></li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Auto Dark Mode is an open-source software that automatically adjusts the Windows night mode. It can switch between dark and light themes in Windows at predetermined times. It is compatible with Windows 11 and Windows 10. The latest version fixes the issue of theme switching still being effective when automatic mode is disabled, and it also includes many new translations. This software also supports switching accent colors, mouse cursors, desktop wallpapers, Windows themes, or Office themes. The software is the winner of the Microsoft Store’s 2022 「Community Choice Award」.</p><p><a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/store/detail/auto-dark-mode/XP8JK4HZBVF435" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Store</a> / <a href="https://github.com/AutoDarkMode/Windows-Auto-Night-Mode/releases" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GitHub</a></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 08:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139068.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139068.html</link>
            <category>系統工具</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[誕生 20 週年，文本編輯器 Notepad++8.6 版發佈]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，文本編輯器 Notepad++官方發佈了最新的 Notepad++ 8.6 版，以紀念該編輯器誕生 20 週年。Notepad++ 8.6 是一個較小的版本，包含多處 Bug 修復、新的多重編輯功能（允許用户在文本文檔的多個位置添加或刪除字符）、自定義多選背景和護理顏色等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The official release of the latest version, Notepad++ 8.6, has been announced by the text editor Notepad++, commemorating its 20th anniversary. Notepad++ 8.6 is a minor release that includes several bug fixes, new multiple editing capabilities (allowing users to add or remove characters at multiple positions within a text document), customizable multi-selection backgrounds and caret colors, and more.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:19:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</link>
            <category>辦公/生產力</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
