<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 12:06:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[去中心化社交應用 Bluesky 全面開放用戶註冊]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>去中心化的社交媒體應用程序 Bluesky 全面開放了用戶註冊</strong>（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.blueskyweb.app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Play 商店</a>）<strong>。</strong>現在任何人無需邀請即可註冊賬號。在開放註冊之前，該應用增強了其基礎設施和內容審核能力。Bluesky 於 2023 年 3 月<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/121704.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">推出</a>，一直以來採用邀請制模式，此前超過 300 萬註冊了該應用。Bluesky 官方還宣佈，未來幾周或幾個月將推出一些新功能，包括：為想要進一步審核其 Feed 的用戶提供標籤服務、允許開發者和其他組織使用自己的審核規則創建自己的 Bluesky 服務器、提供類似於 X 的收費額外功能等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The decentralized social media application Bluesky has opened up user registration to the public. Now anyone can sign up for an account without needing an invitation. Prior to opening up registration, the app enhanced its infrastructure and content moderation capabilities. Launched in March 2023, Bluesky had been operating on an invitation-only basis and attracted over 3 million registrations. Bluesky’s official announcement also revealed that new features will be rolled out in the coming weeks or months, including labeling services for users who want to further moderate their feed, allowing developers and other organizations to create their own Bluesky servers with their own moderation rules, and offering additional paid features similar to X.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德國高速鐵路還在用古老的 Windows 3.11]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，由西門子交通發佈的一則招聘廣告（已刪除）顯示，<strong>其客戶德國鐵路公司（DB）內部仍在使用已有 30 年曆史的 Windows for Workgroups 3.11 系統。該系統發佈於 1992 年 10 月。</strong>西門子正為德國鐵路尋找一位瞭解傳統操作系統的系統管理員，尤其是 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups。其職責是處理該系統的更新和維護。這則招聘信息還顯示，列車駕駛室的顯示系統基於 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups 運行，該系統實時向駕駛員顯示所有重要的技術數據。據悉，該系統最有可能用於舊的 ICE 1 和 ICE2 高速城際快車。西門子交通證實了招聘信息的真實性，並解釋説火車和鐵路基礎設施的使用壽命為 30 年或更長時間。該公司向公眾保證，其客戶 「繼續安全地使用業內久經考驗的遺留系統」，並且西門子為整個生命週期提供支持和維護。該公司還補充説，更新的系統是使用當前可用的軟件產品開發的，甚至會用到人工智能。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A recruitment advertisement (now deleted) released by Siemens Mobility has revealed that their client, Deutsche Bahn (DB), is still using the 30-year-old Windows for Workgroups 3.11 system internally. This system was released in October 1992. Siemens is actively seeking a system administrator with knowledge of traditional operating systems, particularly Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, to handle updates and maintenance of this system for Deutsche Bahn. The job description also states that the display systems in train cabins run on Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, providing real-time display of all critical technical data to the train drivers. It is reported that this system is most likely used for the older ICE 1 and ICE 2 high-speed intercity trains. Siemens Mobility has confirmed the authenticity of the recruitment information, explaining that the lifespan of trains and railway infrastructure is typically 30 years or longer. The company assures the public that their clients continue to use industry-proven legacy systems safely, and Siemens provides support and maintenance throughout the entire lifecycle. The company also adds that the updated systems are developed using currently available software products and may even incorporate artificial intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[高通公開提及下一代 Windows 系統：2024 年中發佈]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>高通最近提到了下一代 Windows。</strong>該公司總裁兼首席執行官 Cristiano Renno Amon 在 2024 年第一季度財報電話會議上説<strong>「 下一版本的微軟 Windows」 將於 2024 年中期發佈。</strong>高通在一個不同於 Windows 11 的未定義的」Windows 操作系統」 上測試了其驍龍 X Elite 芯片組。他沒有明確提及它是否 Windows 12，但他透露該系統具備 「大量 Windows AI 功能」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Qualcomm recently mentioned the next generation of Windows. Cristiano Renno Amon, the President and CEO of the company, stated during Qualcomm’s Q1 2024 earnings call that the 「next version of Microsoft Windows」 will be released in mid-2024. Qualcomm tested its Snapdragon X Elite chipset on an      「Windows operating system」 different from Windows 11. Although he did not specifically mention whether it is Windows 12, he revealed that the system possesses 「a lot of Windows AI capabilities.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141481.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141481.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟首次提及 Windows 11 24H2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/2006409902.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，據 Windows Latest，微軟的開發人員在一份支持文檔討論了有關 Windows 11 24H2 的內容。Windows 11 24H2 是 Windows 11 的下一個重大版本。該版本會在今年第三季度末到第四季度初發布，將帶來更多的人工智能支持。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Windows Latest, Microsoft developers have discussed the details of Windows 11 24H2 in a support document. Windows 11 24H2 is the next major version of Windows 11. This release is expected to be available from the end of the third quarter to the beginning of the fourth quarter of this year and will bring additional artificial intelligence support.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 09:48:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141452.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141452.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google 搜索停止提供網頁快照]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>Google 已從搜索結果中刪除了網頁快照選項。</strong>Google 員工 Danny Sullivan 確認，網頁緩存功能不再顯示在 Google 搜索結果中。以前該選項位於搜索結果條目右側的菜單中，用戶可藉助該選項訪問 Google 緩存網頁的早期索引版本。緩存功能於幾年前引入，它是網絡原因導致原始網頁無法加載時的替代選擇，但現在網絡狀況已有了很大改善。因此，Google 決定停止提供該功能。過去幾個月來，Google 一直在逐漸刪除該功能。Google 建議希望查看網站緩存版本的用戶使用 Google Search Console。用戶還可使用 Wayback Machine 等服務。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google has removed the option for webpage snapshots from its search results. Google employee Danny Sullivan confirmed that the webpage cache functionality is no longer displayed in Google search results. Previously, this option was located in the menu on the right side of the search result entry, allowing users to access earlier indexed versions of webpages through Google’s cache. Google now considers this feature irrelevant. The cache functionality was introduced several years ago as an alternative when the original webpage couldn’t load due to network issues. However, with significant improvements in network conditions, Google has decided to discontinue this feature. Over the past few months, Google has been gradually removing this functionality. Google advises users who wish to view cached versions of websites to use the Google Search Console. Users can also utilize services like the Wayback Machine.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 09:40:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141444.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141444.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
