<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 23:26:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[傳微軟 2024 年夏天發佈 Windows 12]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，據台灣商業時報 (CTEE) ，微軟將於 2024 年 6 月發佈其下一代操作系統 <strong>Windows 12</strong>，以及各種基於人工智能的 PC。這一消息的來源是廣達電腦董事長林百里和宏碁董事長兼首席執行官陳俊聖最近在台灣醫療技術展覽會上的發言。林百里預期明年夏季隨着新一代的 Windows 作業系統時，AI PC 也將陸續推出。他看好這對 PC 硬件產業的機會。</p><p>這不是第一次出現有關 Windows 12 的傳聞。英特爾首席財務官最近也聲稱 Windows 12 將於 2024 年問世。更早前有德國媒體報道，微軟計劃<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138116.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">將 Windows 12 打造為一個基於訂閲的操作系統</a>。已經離開微軟的前 Windows 負責人 Panos Panay 也曾暗示，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/117042.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 12 將由 AI 深度驅動</a>。</p><p>與此同時，微軟還在緊鑼密鼓的開發 Windows 11 24H2，這是 Windows 11 的下一個功能更新。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Taiwan Business Times (CTEE), Microsoft will release its next-generation operating system, Windows 12, and various AI-based PCs in June 2024. The source of this news is the speeches given by Lin Baili, Chairman of Quanta Computer, and Chen Junsheng, Chairman and CEO of Acer, at a recent medical technology exhibition in Taiwan. Lin Baili expects that with the new generation of Windows operating system next summer, AI PCs will also be launched one after another. He sees this as an opportunity for the PC hardware industry.</p><p>This is not the first time rumors about Windows 12 have surfaced. Recently, Intel’s CFO also claimed that Windows 12 will be released in 2024. Earlier reports from German media stated that Microsoft plans to develop Windows 12 as a subscription-based operating system. Former head of Windows at Microsoft who has since left the company, Panos Panay, also hinted that Windows 12 would be driven by AI.</p><p>Meanwhile, Microsoft is also actively developing Windows 11 24H2, which is the next feature update for Windows 11.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 07:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139439.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[「微軟畫圖」應用全面迎來 AI 作圖功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/GABtxPAX0AIpVe7.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟已低調向所有 「微軟畫圖」（Microsoft Paint）用戶開放基於 AI 的 Cocreator（共同創作者）功能。</strong>這是一項人工智能生成圖像功能，基於 OpenAI 的 DALL-E 3 模型。現在用戶無需進行任何申請，即可直接訪問該功能。<strong>軟餐在我們的測試設備上已經獲得該功能。</strong></p><p>用戶必須登錄微軟賬戶才能使用此功能。用戶將自動獲得 50 個積分，用於在 Cocreator 中創作圖像。目前，Cocreator 僅支持英語，並且目前在美國、法國、英國、澳大利亞、加拿大、意大利和德國可用。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>要使用 Cocreator，請打開 Microsoft Paint，然後選擇工具欄上的 Cocreator 圖標以查看 Cocreator（共同創作者）側面板。在文本框中，輸入要創建的圖像的描述。例如，您可以輸入 「一隻戴紅帽子的藍貓」 或 「有山和湖的風景」。儘可能具有描述性，以生成符合您期望的結果。</p><p>輸入文本後，選擇要創建圖像的樣式，然後選擇 「創建」 按鈕。 Cocreator 將生成您請求的圖像的三種不同變體，您可以單擊任何變體以將該圖像應用到 Paint 畫布並開始創建。</p></blockquote><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has quietly opened up its AI-based Cocreator feature to all Microsoft Paint users. This is an artificial intelligence-generated image creation feature based on OpenAI’s DALL-E 3 model. Users can now access this feature directly without any application process. The software update has already been received on our testing devices.</p><p>Users must log in to their Microsoft accounts in order to use this feature. Upon logging in, users will automatically receive 50 points for creating images in Cocreator. Currently, Cocreator only supports English and is available in the United States, France, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, Italy, and Germany.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>To use Cocreator, open Microsoft Paint and select the Cocreator icon on the toolbar to see the Cocreator side panel. In the text box, enter a description of the image you want to create. For example, you can type 「a blue cat with a red hat」 or 「a landscape with mountains and a lake」. Be as descriptive as possible to generate results matching your expectations.</p><p>After you enter the text, choose a style in which you want to create your image and then select the Create button. Cocreator will generate three different variants of the image you requested, you can click on any of the variants to apply that image to Paint canvas and start creating.</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:11:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>圖形圖像</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟有意禁止 Win11 用戶恢復 Win10 任務欄]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，微軟似乎有意禁止用戶在 Windows 11 上恢復 Win10 時代的任務欄。——正在向 Canary 通道上推送的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139405.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows 11 build 26002</a> 中包含一個名為 「DisableWin10Taskbar」 的隱藏功能。顧名思義，啓用其 ID（42537950）後會阻止加載 Windows 10 任務欄。此外它還會破壞第三方應用程序，例如 StartAllBack 或 ExplorerPatcher。</p><p>由於微軟並未默認開啓這項功能，因此很難判斷微軟最終決定阻止 Windows 11 用戶恢復舊的任務欄。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft seems to be intentionally preventing users from restoring the Windows 10 era taskbar on Windows 11. In the Windows 11 build 26002 being pushed to the Canary channel, there is a hidden feature called 「DisableWin10Taskbar」. As the name suggests, enabling its ID (42537950) will prevent loading of the Windows 10 taskbar. Additionally, it will break third-party applications such as StartAllBack or ExplorerPatcher.</p><p>Since Microsoft has not enabled this feature by default, it is difficult to determine whether Microsoft has actually decided to block Windows 11 users from restoring the old taskbar.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 15:46:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139414.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139414.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[圖] 微軟發佈 2023 款「醜毛衣」Windows Ugly Sweater]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/1701176110_bliss_ugly_sweaters_image_story.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，在西方假日季臨近之際，微軟按照傳統推出了 2023 年的 「Windows 醜陋毛衣」(Windows Ugly Sweater)。微軟沒有停止懷舊，這次在毛衣上印上了經典的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/131375.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows XP 默認的 Bliss 壁紙</a>。過去幾年，微軟還曾在醜陋毛衣上印製 Windows 95、掃雷遊戲、微軟畫圖（MS Paint）和 Clippy（大眼夾/回形針）等形象。消費者可通過 windowsuglysweater.com 網站購買 「醜陋毛衣」，微軟將把銷售所得的 10 萬美元捐給大自然保護協會（The&nbsp;Nature&nbsp;Conservancy）。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>As the Western holiday season approaches, Microsoft has traditionally released the 「Windows Ugly Sweater」 for 2023. Microsoft continues its nostalgia by printing the classic Windows XP default Bliss wallpaper on the sweater. In recent years, Microsoft has also printed Windows 95, Minesweeper game, MS Paint, and Clippy (the paperclip) images on ugly sweaters. Consumers can purchase the 「ugly sweater」 through the website windowsuglysweater.com, and Microsoft will donate $100,000 of sales proceeds to The Nature Conservancy (TNC).</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:52:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[鏈接] 三星瀏覽器 Windows 版發佈：非三星電腦也能用]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/693292.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，三星剛剛向<a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">微軟商店</a>上架了適用於 Windows 系統的瀏覽器 <strong>Samsung Internet</strong>。該瀏覽器支持 64 位 Windows 10 及以上版本系統，即使不是三星品牌設備也可運行。三星對該瀏覽器的描述只有一句話：「Samsung Internet 通過各種功能和保護您的隱私，為您提供最佳的網絡瀏覽體驗。」 據悉，該瀏覽器支持部分同步功能，可從安卓版 Samsung Internet 瀏覽器同步瀏覽歷史記錄、書籤、保存的頁面和打開的標籤等數據，但尚不支持同步保存的密碼。</p><p>同時，PC 版 Samsung Internet 支持隱身模式、廣告攔截器，支持從其他瀏覽器（包括 Edge 和 Chrome）導入瀏覽歷史記錄/書籤和搜索引擎。</p><p>三星之前在安卓平台上發佈的 Samsung Internet 瀏覽器擁有眾多忠實的粉絲。這將有助於三星獲取桌面瀏覽器的份額。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Samsung has just released the browser Samsung Internet on the <a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Store</a> for Windows systems. This browser supports 64-bit Windows 10 and above, and can be run even on non-Samsung devices. The description of this browser by Samsung is only one sentence: 「Samsung Internet provides you with the best web browsing experience through various features and protecting your privacy.」 It is reported that this browser supports partial synchronization, allowing users to sync browsing history, bookmarks, saved pages, and open tabs from the Android version of Samsung Internet browser. However, syncing saved passwords is not yet supported.</p><p>In addition, the PC version of Samsung Internet supports incognito mode and ad blocker, as well as importing browsing history/bookmarks and search engines from other browsers (including Edge and Chrome).</p><p>Samsung’s previously released Samsung Internet browser on the Android platform has a large number of loyal fans. This will help Samsung gain market share in desktop browsers.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</link>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
