<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 12:12:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[去中心化社交应用 Bluesky 全面开放用户注册]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>去中心化的社交媒体应用程序 Bluesky 全面开放了用户注册</strong>（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.blueskyweb.app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Play 商店</a>）<strong>。</strong>现在任何人无需邀请即可注册账号。在开放注册之前，该应用增强了其基础设施和内容审核能力。Bluesky 于 2023 年 3 月<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/121704.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">推出</a>，一直以来采用邀请制模式，此前超过 300 万注册了该应用。Bluesky 官方还宣布，未来几周或几个月将推出一些新功能，包括：为想要进一步审核其 Feed 的用户提供标签服务、允许开发者和其他组织使用自己的审核规则创建自己的 Bluesky 服务器、提供类似于 X 的收费额外功能等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The decentralized social media application Bluesky has opened up user registration to the public. Now anyone can sign up for an account without needing an invitation. Prior to opening up registration, the app enhanced its infrastructure and content moderation capabilities. Launched in March 2023, Bluesky had been operating on an invitation-only basis and attracted over 3 million registrations. Bluesky’s official announcement also revealed that new features will be rolled out in the coming weeks or months, including labeling services for users who want to further moderate their feed, allowing developers and other organizations to create their own Bluesky servers with their own moderation rules, and offering additional paid features similar to X.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141541.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Z-Library 现在可以高效地推荐图书]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>电子书网站 Z-Library 周一宣布改进了其图书推荐系统。</strong>新的系统可帮助读者找到真正符合您兴趣的图书。Z-Library 介绍说，以前，其图书推荐仅基于用户行为，但这种方法存在局限，例如它无法为稀有或不受欢迎的图书生成推荐。<strong>为此该网站开发了自己的技术，可以在数百万本图书中找到相似的文本，并将其应用于推荐模块中。</strong>现在，在生成推荐时，除了考虑用户行为，还会用到其独特的文本比较技术。这意味着在选择推荐图书时，Z-Library 会分析图书内容，以提供更准确、多样化的建议。</p><p>Z-Library 同时再次提醒避免访问两个仿冒网站，分别是 z-lib[.] io 和 z-lib[.] id。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The e-book website Z-Library announced on Monday that it has improved its book recommendation system. The new system is designed to help readers find books that truly match their interests. According to Z-Library, the previous book recommendations were solely based on user behavior, but this approach had limitations, such as the inability to generate recommendations for rare or unpopular books. To address this, the website developed its own technology to find similar texts among millions of books and implemented it in the recommendation module. Now, when generating recommendations, Z-Library takes into account not only user behavior but also its unique text comparison technology. This means that when selecting recommended books, Z-Library analyzes the content of the books to provide more accurate and diverse suggestions.</p><p>Z-Library also reminds users to avoid accessing two fraudulent websites, namely z-lib[.] io and z-lib[.] id.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 10:55:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141526.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141526.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[胡锡进谈炒股赔钱：「如果时间可以倒流，我怎么会投呢？」]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>2 月 5 日，胡锡进做客京东金融直播间，分享 「老胡投资这一年」。截至 2 月 5 日收盘，胡锡进总浮亏 78025.6 元，今日浮亏 347 元。直播中，胡锡进笑称，<strong>「如果时间可以倒流，带着今天的思路和见识回到 3140 点，我怎么会投呢？」</strong>胡锡进称，炒股一是为了通过股市了解中国经济，做参与者而不是旁观者。二是开发自己的能力，如果能赚钱，炒股赚钱就不用写稿了。他坦言，「没有能力做投资建议，别模仿老胡，我只是按照我的逻辑、见识去炒股。」 而此前胡锡进曾表示 「2800 点以下遍地是黄金」 如何看待，他表示对于这个问题保持沉默。目前到底是什么情况，需要时间验证，而截至目前加仓的 12 万元，基本是平的。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 16:21:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141497.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141497.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德国高速铁路还在用古老的 Windows 3.11]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，由西门子交通发布的一则招聘广告（已删除）显示，<strong>其客户德国铁路公司（DB）内部仍在使用已有 30 年历史的 Windows for Workgroups 3.11 系统。该系统发布于 1992 年 10 月。</strong>西门子正为德国铁路寻找一位了解传统操作系统的系统管理员，尤其是 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups。其职责是处理该系统的更新和维护。这则招聘信息还显示，列车驾驶室的显示系统基于 Windows 3.11 for Workgroups 运行，该系统实时向驾驶员显示所有重要的技术数据。据悉，该系统最有可能用于旧的 ICE 1 和 ICE2 高速城际快车。西门子交通证实了招聘信息的真实性，并解释说火车和铁路基础设施的使用寿命为 30 年或更长时间。该公司向公众保证，其客户 「继续安全地使用业内久经考验的遗留系统」，并且西门子为整个生命周期提供支持和维护。该公司还补充说，更新的系统是使用当前可用的软件产品开发的，甚至会用到人工智能。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A recruitment advertisement (now deleted) released by Siemens Mobility has revealed that their client, Deutsche Bahn (DB), is still using the 30-year-old Windows for Workgroups 3.11 system internally. This system was released in October 1992. Siemens is actively seeking a system administrator with knowledge of traditional operating systems, particularly Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, to handle updates and maintenance of this system for Deutsche Bahn. The job description also states that the display systems in train cabins run on Windows 3.11 for Workgroups, providing real-time display of all critical technical data to the train drivers. It is reported that this system is most likely used for the older ICE 1 and ICE 2 high-speed intercity trains. Siemens Mobility has confirmed the authenticity of the recruitment information, explaining that the lifespan of trains and railway infrastructure is typically 30 years or longer. The company assures the public that their clients continue to use industry-proven legacy systems safely, and Siemens provides support and maintenance throughout the entire lifecycle. The company also adds that the updated systems are developed using currently available software products and may even incorporate artificial intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141489.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[高通公开提及下一代 Windows 系统：2024 年中发布]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>高通最近提到了下一代 Windows。</strong>该公司总裁兼首席执行官 Cristiano Renno Amon 在 2024 年第一季度财报电话会议上说<strong>「 下一版本的微软 Windows」 将于 2024 年中期发布。</strong>高通在一个不同于 Windows 11 的未定义的」Windows 操作系统」 上测试了其骁龙 X Elite 芯片组。他没有明确提及它是否 Windows 12，但他透露该系统具备 「大量 Windows AI 功能」。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Qualcomm recently mentioned the next generation of Windows. Cristiano Renno Amon, the President and CEO of the company, stated during Qualcomm’s Q1 2024 earnings call that the 「next version of Microsoft Windows」 will be released in mid-2024. Qualcomm tested its Snapdragon X Elite chipset on an      「Windows operating system」 different from Windows 11. Although he did not specifically mention whether it is Windows 12, he revealed that the system possesses 「a lot of Windows AI capabilities.」</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141481.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141481.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
