<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:45:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[蘋果未來幾周將推出多款新品]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>據彭博社作者馬克·古爾曼，<strong>蘋果將在未來幾周內宣佈許多新產品。</strong>蘋果將通過官網發佈這些新品，而不會為此舉辦發佈活動。新的 MacBook Air 將以 13 英寸和 15 英寸的 M3 芯片版本問世，還將推出首款配備 OLED 屏幕的 iPad Pro，以及新版本的 Apple Pencil 和 Magic Keyboard。古爾曼估計，這些新產品可能會在 3 月底或最遲在 4 月初發布。他推測蘋果之所以不選擇舉辦活動，是因為這些設備沒有足夠的內容來支持舉辦實體發佈會。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Bloomberg author Mark Gurman, Apple will announce many new products in the coming weeks. Instead of holding an event, Apple will unveil these new items through its official website. The new MacBook Air models will come in 13-inch and 15-inch versions with M3 chips, and there will also be the first iPad Pro with an OLED screen, as well as new versions of the Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard. Gurman estimates that these new products will be released by the end of March or early April at the latest. He speculates that Apple has chosen not to hold an event because the devices do not have enough content to justify a physical presentation.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:17:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142031.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142031.html</link>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德國關閉該國最大非法交易平台]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>德國警方成功關閉了非法交易平台 Crimemarket.is。</strong>警方對該平台進行了長達四年的監視，並於二月底進行了 100 次家庭搜查，併成功扣押了該網站。Crimemarket.is 是德國最大的非法交易平台，在線提供毒品、假文件、武器以及指導從事網絡犯罪或欺詐的手冊的銷售。當局還認為，訪客之間也進行了武器和兒童色情品的交易。訪客可能使用了加密貨幣進行支付。該網站在 2020 年引起了德國警方的注意。德國警方為此發佈了多個逮捕令，並表示可能還會有更多逮捕行動。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The German police have successfully shut down the illegal trading platform Crimemarket.is. The platform was under surveillance by the police for four years, and in late February, they conducted 100 home searches and successfully seized the website. Crimemarket.is was the largest illegal trading platform in Germany, facilitating the sale of drugs, fake documents, weapons, and manuals for engaging in cybercrime or fraud. Authorities also suspect that weapons and child pornography were traded among visitors. Cryptocurrency was reportedly used as a payment method by the visitors. The website came to the attention of the German police in 2020, leading to the issuance of multiple arrest warrants, with the possibility of further arrests.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:12:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142029.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142029.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Claude 3 發佈，官方稱表現優於 GPT-4 和 Gemini]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006502738.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>Anthropic 發佈了 Claude 3 語言模型，據稱其表現優於 GPT-4 和 Gemini。</strong>Anthropic 推出的第三代 AI 模型包括三個版本：Haiku、Sonnet 和 Opus。Claude 3 可以對長達 150,000 個詞的文本進行摘要，並且在競爭的語言模型中表現更好。AI 初創公司 Anthropic 表示，<strong>在測試中，Claude 3 的 Opus 模型在包括大學水平推理、編程和數學等方面表現優於競爭對手 OpenAI 和谷歌的 GPT-4 和 Gemini 1.0 Ultra。</strong>Opus 是最先進且最昂貴的模型，Haiku 是最小的版本，被稱為 「最快且成本效益最高」。該模型應能夠在不到三秒鐘內閲讀包含圖表和圖形的簡明研究報告。</p><p>這是 Claude 首次提供多模態支持。Claude 3 可以同時處理文本和圖像輸入，並且應能夠對長達 150,000 個詞的文本進行摘要，是其前身的兩倍。Anthropic 表示，與 Claude 2.1 相比，第三代語言模型能夠更好地理解上下文，處理更長的指令，並且更準確。據稱，Sonnet 是中等模型，速度是上一代的兩倍，在 「需要快速響應的任務」 方面表現出色。</p><p>Anthropic 的 Claude 3 模型根據一份文件使用了來自 2023 年 8 月以後的公開信息和第三方的非公開數據進行訓練。語言模型的訓練使用了亞馬遜網絡服務和谷歌雲的硬件。亞馬遜和谷歌都對這家初創公司進行了投資。</p><p>Opus 和 Sonnet 從今天開始可用，Haiku 的發佈將在不久之後。Anthropic 對 Claude 3 Opus 處理的每一百萬個標記收取 15 美元的費用。相比之下，OpenAI 對 GPT-4 Turbo 處理的每一百萬個標記收費 10 美元。Sonnet 和 Haiku 分別為每一百萬個標記收取 3 美元和 0.25 美元。Claude 還有一個限量版的免費版本。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Anthropic has released the Claude 3 language model, which is claimed to outperform GPT-4 and Gemini. The third-generation AI model introduced by Anthropic includes three versions: Haiku, Sonnet, and Opus. Claude 3 is capable of summarizing texts of up to 150,000 words and performs better than competing language models.</p><p>AI startup Anthropic states that in tests, Claude 3’s Opus model performed better than GPT-4 and Gemini 1.0 Ultra from competitors OpenAI and Google in areas such as university-level reasoning, programming, and mathematics. Opus is the most advanced and expensive model, while Haiku is the smallest version, known for being 「the fastest and most cost-effective.」 The model should be able to read a concise research report with diagrams and graphics 「in less than three seconds.」</p><p>This is the first time Claude provides multimodal support. Claude 3 can handle both text and image inputs and is expected to summarize texts of up to 150,000 words, twice as much as its predecessor. According to Anthropic, the third generation of its language model can better understand context, process longer instructions, and be more accurate than Claude 2.1. Sonnet, the medium-sized model, is reportedly twice as fast as the previous generation and excels in 「tasks that require rapid responses.」</p><p>Anthropic’s Claude 3 models were trained on publicly available information from August 2023 onwards, as well as non-public third-party data, as stated in a paper. The training of the language models utilized the hardware of Amazon Web Services and Google Cloud. Both Amazon and Google have invested in the startup.</p><p>Opus and Sonnet are available starting today, while the release of Haiku will follow 「soon.」 Anthropic charges $15 for every million tokens processed by Claude 3 Opus. In comparison, OpenAI charges $10 for every million tokens processed by GPT-4 Turbo. For Sonnet and Haiku, the respective costs are $3 and $0.25 for 1 million tokens. There is also a limited free version of Claude available, although Anthropic’s language models are currently not officially available in the Netherlands and Belgium.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:46:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142014.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142014.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德國公司將上線 iOS 第三方應用商店 App Marketplace]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>德國數字服務提供商 Mobivention 宣佈，將於 3 月 7 日在歐盟推出名為 App Marketplace 的 iOS 第三方應用商店。</strong>這也是歐盟數字市場法案（DMA）正式生效的前一天。本週晚些時候，蘋果將發佈 iOS 17.4。應 DMA 的要求，此更新將使歐盟用户能夠在 App Store 之外下載 iOS 應用程序。Mobivention 將成為歐盟首家提供此類替代應用商店的公司。該公司稱，App Marketplace 具有 「簡化的規則、替代計費模式、較低的應用內購買收入份額以及集成替代支付解決方案的可能性」。該公司補充説，他們直接與蘋果合作，以確保遵守蘋果的指導方針。除了 Mobivention，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141917.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MacPaw</a> 和 Epic Games 也在開發適用於歐洲市場的自有應用商店。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>German digital service provider Mobivention has announced the launch of an alternative iOS third-party app store called App Marketplace in the European Union on March 7th. This comes a day before the official enforcement of the Digital Markets Act (DMA). Later this week, Apple will release iOS 17.4, which, in compliance with the DMA, will allow EU users to download iOS applications from sources other than the App Store. Mobivention will be the first company in the EU to offer such an alternative app store. According to the company, the App Marketplace will feature 「simplified rules, alternative billing models, a lower revenue share for in-app purchases, and the possibility to integrate alternative payment solutions.」 They also stated that they have collaborated directly with Apple to ensure compliance with the company’s guidelines. In addition to Mobivention, MacPaw and Epic Games are also developing their own app stores for the European market.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:33:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html</link>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[ChatGPT 推出「大聲朗讀」功能，將文本回答轉為語音]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>OpenAI 發佈了 ChatGPT 的 Read Aloud（<strong>大聲朗讀</strong>）功能。</strong>該功能適用於 GPT-4 和 GPT-3.5 用户。聊天機器人可以將文本轉化為音頻並讀出內容。該功能在 ChatGPT 在 ChatGPT 的網頁版和 iOS、Android 上均可使用。ChatGPT 的 Read Aloud 功能支持 37 種語言，提供 5 種聲音。用户還可以選擇讓 ChatGPT 聊天機器人始終以口頭方式迴應問題。去年，OpenAI 已經發布了 ChatGPT 應用程序版本的語音提問和回覆功能。但通過 Read Aloud，用户現在還可以讓生成的文本回答被朗讀出來。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>OpenAI has released the Read Aloud feature for ChatGPT. This feature is available for users of GPT-4 and GPT-3.5. The chatbot is capable of converting text into audio and reading it aloud. The Read Aloud functionality is available on the web version of ChatGPT as well as on iOS and Android platforms. It supports 37 languages and provides a selection of five voices. Users also have the option to have the ChatGPT chatbot respond verbally to their queries consistently. Last year, OpenAI introduced the voice command and response feature for the app version of ChatGPT. However, with Read Aloud, users can now have the generated text responses read out loud.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142004.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142004.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
