<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 19:00:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google 播客将关闭，提醒用户迁移数据</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;软餐收到了 Google 邮件通知，该公司再次提醒即将停止 Google 播客服务，并建议用户将已订阅的播客迁至 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music 或下载到本地。&lt;/strong&gt;Google 在邮件中写道：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;谨在此提醒您，2024 年 4 月 2 日之后，您无法再在 Google 播客中收听播客了。在 2024 年 7 月 29 日之前，您仍然可以将订阅的播客节目迁移到 YouTube&amp;nbsp;Music，或者将订阅的节目下载到本地，然后上传到支持导入该文件的应用中。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;若要使用迁移和导出工具，您需要使用最新版本的 Google 搜索和 Google 播客应用，并拥有&lt;a href=&quot;https://notifications.google.com/g/p/ANiao5oBIBrIhJBFxKM1oW6L2Q0YoUTl-evLUjbi8w32zGHJlk7nwCmxT-k-BEwVFUR3blInqRvUQY15ss4h9Ev9-gHt4Nr8iJs6dxfn0Mg8iSbP7N7Ty1HPTzygHlnb1Q0ywCNyAt_Cr7LEiC-HGbbUQYSVBT0J9yHtEmSUHO5hJeetLWwA3ULq94nPgQJKaYo-J1nvrSgdMs9ammPvrXDYBwZXVxIqmOBHUfVX9Qg3H5cumJ_FMLhWXJM7ynXShC5NyvU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;有效的账号类型&lt;/a&gt;。如果您使用的是不受支持的应用版本，那么只能针对网页版 Google 播客使用迁移和导出工具。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google 于去年 9 月&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/137956.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;宣布&lt;/a&gt;将关闭播客应用程序 Google Podcasts，播客功能将由 YouTube Music 承接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have received a notification email from Google informing us once again that they will be discontinuing the Google Podcasts service. They advised users to migrate their subscribed podcasts to YouTube Music or download them locally. In the email, Google stated:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to remind you that starting from April 2, 2024, you will no longer be able to listen to podcasts on Google Podcasts. Until July 29, 2024, you can still migrate your subscribed podcast programs to YouTube Music or download the subscribed episodes locally and then upload them to an app that supports importing such files.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To use the migration and export tools, you will need to have the latest versions of Google Search and Google Podcasts applications and have a valid account type. If you are using an unsupported app version, you can only use the migration and export tools for the web version of Google Podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google announced in September of last year that they would be shutting down the Google Podcasts application, and the podcast functionality would be taken over by YouTube Music.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142559.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 17:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>3 月安全更新能让 Windows Server 崩溃</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微软表示，在安装了 2024 年 3 月的安全更新 (KB5035857) 后，会导致 Windows Server 出现死机问题。&lt;/strong&gt;由于这个内存问题，服务器会意外重启或卡住。该 bug 存在于所有现代版本的软件中。受影响的版本包括 Windows Server 2012 R2、2016、2019 和 2022。微软表示正在努力修复这个问题。上周，在安装更新后，一些系统管理员在线投诉服务器操作系统出现问题。微软介绍，如果在域控制器上安装了 Windows Server，并且同时使用本地安全性子系统服务（Local Security Authority Subsystem Service）或 Lsass 和基于云的 Active Directory 的本地域控制器通过 Kerberos 进行身份验证请求，可能会发生内存泄漏。由于 「极端的内存泄漏」，Lsass 可能会崩溃。微软表示，这会导致域控制器重新启动，尽管许多管理员报告称域控制器也会卡住。&lt;strong&gt;微软表示已经找到了主要原因，但对此并未提供更多细节。公司写道：「我们正在研究解决方案，并将在未来几天内提供。」&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has stated that installing the security update (KB5035857) for March 2024 can cause Windows Server to experience freezing issues. Due to this memory problem, servers may unexpectedly restart or become stuck. This bug exists in all modern versions of the software. The affected versions include Windows Server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019, and 2022. Microsoft is actively working to fix this problem. Last week, after installing the update, some system administrators complained online about issues with the server operating system. Microsoft explains that if Windows Server is installed on a domain controller and both the Local Security Authority Subsystem Service (Lsass) and cloud-based Active Directory are used for Kerberos authentication requests, a memory leak may occur. Due to an 「extreme memory leak,」 Lsass may crash. Microsoft states that this leads to the domain controller restarting, although many administrators have reported that the domain controllers also become stuck. Microsoft claims to have identified the primary cause but has not provided further details. The company writes, 「We are investigating a solution and will provide it in the coming days.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142546.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 16:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>被广泛批评后，Meta 希望将「去广告」服务价格减半</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，Meta 的一位高管周二表示，&lt;strong&gt;该公司提出将 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月订阅费从 9.99 欧元减半至 5.99 欧元，以消除欧盟监管监管机构的担忧。&lt;/strong&gt;此次降价是在隐私活动人士和消费者团体对 Meta 在欧盟的无广告订阅服务提出批评之后进行的，批评者称该服务要求用户付费以确保其隐私。现在，欧盟的隐私保护活动人士并不认可降价方案，他们认为这与价格无关，即使降价到 1.99 欧元或更低，也会导致用户选择 「同意」，即接受在访问 Meta 服务的同时浏览广告。上周，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;39 名欧盟议员发出公开信，希望 Meta 停止提供该付费去广告模式&lt;/a&gt;。Meta 于 11 月推出了付费去广告订阅计划，以遵守《数字市场法案》(DMA)，该法案限制了其在未经用户同意的情况下为用户提供个性化广告的能力，从而损害了其主要收入来源。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>7-Zip 已支持解压缩.zst 格式文件</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;开源解压缩软件 7-Zip 已增加了对 ZSTD 或 Zstandard 数据压缩算法的支持，7-Zip 现在可以解压缩.zst 文件，以及使用 ZSTD 压缩方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存档。&lt;/strong&gt;这项支持最早在 1 月底发布的 beta 版 24.01 中推出。7-Zip 声称它没有使用 Facebook 的原始 Zstandard (ZSTD) 代码。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows 11 此前已支持 Zst 和 Tzst 格式，它基于开源的 libarchive 项目实现了该功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;7-Zip 24.01 的更新日志：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包 ZSTD 存档（.zst 文件扩展名）。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包使用 ZSTD 压缩方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存档。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在支持在 ZSTD 中使用的快速哈希算法 XXH64。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包由新版 WinRAR 7.00 创建的使用大于 4 GB 字典的 RAR 存档。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包使用 XZ（ULMO/LZMA）压缩方法的 DMG 存档。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包具有大于 64 KB 簇大小的 NTFS 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 现在可以解包具有 4 KB 扇区的 MBR 和 GDP 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;存档解包的速度优化：rar、cab、wim、zip、gz。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;哈希计算的速度优化：CRC-32、CRC-64、Blake2sp。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修复了一个错误：Linux 上的 7-Zip 在某些情况下无法创建多卷。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修复了一些错误。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 10:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>系统工具</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Win11 更新致 ASUS ROG Ally 性能下降</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2024 年 3 月的&lt;/strong&gt; Windows 11 &lt;strong&gt;「星期二补丁日」&lt;/strong&gt;更新，即 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142254.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;KB5035853&lt;/a&gt; 可能会导致 ASUS ROG Ally 性能下降。&lt;/strong&gt;该手持游戏机的用户报告了性能下降问题，同时似乎也会影响其他 AMD 硬件。反馈显示，ASUS ROG Ally 和 AMD 笔记本电脑都出现了卡顿现象，数据显示游戏以每秒 60 帧的速度运行，但感觉更像是以每秒 15 帧的速度运行，无论是在新游戏如《博德之门 3》还是在旧游戏如《毁灭战士 II》都会出现该问题。Windows Latest 报道称，通过关闭游戏中的叠加窗口并重新启动设备，有可能解决 ASUS ROG Ally 的性能问题。另外，卸载 KB5035853 更新也能解决该问题。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Windows 11 「Patch Tuesday」 update for March 2024, known as KB5035853, may cause performance issues on the ASUS ROG Ally. Users of the handheld gaming console have reported experiencing performance drops, which seem to affect other AMD hardware as well. Feedback indicates that both the ASUS ROG Ally and AMD laptops exhibit stuttering. While the games are reported to run at 60 frames per second, users perceive a framerate closer to 15 frames per second. This issue occurs in both newer games like Baldur’s Gate 3 and older games like DOOM II. Windows Latest suggests that disabling the in-game overlay and restarting the device may potentially resolve the performance issues on the ASUS ROG Ally. Additionally, uninstalling the KB5035853 update can also address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142472.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142472.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 10:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>