<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:15:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Win11 新功能：将安卓手机作为无线网络摄像头]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006495256.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐获悉，<strong>在最新的 Windows 11 预览版中，Windows 11 insider 内测用户现在可将 Android 设备用作无线网络摄像头。</strong>用户能够同时使用前置摄像头和后置摄像头作为网络摄像头。在通话过程中，可以切换摄像头或暂停画面，在某些设备上还可以启用 HDR。用户需要下载 Android 应用程序 「Link to Windows」（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.appmanager&amp;pli=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>）并至少运行 Android 9 才能使用该功能。用户可以通过 Windows 的 「移动设备设置」 来配置网络摄像头。微软表示，网络摄像头功能适用于 Windows 11 的所有内测渠道的测试版本。尚不清楚何时正式可用。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the latest preview version of Windows 11, Windows 11 Insider testers can now use their Android devices as wireless webcams. Users are able to utilize both the front and rear cameras as webcams. During video calls, they can switch between cameras or pause the video. HDR functionality is also available on certain devices. To use this feature, users need to download the 「Link to Windows」 Android application (available on Google Play) and have at least Android 9 installed. Users can configure the webcam through the 「Mobile Device Settings」 in Windows. Microsoft states that the webcam feature is available for testing across all Insider channels of Windows 11, but it is unclear when it will be officially released.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:37:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141985.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141985.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[GitHub 为所有用户默认启用机密信息扫描]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2005032766.jpeg.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐获悉，<strong>GitHub 将为所有用户默认启用对机密信息的扫描功能。</strong>GitHub 将自动为所有公共代码库启用 「推送保护」 功能，这样可以在推送前对代码库进行扫描，以检查是否存在 「机密信息」 或 API 密钥。GitHub 表示，他们将默认为所有用户（包括没有付费订阅的用户）启用该功能。如果用户向包含机密信息的代码库进行 「git push」，则该推送将被阻止。除了机密信息外，该功能还可以检查密码或 API 密钥等内容。</p><p>「机密信息扫描」 功能在 GitHub 上已经存在两年了。该公司在两年前开始进行试点测试，去年将其扩展到了所有的公共代码库。现在，GitHub 不仅将该功能作为选项提供，而且将其默认启用，适用于所有的代码库和所有的用户，无论他们是否拥有 Advanced Security 等付费订阅。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>GitHub will enable the scanning feature for sensitive information by default for all users. GitHub will automatically enable 「push protection」 for all public repositories, allowing pre-push scans to check for the presence of 「secrets」 or API keys.GitHub states that they will now enable this feature by default for all users, including those without a paid subscription. If a user performs a 「git push」 to a repository that contains a secret, the push will be blocked. This feature can also detect passwords or API keys, among other sensitive information.</p><p>The 「secret scanning」 feature has been available on GitHub for two years. The company started a pilot program two years ago and expanded it to all public repositories last year. Now, GitHub not only offers this feature as an option but also enables it by default for all repositories and all users, regardless of whether they have a paid subscription like Advanced Security or not.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:29:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141981.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141981.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微软 AI 助理将支持繁体中文等 17 种新语言]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软的人工智能助理 Microsoft Copilot 将在本月或 4 月开始支持 17 种新语言。其中包括荷兰语、阿拉伯语、繁体中文、希伯来语和俄语等主要语言。具体的发布时间尚未敲定。</strong>Copilot 此前已支持英语、西班牙语、日语、法语、德语、葡萄牙语（BR）、意大利语和简体中文。Microsoft Copilot 还将为教育领域提供支持，包括将推出一项工具，允许用户共享提示词并观看培训视频；微软打算 Copilot Lab 改造为一个知识中心，用户可以在其中共享提示词、交流 Copilot 使用技巧；Copilot 将在 Microsoft 365 移动应用程序和 Word、PowerPoint 应用程序中提供支持；此外，微软还将在 Forms 中添加 Copilot 集成。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p><span style="font-size: revert; color: var(--pdl-fg-base); white-space: normal;">Microsoft’s artificial intelligence assistant, Microsoft Copilot, will begin supporting 17 new languages starting this month or in April. These languages include Dutch, Arabic, Traditional Chinese, Hebrew, and Russian, among others. The specific release dates have not been finalized. Previously, Copilot supported English, Spanish, Japanese, French, German, Portuguese (Brazil), Italian, and Simplified Chinese. Microsoft Copilot will also provide support for the education sector, including the introduction of a tool that allows users to share prompts and watch training videos. Microsoft plans to transform Copilot Lab into a knowledge center where users can share prompts and exchange tips on how to make better use of the assistant. Copilot will be available in Microsoft 365 mobile applications, as well as Word and PowerPoint applications. Additionally, Microsoft will integrate Copilot into Forms.</span></p><div class="ChatMessage_chatMessage__xkgHx" data-complete="true" style="font-family: -apple-system, system-ui, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; white-space: normal;"><div class="ChatMessage_messageRow__DHlnq" style="display: flex; align-items: center;"><div class="ChatMessage_messageWrapper__4Ugd6" style="display: flex; flex: 1 1 0%; min-width: 0px; align-items: center;"><div class="Message_rowWithFooter__FShU6" style="min-width: 0px;"><div class="Message_botOptimisticFooter__FL0c_"></div></div></div></div></div><section class="ChatMessageActionBar_actionBar__gyeEs" style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; gap: var(--pdl-spacing-x-sm); font-family: -apple-system, system-ui, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif; white-space: normal;"></section><div><span style="font-size: revert; color: var(--pdl-fg-base); white-space: normal;"></span></div><p></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:14:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141974.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141974.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[谷歌确实在开发 Android 14 衞星求救功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>谷歌可能正在开发在 Android 设备上<strong>通过衞星</strong>发送紧急信号的选项。</strong>科技频道 Google News 在 Android 14 的 Adaptive Connectivity Services 应用程序的更新中发现了这个功能。在版本 p.2024.08 中，包含 「Satellite SOS」 的引用。这意味着当用户处于移动网络或 Wi-Fi 网络的范围之外时，应该可以通过衞星连接发送紧急信号。尚不清楚这个功能是仅适用于 Pixel 手机。此前有报道指出，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/111028.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Android 14 将支持衞星通信</a>。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google may be developing an option to send emergency signals via satellite on Android devices. The technology channel Google News discovered this feature in an update of the Adaptive Connectivity Services application for Android 14. References to 「Satellite SOS」 were found in version p.2024.08. This suggests that it should be possible to send emergency signals through a satellite connection when users are out of range of mobile or Wi-Fi networks. It is not yet clear if this feature will be exclusive to Pixel phones. Previous reports indicated that Android 14 would support satellite communication.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:47:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141967.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141967.html</link>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[密码管理器 Proton Pass 发布了 Windows 版本]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006495252.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐获悉，<strong>密码管理器 Proton Pass 终于发布了适用于 Windows 系统的应用程序。</strong>Proton <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/133621.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">于去年推出</a>了 Proton Pass 密码管理服务，但以前仅提供了浏览器扩展和手机客户端。最新发布的 Windows 客户端包括存储用于双因素身份验证的 totp 代码和创建电子邮件别名的功能。密码管理器可以离线使用，但只适用于拥有付费 Proton 订阅的用户。该公司称，适用于 macOS 和 Linux 的应用程序也将 「很快」 推出。与所有 Proton 软件包一样，Proton Pass 的源代码是开源的。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Proton Pass, the password manager, has finally released its application for Windows systems. Proton introduced the Proton Pass password management service last year, but previously only offered it as a browser extension and mobile client. The newly released Windows client includes features such as storing TOTP codes for two-factor authentication and creating email aliases. The password manager can be used offline, but only for users with a paid Proton subscription. The company stated that applications for macOS and Linux will also be released 「soon.」 Like all Proton packages, the source code for Proton Pass is open source.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:27:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141953.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141953.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
