<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 17:59:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[德国公司将上线 iOS 第三方应用商店 App Marketplace]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>德国数字服务提供商 Mobivention 宣布，将于 3 月 7 日在欧盟推出名为 App Marketplace 的 iOS 第三方应用商店。</strong>这也是欧盟数字市场法案（DMA）正式生效的前一天。本周晚些时候，苹果将发布 iOS 17.4。应 DMA 的要求，此更新将使欧盟用户能够在 App Store 之外下载 iOS 应用程序。Mobivention 将成为欧盟首家提供此类替代应用商店的公司。该公司称，App Marketplace 具有 「简化的规则、替代计费模式、较低的应用内购买收入份额以及集成替代支付解决方案的可能性」。该公司补充说，他们直接与苹果合作，以确保遵守苹果的指导方针。除了 Mobivention，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141917.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MacPaw</a> 和 Epic Games 也在开发适用于欧洲市场的自有应用商店。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>German digital service provider Mobivention has announced the launch of an alternative iOS third-party app store called App Marketplace in the European Union on March 7th. This comes a day before the official enforcement of the Digital Markets Act (DMA). Later this week, Apple will release iOS 17.4, which, in compliance with the DMA, will allow EU users to download iOS applications from sources other than the App Store. Mobivention will be the first company in the EU to offer such an alternative app store. According to the company, the App Marketplace will feature 「simplified rules, alternative billing models, a lower revenue share for in-app purchases, and the possibility to integrate alternative payment solutions.」 They also stated that they have collaborated directly with Apple to ensure compliance with the company’s guidelines. In addition to Mobivention, MacPaw and Epic Games are also developing their own app stores for the European market.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:33:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142007.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[ChatGPT 推出「大声朗读」功能，将文本回答转为语音]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>OpenAI 发布了 ChatGPT 的 Read Aloud（<strong>大声朗读</strong>）功能。</strong>该功能适用于 GPT-4 和 GPT-3.5 用户。聊天机器人可以将文本转化为音频并读出内容。该功能在 ChatGPT 在 ChatGPT 的网页版和 iOS、Android 上均可使用。ChatGPT 的 Read Aloud 功能支持 37 种语言，提供 5 种声音。用户还可以选择让 ChatGPT 聊天机器人始终以口头方式回应问题。去年，OpenAI 已经发布了 ChatGPT 应用程序版本的语音提问和回复功能。但通过 Read Aloud，用户现在还可以让生成的文本回答被朗读出来。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>OpenAI has released the Read Aloud feature for ChatGPT. This feature is available for users of GPT-4 and GPT-3.5. The chatbot is capable of converting text into audio and reading it aloud. The Read Aloud functionality is available on the web version of ChatGPT as well as on iOS and Android platforms. It supports 37 languages and provides a selection of five voices. Users also have the option to have the ChatGPT chatbot respond verbally to their queries consistently. Last year, OpenAI introduced the voice command and response feature for the app version of ChatGPT. However, with Read Aloud, users can now have the generated text responses read out loud.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 14:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142004.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142004.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Spotify 等 34 家公司致信欧盟控诉苹果 App Store 政策]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>Spotify 和 Epic Games 等公司联合向欧盟委员会发信，公开批评苹果的 App Store 政策。</strong>在这封信中，共有 34 家应用开发者表达了他们对苹果新的 App Store 政策的担忧。其他签署这封信的公司还包括 Proton、Mustang、音乐流媒体服务 Deezer 和 Blockchain.com 等。他们认为苹果的政策不符合欧盟数字市场法规（Digital Markets Act，DMA）。例如，如果 iOS 应用程序的下载量超过一百万次，开发者需要支付每次安装 50 美分的费用。信中指出，这种费用的设定是 「旨在维持甚至加强苹果对应用用户的主导地位的剥削」。这些公司还声称，根据 DMA 的规定，苹果被要求允许侧载（sideloading），但实际情况并非如此。在新的条件下，安装和使用替代应用商店对开发者来说是 「困难、有风险且在财务上不具吸引力」。这 34 家公司称欧盟委员会对苹果提案的回应是 DMA 的 「试金石」。他们敦促欧盟对其政策迅速采取行动。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Spotify, Epic Games, and other companies have jointly written a letter to the European Commission, publicly criticizing Apple’s App Store policies. In this letter, a total of 34 app developers expressed their concerns regarding Apple’s new App Store policies. Other companies that have signed the letter include Proton, Mustang, music streaming service Deezer, and Blockchain.com, among others. They believe that Apple’s policies do not comply with the European Union’s Digital Markets Act (DMA). For instance, if an iOS app exceeds one million downloads, developers are required to pay a fee of 50 cents per installation. The letter states that this fee structure is 「designed to maintain and even strengthen Apple’s exploitation of its dominance over app users.」 The companies also claim that the DMA mandates Apple to allow sideloading, but under the new rules, this is not truly the case. In the new conditions, installing and using alternative app stores is 「difficult, risky, and financially unattractive for developers.」 These 34 companies consider the European Commission’s response to Apple’s proposal as the 「litmus test」 for the DMA and urge the European Union to take prompt action concerning Apple’s policies.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 06:10:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141999.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141999.html</link>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Google Drive 网盘加载视频更快了]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>谷歌为网盘服务 Google Drive 带来了一些更新。</strong></p><ul><li><strong>新的转码技术加快了视频加载速度。</strong>所有在 Google Drive 上传的新视频都将使用动态自适应流媒体传输（Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP）。这是一种转码技术，根据用户的互联网连接自动调整比特率。因此，视频的质量可能会高于或低于以前，取决于互联网网络的质量。谷歌表示，这样可以加快视频的开始播放速度，并减少中途缓冲的时间。</li><li><strong>改进了 Google Drive 移动客户端的搜索功能。</strong>现在可以更轻松对文件类型、修改时间、人物等进行搜索筛选。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google has introduced some updates to its cloud storage service, Google Drive.</p><ul><li>The new transcoding technology has accelerated video loading speed. All new videos uploaded to Google Drive will now use Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH), which is a transcoding technique that automatically adjusts the bitrate based on the user’s internet connection. As a result, the video quality may be higher or lower than before, depending on the quality of the internet network. Google states that this enables faster video playback initiation and reduces buffering during playback.</li><li>The search functionality in the Google Drive mobile client has been improved. Users can now easily search and filter by file type, modification time, and people.</li></ul>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 06:00:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141995.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141995.html</link>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Linux 市场份额首次达到 4%]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong>Statcounter 的数据显示，Linux 桌面操作系统的市场份额首次达到了 4%。</strong>去年这一数字刚突破 3%。截至 2024 年 2 月，Linux 在桌面操作系统市场上的份额达到了 4.03%，这是该操作系统有史以来的最高份额。尚不清楚各个发行版的具体份额。ChromeOS 的份额为 2.27%；MacOS 的市场份额为 15.42%；Windows 的市场份额为 72%。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to Statcounter’s data, the market share of Linux desktop operating systems has reached 4% for the first time. Last year, it had just surpassed 3%. As of February 2024, Linux’s market share in the desktop operating system market reached 4.03%, marking the highest share ever recorded for the operating system. The specific market shares of different distributions are not yet clear. ChromeOS holds a share of 2.27%, while MacOS has a market share of 15.42%. Windows remains the dominant desktop operating system with a market share of 72%.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 05:50:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141989.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141989.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
