<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 10:30:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[下载] 精简版系统 tiny11 2311 发布：基于 Win11 23H2 制作]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，Win11 第三方精简版系统 tiny11 迎来更新，开发者 @NTDEV 现在基于 Windows 11 23H2 制作了新版本 <strong>tiny11 2311</strong>。<strong>tiny11 2311</strong> 包含了 Win11 23H2 的所有新功能，包括 Copilot、RAR 解压缩支持、重新设计的音量滑块、设置应用中的 RGB 控制等。与老版本相比，tiny11 2311 的体积缩小了 20%。并且可以接收微软官方的服务更新。该版本没有预装 Edge 浏览器，删除了 Xbox 相关功能（从微软商店下载游戏后会恢复）。</p><ul><li>读者可从 <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a> 下载 tiny11 2311</li><li>网盘下载：请<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/wxa-6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">点此关注</a>公众号 「软餐」，发送口令&nbsp;<code><strong>139081</strong></code>获取下载链接。</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>[[Download] Simplified version system tiny11 2311 released: Based on Win11 23H2 production] The third-party lightweight version of Win11, tiny11, has received an update. Developer @NTDEV has now created a new version, tiny11 2311, based on Windows 11 23H2. Tiny11 2311 includes all the new features of Win11 23H2, including Copilot, RAR decompression support, redesigned volume slider, and RGB control in the Settings app. Compared to the previous version, tiny11 2311 has reduced its size by 20%. It can also receive official service updates from Microsoft. This version does not come pre-installed with Edge browser and removes Xbox-related functions (which will be restored after downloading games from the Microsoft Store).</p><p>Readers can download tiny11 2311 from <a href="https://archive.org/details/tiny11-2311" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet Archive</a>.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 05:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139081.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[复旦教授肖仰华：我们与 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>复旦大学计算机科学技术学院教授、上海市数据科学重点实验室主任肖仰华推测，ChatGPT 或许使用了大小模型结合的技术，多模型协同可以很大程度上解决成本问题。「让大模型去解决复杂问题，但普通用户一般都是简单的问题，用小模型就可以了。」 他形容，ChatGPT 的 AI 技术已形成一种 「飞轮效应」，迭代和优化正推动技术进入一个自我强化的快速发展阶段行业或将变成 「只有第一，没有第二」 的局面。「我们的文化中，聪明人太多，总想抄近路。有时候就是要坚持，要笨一点，才能做出真正的大杀器。<strong>我们与 OpenAI 的差距正在拉大，不是在缩小。</strong>」 肖教授指出，还有很多如机器人、环境交互技术、医疗大模型、科学大模型等其他方向，都是大趋势。企业可以在这些新领域找到自己的优势。肖仰华指出，AI 技术的进步可能导致人类智力的相对退化。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Recently, Professor Xiaoyanghua, from the School of Computer Science and Technology at Fudan University and Director of the Shanghai Key Laboratory of Data Science, speculated that ChatGPT may have used a combination of large and small models to address cost issues. 「Let the large model solve complex problems, but ordinary users usually have simple questions that can be answered with a small model,」 he described. The AI technology of ChatGPT has formed a 「flywheel effect」, where iteration and optimization are driving the technology into a self-reinforcing rapid development stage. The industry may become a situation where there is only one leader without any competitors. 「In our culture, there are too many smart people who always want shortcuts. Sometimes we need to persist and be a little foolish in order to create truly powerful tools. The gap between us and OpenAI is widening rather than narrowing,」 Professor Xiao pointed out. He also mentioned that there are other emerging trends such as robotics, interactive environmental technologies, large-scale medical models, scientific models, etc., where companies can find their own advantages. Professor Xiaoyanghua indicated that advancements in AI technology could potentially lead to relative decline in human intelligence.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139077.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[诞生 20 周年，文本编辑器 Notepad++8.6 版发布]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，文本编辑器 Notepad++官方发布了最新的 Notepad++ 8.6 版，以纪念该编辑器诞生 20 周年。Notepad++ 8.6 是一个较小的版本，包含多处 Bug 修复、新的多重编辑功能（允许用户在文本文档的多个位置添加或删除字符）、自定义多选背景和护理颜色等。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The official release of the latest version, Notepad++ 8.6, has been announced by the text editor Notepad++, commemorating its 20th anniversary. Notepad++ 8.6 is a minor release that includes several bug fixes, new multiple editing capabilities (allowing users to add or remove characters at multiple positions within a text document), customizable multi-selection backgrounds and caret colors, and more.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:19:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139041.html</link>
            <category>办公/生产力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Chrome 扩展商店迎来全新 UI 改版]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/20231122171854.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐访问谷歌 Chrome 网上应用店看到，谷歌为该商店带来了全面的 UI 更新。谷歌基于 Material You 风格重新设计了页面，并增加了新的扩展分类。搜索栏已被放置在右上角，并新增了更多筛选选项。谷歌表示，由于图标可读性的提升和新的设计，现在浏览 Chrome 网上应用店变得更加容易。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google has brought a comprehensive UI update to the Chrome Web Store. Google has redesigned the pages based on the Material You style and added new extension categories. The search bar has been relocated to the top right corner, and additional filtering options have been introduced. According to Google, browsing the Chrome Web Store has become easier now with improved icon readability and the new design.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:32:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/138951.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/138951.html</link>
            <category>Chrome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[YouTube 否认故意针对 Firefox 降速]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，谷歌否认针对 Firefox 浏览器故意延迟了 YouTube 的加载速度。该公司通过外媒发布声明称：「<em>为了支持全球多元化的创作者生态系统，并让数十亿人在 YouTube 上访问他们喜爱的内容，我们发起了一项活动，敦促启用了广告拦截器的观看者允许在 YouTube 上投放广告，或尝试使用 YouTube Premium 以获得无广告体验。<strong>安装了广告拦截器的用户可能会遇到观看效果不佳的情况，无论他们使用什么浏览器。</strong></em>」</p><p>谷歌的声明确实间接否认了传言，并且指出延迟是因广告拦截扩展引起的。本周早些时候，有 Reddit 用户<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/138878.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">发现</a>，YouTube 似乎置入了导致 Firefox 加载视频延迟的代码。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google denies deliberately delaying YouTube’s loading speed for Firefox. The company said in a statement: 「To support a diverse ecosystem of creators globally and allow billions to access their favorite content on YouTube, we’ve launched an effort to urge viewers with ad blockers enabled to allow ads on YouTube or try YouTube Premium for an ad free experience. Users who have ad blockers installed may experience suboptimal viewing, regardless of the browser they are using.」</p><p>Google’s statement did indirectly deny the rumors and pointed out that the delay was caused by the expansion of ad blocking. Earlier this week, Reddit users noticed that YouTube appeared to have embedded code that caused Firefox to delay loading videos.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 04:38:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/138942.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/138942.html</link>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
