<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 20:32:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[「微软画图」应用全面迎来 AI 作图功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/GABtxPAX0AIpVe7.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软已低调向所有 「微软画图」（Microsoft Paint）用户开放基于 AI 的 Cocreator（共同创作者）功能。</strong>这是一项人工智能生成图像功能，基于 OpenAI 的 DALL-E 3 模型。现在用户无需进行任何申请，即可直接访问该功能。<strong>软餐在我们的测试设备上已经获得该功能。</strong></p><p>用户必须登录微软账户才能使用此功能。用户将自动获得 50 个积分，用于在 Cocreator 中创作图像。目前，Cocreator 仅支持英语，并且目前在美国、法国、英国、澳大利亚、加拿大、意大利和德国可用。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>要使用 Cocreator，请打开 Microsoft Paint，然后选择工具栏上的 Cocreator 图标以查看 Cocreator（共同创作者）侧面板。在文本框中，输入要创建的图像的描述。例如，您可以输入 「一只戴红帽子的蓝猫」 或 「有山和湖的风景」。尽可能具有描述性，以生成符合您期望的结果。</p><p>输入文本后，选择要创建图像的样式，然后选择 「创建」 按钮。 Cocreator 将生成您请求的图像的三种不同变体，您可以单击任何变体以将该图像应用到 Paint 画布并开始创建。</p></blockquote><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has quietly opened up its AI-based Cocreator feature to all Microsoft Paint users. This is an artificial intelligence-generated image creation feature based on OpenAI’s DALL-E 3 model. Users can now access this feature directly without any application process. The software update has already been received on our testing devices.</p><p>Users must log in to their Microsoft accounts in order to use this feature. Upon logging in, users will automatically receive 50 points for creating images in Cocreator. Currently, Cocreator only supports English and is available in the United States, France, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, Italy, and Germany.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>To use Cocreator, open Microsoft Paint and select the Cocreator icon on the toolbar to see the Cocreator side panel. In the text box, enter a description of the image you want to create. For example, you can type 「a blue cat with a red hat」 or 「a landscape with mountains and a lake」. Be as descriptive as possible to generate results matching your expectations.</p><p>After you enter the text, choose a style in which you want to create your image and then select the Create button. Cocreator will generate three different variants of the image you requested, you can click on any of the variants to apply that image to Paint canvas and start creating.</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:11:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139427.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>图形图像</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[图] 微软发布 2023 款「丑毛衣」Windows Ugly Sweater]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/1701176110_bliss_ugly_sweaters_image_story.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，在西方假日季临近之际，微软按照传统推出了 2023 年的 「Windows 丑陋毛衣」(Windows Ugly Sweater)。微软没有停止怀旧，这次在毛衣上印上了经典的 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/131375.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Windows XP 默认的 Bliss 壁纸</a>。过去几年，微软还曾在丑陋毛衣上印制 Windows 95、扫雷游戏、微软画图（MS Paint）和 Clippy（大眼夹/回形针）等形象。消费者可通过 windowsuglysweater.com 网站购买 「丑陋毛衣」，微软将把销售所得的 10 万美元捐给大自然保护协会（The&nbsp;Nature&nbsp;Conservancy）。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>As the Western holiday season approaches, Microsoft has traditionally released the 「Windows Ugly Sweater」 for 2023. Microsoft continues its nostalgia by printing the classic Windows XP default Bliss wallpaper on the sweater. In recent years, Microsoft has also printed Windows 95, Minesweeper game, MS Paint, and Clippy (the paperclip) images on ugly sweaters. Consumers can purchase the 「ugly sweater」 through the website windowsuglysweater.com, and Microsoft will donate $100,000 of sales proceeds to The Nature Conservancy (TNC).</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:52:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139274.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[链接] 三星浏览器 Windows 版发布：非三星电脑也能用]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/693292.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>软餐获悉，三星刚刚向<a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">微软商店</a>上架了适用于 Windows 系统的浏览器 <strong>Samsung Internet</strong>。该浏览器支持 64 位 Windows 10 及以上版本系统，即使不是三星品牌设备也可运行。三星对该浏览器的描述只有一句话：「Samsung Internet 通过各种功能和保护您的隐私，为您提供最佳的网络浏览体验。」 据悉，该浏览器支持部分同步功能，可从安卓版 Samsung Internet 浏览器同步浏览历史记录、书签、保存的页面和打开的标签等数据，但尚不支持同步保存的密码。</p><p>同时，PC 版 Samsung Internet 支持隐身模式、广告拦截器，支持从其他浏览器（包括 Edge 和 Chrome）导入浏览历史记录/书签和搜索引擎。</p><p>三星之前在安卓平台上发布的 Samsung Internet 浏览器拥有众多忠实的粉丝。这将有助于三星获取桌面浏览器的份额。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Samsung has just released the browser Samsung Internet on the <a href="https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/XPDCMJG5PTR3TP" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft Store</a> for Windows systems. This browser supports 64-bit Windows 10 and above, and can be run even on non-Samsung devices. The description of this browser by Samsung is only one sentence: 「Samsung Internet provides you with the best web browsing experience through various features and protecting your privacy.」 It is reported that this browser supports partial synchronization, allowing users to sync browsing history, bookmarks, saved pages, and open tabs from the Android version of Samsung Internet browser. However, syncing saved passwords is not yet supported.</p><p>In addition, the PC version of Samsung Internet supports incognito mode and ad blocker, as well as importing browsing history/bookmarks and search engines from other browsers (including Edge and Chrome).</p><p>Samsung’s previously released Samsung Internet browser on the Android platform has a large number of loyal fans. This will help Samsung gain market share in desktop browsers.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139253.html</link>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[字节跳动打造爆款游戏的计划落空了]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，消息人士称，字节跳动的游戏部门朝夕光年日前大举裁员，其幕后是创始人张一鸣和董事会主席梁汝波等高管不满意其表现。因为该部门一直未能开发出在全球大热的游戏，其游戏产品亦难以留住玩家。字节跳动近年来在游戏上投入了数十亿美元，并收购了热门游戏开发商，但收效甚微。收缩游戏部门是字节跳动精简业务并专注核心业务计划中的一环。本月，字节跳动还裁减了 VR 头戴设备业务 Pico 的团队。</p><p>据悉，字节跳动正转而专注 TikTok、抖音和电商等核心业务领域。最近 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139114.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TikTok 正试图在美国复制直播带货模式</a>，以挑战亚马逊、Temu 和希音 (Shein) 等对手。今年上半年，该公司的收入同比增长约 37%，逾 530 亿美元。字节跳动希望借助调整保持增长势头。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Insiders say that ByteDance’s gaming division recently carried out massive layoffs, driven by dissatisfaction from founder Zhang Yiming and Chairman of the Board Liang Rubo, among other executives. The division has been unable to develop globally popular games and its game products have struggled to retain players. In recent years, ByteDance has invested billions of dollars in gaming and acquired popular game developers, but with little success.</p><p>The contraction of the gaming division is part of ByteDance’s plan to streamline its business and focus on core operations. This month, ByteDance also downsized the team at Pico, a VR headset business. The company will now concentrate on core businesses such as TikTok, Douyin (the Chinese version of TikTok), and e-commerce. Recently, TikTok has been attempting to replicate the live-streaming shopping model in the United States to challenge competitors like Amazon, Temu, and Shein.</p><p>ByteDance hopes to maintain its growth momentum through strategic adjustments. In the first half of this year alone, the company’s revenue increased by approximately 37% compared to last year, surpassing $53 billion USD.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139198.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139198.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Instagram 推送了数量惊人的不雅短视频]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，华尔街日报的一项测试显示，Meta 旗下社交媒体 <strong>Instagram 的 Reels 视频服务向该媒体建立的测试账号推送了数量惊人的不雅内容。</strong>这包括儿童不雅视频和露骨的成人色情视频，以及一些美国大品牌的广告。该媒体还观察到，在青少年网红账户的成千上万名粉丝中，经常包含有大量成年男性，后者也表现出对儿童和成人性内容的兴趣。儿童保护组织加拿大儿童保护中心 (Canadian Centre for Child Protection) 进行的测试也得出了类似的结果。</p><p>Meta 发言人回应称，《华尔街日报》的测试并不代表数十亿用户所看到的内容。对于为什么算法会将显示儿童、性和广告的不同视频编排在一起，该公司不予置评，Instagram 每个月都会对 400 万个涉嫌违反其标准的视频进行删除或限流。</p><p>Instagram Reels 短视频的广告主包括 Match、Bumble、迪士尼、沃尔玛、Hims、必胜客等知名公司，这些公司要么对 Meta 的回应表示不满，要么不予置评。可以肯定的是，这些知名品牌都不希望在不当内容旁投放广告，因为这有损其品牌形象。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>A test conducted by The Wall Street Journal revealed that Meta’s social media platform, Instagram, pushed an alarming amount of explicit content to a test account created by the media outlet. This included inappropriate videos involving children, explicit adult content, as well as advertisements from some major American brands. The media outlet also observed that among the tens of thousands of followers of teenage influencer accounts, there was a significant presence of adult males who displayed an interest in both child and adult sexual content. Similar results were obtained in tests conducted by the Canadian Centre for Child Protection.</p><p>A spokesperson for Meta responded by stating that The Wall Street Journal’s test does not represent the content seen by billions of users. The company refrained from commenting on why the algorithm would group together different videos featuring children, sex, and advertisements. Instagram removes or limits the visibility of around 4 million videos each month that are suspected of violating its standards.</p><p>Prominent companies such as Match, Bumble, Disney, Walmart, Hims, and Pizza Hut advertise on Instagram’s Reels short video feature, and they either expressed dissatisfaction with Meta’s response or refrained from commenting. It is evident that these well-known brands do not want their advertisements to appear alongside inappropriate content as it would harm their brand image.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 09:30:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/139188.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
