<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:15:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[Win11 新功能：將安卓手機作為無線網絡攝像頭]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006495256.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>在最新的 Windows 11 預覽版中，Windows 11 insider 內測用户現在可將 Android 設備用作無線網絡攝像頭。</strong>用户能夠同時使用前置攝像頭和後置攝像頭作為網絡攝像頭。在通話過程中，可以切換攝像頭或暫停畫面，在某些設備上還可以啓用 HDR。用户需要下載 Android 應用程序 「Link to Windows」（<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.appmanager&amp;pli=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Google Play</a>）並至少運行 Android 9 才能使用該功能。用户可以通過 Windows 的 「移動設備設置」 來配置網絡攝像頭。微軟表示，網絡攝像頭功能適用於 Windows 11 的所有內測渠道的測試版本。尚不清楚何時正式可用。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>In the latest preview version of Windows 11, Windows 11 Insider testers can now use their Android devices as wireless webcams. Users are able to utilize both the front and rear cameras as webcams. During video calls, they can switch between cameras or pause the video. HDR functionality is also available on certain devices. To use this feature, users need to download the 「Link to Windows」 Android application (available on Google Play) and have at least Android 9 installed. Users can configure the webcam through the 「Mobile Device Settings」 in Windows. Microsoft states that the webcam feature is available for testing across all Insider channels of Windows 11, but it is unclear when it will be officially released.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:37:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141985.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141985.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[GitHub 為所有用户默認啓用機密信息掃描]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2005032766.jpeg.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>GitHub 將為所有用户默認啓用對機密信息的掃描功能。</strong>GitHub 將自動為所有公共代碼庫啓用 「推送保護」 功能，這樣可以在推送前對代碼庫進行掃描，以檢查是否存在 「機密信息」 或 API 密鑰。GitHub 表示，他們將默認為所有用户（包括沒有付費訂閲的用户）啓用該功能。如果用户向包含機密信息的代碼庫進行 「git push」，則該推送將被阻止。除了機密信息外，該功能還可以檢查密碼或 API 密鑰等內容。</p><p>「機密信息掃描」 功能在 GitHub 上已經存在兩年了。該公司在兩年前開始進行試點測試，去年將其擴展到了所有的公共代碼庫。現在，GitHub 不僅將該功能作為選項提供，而且將其默認啓用，適用於所有的代碼庫和所有的用户，無論他們是否擁有 Advanced Security 等付費訂閲。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>GitHub will enable the scanning feature for sensitive information by default for all users. GitHub will automatically enable 「push protection」 for all public repositories, allowing pre-push scans to check for the presence of 「secrets」 or API keys.GitHub states that they will now enable this feature by default for all users, including those without a paid subscription. If a user performs a 「git push」 to a repository that contains a secret, the push will be blocked. This feature can also detect passwords or API keys, among other sensitive information.</p><p>The 「secret scanning」 feature has been available on GitHub for two years. The company started a pilot program two years ago and expanded it to all public repositories last year. Now, GitHub not only offers this feature as an option but also enables it by default for all repositories and all users, regardless of whether they have a paid subscription like Advanced Security or not.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:29:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141981.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141981.html</link>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[微軟 AI 助理將支持繁體中文等 17 種新語言]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>微軟的人工智能助理 Microsoft Copilot 將在本月或 4 月開始支持 17 種新語言。其中包括荷蘭語、阿拉伯語、繁體中文、希伯來語和俄語等主要語言。具體的發佈時間尚未敲定。</strong>Copilot 此前已支持英語、西班牙語、日語、法語、德語、葡萄牙語（BR）、意大利語和簡體中文。Microsoft Copilot 還將為教育領域提供支持，包括將推出一項工具，允許用户共享提示詞並觀看培訓視頻；微軟打算 Copilot Lab 改造為一個知識中心，用户可以在其中共享提示詞、交流 Copilot 使用技巧；Copilot 將在 Microsoft 365 移動應用程序和 Word、PowerPoint 應用程序中提供支持；此外，微軟還將在 Forms 中添加 Copilot 集成。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p><span style="font-size: revert; color: var(--pdl-fg-base); white-space: normal;">Microsoft’s artificial intelligence assistant, Microsoft Copilot, will begin supporting 17 new languages starting this month or in April. These languages include Dutch, Arabic, Traditional Chinese, Hebrew, and Russian, among others. The specific release dates have not been finalized. Previously, Copilot supported English, Spanish, Japanese, French, German, Portuguese (Brazil), Italian, and Simplified Chinese. Microsoft Copilot will also provide support for the education sector, including the introduction of a tool that allows users to share prompts and watch training videos. Microsoft plans to transform Copilot Lab into a knowledge center where users can share prompts and exchange tips on how to make better use of the assistant. Copilot will be available in Microsoft 365 mobile applications, as well as Word and PowerPoint applications. Additionally, Microsoft will integrate Copilot into Forms.</span></p><div class="ChatMessage_chatMessage__xkgHx" data-complete="true" style="font-family: -apple-system, system-ui, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; white-space: normal;"><div class="ChatMessage_messageRow__DHlnq" style="display: flex; align-items: center;"><div class="ChatMessage_messageWrapper__4Ugd6" style="display: flex; flex: 1 1 0%; min-width: 0px; align-items: center;"><div class="Message_rowWithFooter__FShU6" style="min-width: 0px;"><div class="Message_botOptimisticFooter__FL0c_"></div></div></div></div></div><section class="ChatMessageActionBar_actionBar__gyeEs" style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; gap: var(--pdl-spacing-x-sm); font-family: -apple-system, system-ui, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif; white-space: normal;"></section><div><span style="font-size: revert; color: var(--pdl-fg-base); white-space: normal;"></span></div><p></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:14:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141974.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141974.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[谷歌確實在開發 Android 14 衞星求救功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>谷歌可能正在開發在 Android 設備上<strong>通過衞星</strong>發送緊急信號的選項。</strong>科技頻道 Google News 在 Android 14 的 Adaptive Connectivity Services 應用程序的更新中發現了這個功能。在版本 p.2024.08 中，包含 「Satellite SOS」 的引用。這意味着當用户處於移動網絡或 Wi-Fi 網絡的範圍之外時，應該可以通過衞星連接發送緊急信號。尚不清楚這個功能是僅適用於 Pixel 手機。此前有報道指出，<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/111028.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Android 14 將支持衞星通信</a>。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Google may be developing an option to send emergency signals via satellite on Android devices. The technology channel Google News discovered this feature in an update of the Adaptive Connectivity Services application for Android 14. References to 「Satellite SOS」 were found in version p.2024.08. This suggests that it should be possible to send emergency signals through a satellite connection when users are out of range of mobile or Wi-Fi networks. It is not yet clear if this feature will be exclusive to Pixel phones. Previous reports indicated that Android 14 would support satellite communication.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:47:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141967.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141967.html</link>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[密碼管理器 Proton Pass 發佈了 Windows 版本]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006495252.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure><p>軟餐獲悉，<strong>密碼管理器 Proton Pass 終於發佈了適用於 Windows 系統的應用程序。</strong>Proton <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/133621.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">於去年推出</a>了 Proton Pass 密碼管理服務，但以前僅提供了瀏覽器擴展和手機客户端。最新發布的 Windows 客户端包括存儲用於雙因素身份驗證的 totp 代碼和創建電子郵件別名的功能。密碼管理器可以離線使用，但只適用於擁有付費 Proton 訂閲的用户。該公司稱，適用於 macOS 和 Linux 的應用程序也將 「很快」 推出。與所有 Proton 軟件包一樣，Proton Pass 的源代碼是開源的。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Proton Pass, the password manager, has finally released its application for Windows systems. Proton introduced the Proton Pass password management service last year, but previously only offered it as a browser extension and mobile client. The newly released Windows client includes features such as storing TOTP codes for two-factor authentication and creating email aliases. The password manager can be used offline, but only for users with a paid Proton subscription. The company stated that applications for macOS and Linux will also be released 「soon.」 Like all Proton packages, the source code for Proton Pass is open source.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 09:27:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141953.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141953.html</link>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
