<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:43:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[部分 Win11 用户无法安装 2 月安全更新，微软回应]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>微软确认部分用户在安装 Windows 11 22H2 和 23H2 的最新安全更新 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141565.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KB5034765</a> 时可能遇到安装失败问题。</strong>用户可能看到 「我们无法安装此更新，但您可以重试（0x800f0922）」 提示。微软称，对于受影响的用户，卸载（即删除）隐藏文件夹 C：\$WinREAgent 应该可以解决问题并强制安装更新。删除该文件夹后，重新启动系统，然后即可再次尝试下载安装 KB5034765。微软同时正在努力修复该问题。</p><p>几天前，微软还修复了 Windows 11 中的另一个错误，该错误阻止应用程序使用 WVC1 编解码器录制、播放或捕获视频。修复该 bug 需要安装 2024 年 1 月可选非安全更新 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141336.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KB5034204</a> 或 2 月安全更新 <a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/141565.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KB5034765</a>。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Microsoft has confirmed that some users may encounter installation failure issues when installing the latest security updates KB5034765 for Windows 11 22H2 and 23H2. Users may see the error message 「We couldn’t install this update, but you can try again (0x800f0922).」 Microsoft suggests that affected users can resolve the issue and force the update to install by uninstalling (or deleting) the hidden folder C:$WinREAgent. After deleting this folder, restart the system and then attempt to download and install KB5034765 again. Microsoft is actively working on fixing this problem.</p><p>A few days ago, Microsoft also fixed another issue in Windows 11 that prevented applications from using the WVC1 codec for recording, playing, or capturing videos. To fix this bug, users need to install the optional non-security update KB5034204 from January 2024 or the security update KB5034765 from February.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 10:54:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141892.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141892.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[美日等国发声支持 6G，引发中国电信设备制造商股价大涨]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>据华尔街日报，<strong>在美国、日本和英国等国发表了一份声明支持全球 6G 网络发展的原则后，中兴通讯和其他中国电信设备制造商的股票大幅上涨。</strong>中兴通讯周二上涨 10%，触及单日涨幅上限，其香港股票周二收盘上涨 11%。集成电路板制造商明阳电路 (Sunshine Global Circuits) 和电连接器制造商陕西华达 (Shaanxi Huada Science Technology) 的股价分别上涨了 20%，深南电路 (Shennan Circuits) 上涨了 10%。不久前，美国和其他九个国家发表了一份联合声明，敦促在全球 6G 网络的发展中支持国家安全、隐私和其他原则。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>After a joint statement supporting the principles for the development of global 6G networks was released in countries such as the United States, Japan, and the United Kingdom, stocks of ZTE Corporation and other Chinese telecom equipment manufacturers saw a significant increase. ZTE Corporation rose by 10% on Tuesday, hitting the daily limit for gains, and its Hong Kong stock closed with an 11% increase on the same day. Integrated circuit board manufacturer Sunshine Global Circuits and electrical connector manufacturer Shaanxi Huada Science Technology saw their stock prices rise by 20% each, while Shennan Circuits rose by 10%. Recently, the United States and nine other countries issued a joint statement urging support for national security, privacy, and other principles in the development of global 6G networks.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 14:14:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141868.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141868.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[「贵州女企业家讨债被抓」之际，贵州迅速召开高规格会议]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/760423030_120388781" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">贵州六盘水市女企业家因讨工程款被抓</a>消息在互联网上发酵之际，贵州迅速做出反应和行动。</strong>据极目新闻，2 月 27 日，贵州召开全省民营经济高质量发展暨营商环境建设大会。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>各地各部门要以营商环境大改善促进民营经济大发展，深入实施营商环境大改善三年行动，大力整治营商环境突出问题，真正落实 「一视同仁、平等对待」 要求，<strong>严格兑现政府承诺，全面清理拖欠企业账款</strong>，切实降低民营企业生产经营成本，当好服务企业的 「店小二」，不断提升民营企业获得感。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 14:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141862.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141862.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[莫言被起诉抹黑英雄先烈？胡锡进都看不下去了]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>据<a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/760495918_120094090" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">顶端新闻</a>，一向被外界冠之以 「喉舌」 的胡锡进发文称，有人向法院起诉作家莫言，指控其在作品中 「涉嫌抹黑英雄先烈」「涉嫌美化侵华日军」，并且将此事拿到网上炒作，获约万人投票支持。<strong>胡锡进称，这件事就是一场个别人用 「打莫言」 自我炒作的闹剧。发布者打出 「爱国」「正能量」 的旗号，抓一个又一个可以找茬批斗的人与事情，逐渐形成了一种破坏社会和谐与多元的戾气。</strong></p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>如今互联网上激进的东西不少，发出者为了自我安全，打出 「爱国」「正能量」 的旗号，在我们社会丰富多彩的现实中不断扫描，抓一个又一个可以找茬批斗的人与事情，「宰活鱼」，逐渐形成了一种破坏社会和谐与多元的戾气。像莫言的这个起诉者，完全是在扣帽子，断章取义，他这么干虽然一时伤害不了莫言，但这件事在又一次打开互联网上恶意构陷的边界和想象空间。一些人会认为，只要举起 「政治正确」 的旗号，干啥都没问题，他们也因此成了 「宁左勿右」 的网上示范者。</p></blockquote>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:05:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141835.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141835.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[SpaceX 或已暂停台湾衞星互联网服务]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>本站对所刊之内容保持中立，不持任何立场。</p></div></div></div><p>有消息人士称，马斯克拥有的 SpaceX 可能已经暂停了在台湾提供的衞星宽带互联网服务。多个消息来源称，通过 SpaceX 旗下星盾 (Starshield) 部门提供的衞星宽带在台湾地区及附近处于非活动状态。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>According to sources, SpaceX, owned by Elon Musk, has reportedly suspended satellite broadband internet services provided in Taiwan. Multiple sources indicate that the satellite broadband service offered through SpaceX’s subsidiary, Starshield, is currently inactive in Taiwan and its surrounding areas.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 14:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/141817.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/141817.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
