<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 12:30:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>被廣泛批評後，Meta 希望將「去廣告」服務價格減半</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，Meta 的一位高管週二表示，&lt;strong&gt;該公司提出將 Facebook 和 Instagram 的每月訂閲費從 9.99 歐元減半至 5.99 歐元，以消除歐盟監管監管機構的擔憂。&lt;/strong&gt;此次降價是在隱私活動人士和消費者團體對 Meta 在歐盟的無廣告訂閲服務提出批評之後進行的，批評者稱該服務要求用戶付費以確保其隱私。現在，歐盟的隱私保護活動人士並不認可降價方案，他們認為這與價格無關，即使降價到 1.99 歐元或更低，也會導致用戶選擇 「同意」，即接受在訪問 Meta 服務的同時瀏覽廣告。上週，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142410.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;39 名歐盟議員發出公開信，希望 Meta 停止提供該付費去廣告模式&lt;/a&gt;。Meta 於 11 月推出了付費去廣告訂閲計劃，以遵守《數字市場法案》(DMA)，該法案限制了其在未經用戶同意的情況下為用戶提供個性化廣告的能力，從而損害了其主要收入來源。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A senior executive at Meta announced on Tuesday that the company is proposing to reduce the monthly subscription fees for Facebook and Instagram from €9.99 to €5.99, in an effort to address concerns from European Union regulatory authorities. This price reduction comes after privacy activists and consumer groups criticized Meta’s ad-free subscription service in the EU, arguing that it requires users to pay to safeguard their privacy. However, privacy advocates in the EU are not endorsing the pricing scheme, as they believe it is unrelated. Even if the price were reduced to €1.99 or lower, they argue that it would still result in users opting to 「agree,」 thereby accepting the browsing of ads while accessing Meta services. Last week, 39 EU lawmakers sent an open letter urging Meta to discontinue the paid ad-free model. Meta introduced the paid ad-free subscription plan in November to comply with the Digital Markets Act (DMA), which restricts its ability to provide personalized ads to users without their consent, impacting its primary revenue source.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142486.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>7-Zip 已支持解壓縮.zst 格式文件</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;開源解壓縮軟件 7-Zip 已增加了對 ZSTD 或 Zstandard 數據壓縮算法的支持，7-Zip 現在可以解壓縮.zst 文件，以及使用 ZSTD 壓縮方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存檔。&lt;/strong&gt;這項支持最早在 1 月底發佈的 beta 版 24.01 中推出。7-Zip 聲稱它沒有使用 Facebook 的原始 Zstandard (ZSTD) 代碼。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows 11 此前已支持 Zst 和 Tzst 格式，它基於開源的 libarchive 項目實現了該功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;7-Zip 24.01 的更新日誌：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包 ZSTD 存檔（.zst 文件擴展名）。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包使用 ZSTD 壓縮方法的 ZIP、SquashFS 和 RPM 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在支持在 ZSTD 中使用的快速哈希算法 XXH64。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包由新版 WinRAR 7.00 創建的使用大於 4 GB 字典的 RAR 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包使用 XZ（ULMO/LZMA）壓縮方法的 DMG 存檔。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包具有大於 64 KB 簇大小的 NTFS 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;7-Zip 現在可以解包具有 4 KB 扇區的 MBR 和 GDP 映像。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;存檔解包的速度優化：rar、cab、wim、zip、gz。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;哈希計算的速度優化：CRC-32、CRC-64、Blake2sp。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修復了一個錯誤：Linux 上的 7-Zip 在某些情況下無法創建多卷。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;修復了一些錯誤。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142477.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 10:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>系統工具</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mozilla 推出個人興趣分享應用 Didthis</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006571970.webp&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla 推出了新的應用程序 Didthis，這是一款用於追蹤和與感興趣的人分享個人興趣項目進展的應用和服務。&lt;/strong&gt;Mozilla 稱該服務目前只是一個實驗，仍處於測試階段。Didthis 提供網站（&lt;a href=&quot;https://didthis.app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;官網&lt;/a&gt;）和 iOS 應用，未來還將推出 Android 版本。用戶可以上傳照片、視頻和文字，並將它們組織到不同的個人興趣項目中，這些內容默認為私密，未來計劃添加社區功能。用戶可以與其他用戶或聯繫人共享自己的項目。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has launched a new application called Didthis, which is designed to track and share the progress of personal hobby projects with like-minded individuals. Mozilla describes this service as an experimental project that is currently in the testing phase. Didthis is available as a website and an iOS app, with plans to release an Android version in the future. Users can upload photos, videos, and text, organizing them into various personal interest projects. By default, these contents are kept private, but there are plans to incorporate community features in the future. Users have the option to share their projects with other users or contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142465.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142465.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 16:04:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>iPhone 借力谷歌 Gemini，暗示蘋果 AI 研發緩慢</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;我們稍早前&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142426.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;報道&lt;/a&gt;，蘋果正與 Google 討論向新款 iPhone 植入後者的 Gemini 人工智能引擎。這無疑對 iPhone 和 Gemini AI 模型都是雙贏的局面。但華爾街日報評論説，這 「&lt;strong&gt;同時也可能意味着，蘋果公司開發自身 AI 能力的進展可能比投資者希望的要慢。&lt;/strong&gt;」&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we reported that Apple is in discussions with Google regarding the integration of Google’s Gemini artificial intelligence engine into the new iPhone. This undoubtedly presents a win-win situation for both the iPhone and the Gemini AI model. However, The Wall Street Journal comments, 「It may also imply that Apple’s progress in developing its own AI capabilities could be slower than what investors had hoped for.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142454.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:45:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pixel Launcher 已允許歐盟用戶切換搜索引擎</title>
            <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/2006567768.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;Pixel Launcher 的新版本已允許歐盟用戶選擇其他搜索引擎。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌此舉是為了遵守歐盟數字市場法規（DMA）。在此之前，用戶在 Pixel 手機上無法選擇除 Google 以外的其他搜索引擎，主屏上的 Google 搜索欄小部件無法關閉。而在新版本中，用戶可將 Google 搜索欄替換為其競爭對手的搜索欄，例如 DuckDuckGo 和 Ecosia，當然，需要先下載這些搜索引擎的應用程序。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new version of Pixel Launcher has allowed EU users to choose alternative search engines. Previously, users were unable to select search engines other than Google on Pixel phones, and the Google search bar widget on the home screen could not be disabled. Google has made this change in order to comply with the European Union’s Digital Markets Act (DMA). In the new version, users can replace the Google search bar with the search bar of their competitors, such as DuckDuckGo and Ecosia. However, they need to download the applications of these search engines first.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:29:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>