<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:04:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[适用于 ARM64 的 tiny11 core 已经发布]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>适用于 ARM64 的 tiny11 core&nbsp;已经发布。</strong>——「tiny11 core」 是 tiny11 开发者推出的新项目，是常规版的 tiny11 镜像的更轻量版本。tiny11 core 为用户另外提供了一个快速的环境，用于测试虚拟机内的应用程序或驱动程序，而无需下载更大的镜像，以节省磁盘空间。因此 tiny11 core 并不适用于执行重要任务的设备。</p><p><em>下载：https://archive.org/details/tiny11-core-arm64</em></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The tiny11 core for ARM64 has been released. 「tiny11 core」 is a new project launched by the developers of tiny11, which is a lighter version of the regular tiny11 image. It provides users with a fast environment for testing applications or drivers within a virtual machine without the need to download larger images, thus saving disk space. Therefore, tiny11 core is not suitable for devices intended for critical tasks.</p><p><em>Download:&nbsp;https://archive.org/details/tiny11-core-arm64</em></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:32:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140688.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140688.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[淘宝之后，京东跟进「仅退款」功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>12 月 27 日，继淘宝之后，京东也推出了 「仅退款」 功能。京东修订了《京东开放平台交易纠纷处理总则》，其中交易纠纷新增支持用户仅退款。仅退款的操作模式为，消费者无需返回原商品，退款完成后，将不能对此商品再次发起退货申请。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Following in the footsteps of Taobao, JD.com has also introduced the 「Refund Only」 feature. JD.com has revised its 「General Rules for Dispute Resolution on JD.com Open Platform,」 which now includes support for users to receive a refund without returning the original product. Under the 「Refund Only」 operation mode, consumers are not required to return the original item. Once the refund is completed, they will not be able to initiate a return request for the same product again.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 12:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140677.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140677.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[经济日报这篇文章回应意味明显]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-wpcom-alert"><div class="alert alert-info block-alert" role="alert"><i class="wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el"></i><div class="alert-content"><p>文中观点不代表本站。本站对所刊内容不持任何立场。</p></div></div></div><p><em>本站特邀作者/益鸣</em></p><p>声明：本文中的解读是作者的个人观点，不具有任何参考价值。该声明是本文的组成部分。</p><p>官媒经济日报 「金观平」 今天发文 <a href="https://www.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_25804633" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">《经济日报金观平：持续扩大中等收入群体》</a>。文章称要加快推动形成更大规模的中等收入群体。文中提及 「要看到，目前我国中等收入群体有 4 亿多人，总量不少。但以 14 亿多人口的基数计算，所占比重约为 30%，还不够高。内部结构也不均衡，相对较低收入人群在中等收入群体中占比较大，一部分中等收入群体就业稳定性不足、存在 「掉队」 风险。此外，还有相当多农村人口尚未进入中等收入群体。加快推动形成更大规模的中等收入群体，必要且紧迫。」</p><p><strong>这篇文章的回应意味明显。</strong></p><p>——25 日，经济学家李迅雷发文 <a href="https://www.sohu.com/a/747134053_120094090" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">《上山容易下山难？从需求侧看经济》</a>，文章称 「根据北师大中国收入分配研究院 2021 年发表的调查数据，我国月收入 2000 元以下的人口约为 9.64 亿。」。随即引发热议。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 09:56:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140649.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140649.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[淘宝也上线了「仅退款」服务]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>淘宝也上线了 「仅退款」 服务。</strong>淘宝最近公示了关于变更其平台争议处理规则的提案，其中新增了淘宝基于平台自身大数据能力，识别多维度结合，对于买家发起符合相关情形的售后，做出快速退款或退货退款的规定。该提案已于昨日（12 月 26 日）正式实施。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Taobao has also launched its 「Refund Only」 service. Taobao recently announced a proposal to amend its platform’s dispute resolution rules, which includes the addition of provisions allowing Taobao to make quick refunds or return refunds based on its own platform’s big data capabilities and the identification of multiple dimensions combined, in response to buyer-initiated after-sales requests that meet relevant conditions. This proposal was officially implemented yesterday (December 26th).</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 09:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140647.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140647.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[拜登政府决定不推翻苹果手表禁售令]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，由于涉嫌侵犯一项专利，苹果最近在美国<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/140242.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">停售</a>了新发布的 Watch Series 9 和 Watch Ultra 2 智能手表。当时的裁决由美国国际贸易委员会（International Trade Commission）做出。<strong>现在拜登政府决定不推翻这项裁决。这意味着苹果仍需在美国停售这两款手表。</strong>美国贸易代表（戴琪/Katherine Tai）办公室在声明中称：「2023 年 10 月 26 日，美国国际贸易委员会发现 Apple， Inc. 侵犯了总部位于美国的 Masimo Corporation 和 Cercacor Laboratories， Inc. 拥有的两项专利…… 经过慎重协商，戴大使决定不推翻国贸委员会的决定，国际贸易委员会的决定于 2023 年 12 月 26 日成为最终决定。」</p><p>苹果的预算型手表 Apple Watch SE 不受禁令影响。该决定也不影响亚马逊等第三方零售商销售智能手表。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Apple recently halted the sales of its newly released Watch Series 9 and Watch Ultra 2 smartwatches in the United States due to alleged patent infringement. The decision was made by the International Trade Commission (ITC) of the United States. The Biden administration has now decided not to overturn this ruling. This means that Apple will still be required to halt the sales of these two watches in the United States.</p><p>The Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR), led by Katherine Tai, stated in a declaration:</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>On October 26, 2023, the U.S. International Trade Commission found that Apple, Inc. infringed two patents owned by Masimo Corporation and Cercacor Laboratories, Inc, both based in the United States… After careful consultations, Ambassador Tai decided not to reverse the ITC’s determination and the ITC’s decision became final on December 26, 2023.</p></blockquote><p>The budget-friendly Apple Watch SE is not affected by the ban. This decision also does not impact third-party retailers like Amazon from selling smartwatches.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 09:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140642.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140642.html</link>
            <category>设备</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
