<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"


>
    <channel>
        <title>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯]]>
        </title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>
            <![CDATA[软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]>
        </description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>zh-cn</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 15:59:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[称日本地震是报应，海南广电总枱一主持人被停职]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/20240102204431.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"></figure></div><p>海南广播电视总枱通过微信公号发布声明说，针对我台主持人肖程皓在其个人自媒体账号上发布不当言论一事，我台正组织核查，在此期间，暂停止其工作。据悉，该主持人早前称 「日本发生地震是报应」 引发热议。</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 12:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140726.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140726.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[[清单] Telegram 发布 2023 年终更新]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，当地时间 12 月 31 日，Telegram 官方发布了 2023 年第 10 次更新，也是最后一次更新。</p><p>我们提炼了这次更新的要点：</p><ol><li><strong>为通话添加了新的动画和背景</strong>。它们可根据通话状态（响铃/活动/已结束）动态变化，并且占用的资源更少、更加省电。</li><li>修复了通话功能数百个错误和界面故障，并<strong>对通话质量进行了改进。</strong></li><li>继<a href="https://www.ruancan.com/p/139497.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">上个月的 iOS 版</a>之后，<strong>安卓版也获得了消息自毁动画效果。</strong></li><li>Telegram 机器人现在可以对消息做出反应并管理反应、引用和链接，发送回复等。</li><li>机器人可在频道中获取有关赠品和提升的信息。</li></ol><p>Telegram 正对机器人功能进行大规模更新，官方将在本月公布更多信息。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>On December 31st, local time, Telegram officially released its 10th and final update of 2023.</p><p><strong>Here are the key points of this update:</strong></p><ol><li>New animations and backgrounds have been added for calls. They dynamically change based on the call status (ringing/active/ended) and consume fewer resources while being more power-efficient.</li><li>Hundreds of bugs and interface issues related to calls have been fixed, and improvements have been made to the call quality.</li><li>Following the iOS version released last month, the Android version now features message self-destruct animation effects.</li><li>Telegram bots can now react to messages and manage reactions, quotes, links, and reply sending.</li><li>Bots can acquire information about giveaways and promotions in channels.</li></ol><p>Telegram is undergoing extensive updates to its bot functionality, and more information will be announced by the official later this month.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 14:45:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140712.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140712.html</link>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[油管第三方客户端 NewPipe 0.26 发布]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>流行的 YouTube 第三方安卓客户端 NewPipe 重要更新了。最新版 NewPipe 0.26 版（<a href="https://newpipe.net/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">官网</a>）现在支持了很多新的内容类型。</strong>这包括对 YouTube 直播、Shorts 的支持，以及对频道关于页面的支持。除了 YouTube，NewPipe 还支持 PeerTube、Bandcamp、SoundCloud 等流媒体平台，这次更新同样涉及这些平台。</p><ul><li>YouTube：视频、短片、直播、播放列表、简介（请注意，YouTube 不提供短片的上传日期和时长，因此它们不会显示在 Feed 中）</li><li>PeerTube：视频、播放列表、频道（适用于帐户）、关于</li><li>SoundCloud：曲目、播放列表、专辑、关于</li><li>Bandcamp：专辑、曲目、关于</li><li>media.ccc.de： 视频， 关于</li></ul><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The popular third-party Android client for YouTube, NewPipe, has received a significant update. The latest version, NewPipe 0.26 (<a href="https://newpipe.net/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website</a>), now supports various new content types. This includes support for YouTube live streams, Shorts, and channel about pages. In addition to YouTube, NewPipe also supports other streaming platforms such as PeerTube, Bandcamp, SoundCloud, and this update includes improvements for these platforms as well.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140694.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140694.html</link>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[适用于 ARM64 的 tiny11 core 已经发布]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>软餐获悉，<strong>适用于 ARM64 的 tiny11 core&nbsp;已经发布。</strong>——「tiny11 core」 是 tiny11 开发者推出的新项目，是常规版的 tiny11 镜像的更轻量版本。tiny11 core 为用户另外提供了一个快速的环境，用于测试虚拟机内的应用程序或驱动程序，而无需下载更大的镜像，以节省磁盘空间。因此 tiny11 core 并不适用于执行重要任务的设备。</p><p><em>下载：https://archive.org/details/tiny11-core-arm64</em></p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>The tiny11 core for ARM64 has been released. 「tiny11 core」 is a new project launched by the developers of tiny11, which is a lighter version of the regular tiny11 image. It provides users with a fast environment for testing applications or drivers within a virtual machine without the need to download larger images, thus saving disk space. Therefore, tiny11 core is not suitable for devices intended for critical tasks.</p><p><em>Download:&nbsp;https://archive.org/details/tiny11-core-arm64</em></p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:32:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140688.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140688.html</link>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                <![CDATA[淘宝之后，京东跟进「仅退款」功能]]>
            </title>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[<p>12 月 27 日，继淘宝之后，京东也推出了 「仅退款」 功能。京东修订了《京东开放平台交易纠纷处理总则》，其中交易纠纷新增支持用户仅退款。仅退款的操作模式为，消费者无需返回原商品，退款完成后，将不能对此商品再次发起退货申请。</p><hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"><p>Following in the footsteps of Taobao, JD.com has also introduced the 「Refund Only」 feature. JD.com has revised its 「General Rules for Dispute Resolution on JD.com Open Platform,」 which now includes support for users to receive a refund without returning the original product. Under the 「Refund Only」 operation mode, consumers are not required to return the original item. Once the refund is completed, they will not be able to initiate a return request for the same product again.</p>
                                                                                ]]>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 12:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/140677.html</guid>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/140677.html</link>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
